<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CricTech</string>
    <string name="hide_bottom_view_on_scroll_behavior" translatable="false">com.google.android.material.behavior.HideBottomViewOnScrollBehavior</string>
    <string name="history">"  The sport of cricket has a known history beginning in the late 16th century England. It became an established sport in the country in the 18th century and developed globally in the 19th and 20th centuries. International matches have been played since the 19th-century and formal Test cricket matches are considered to date from 1877. Cricket is the world's second most popular spectator sport, after association football (soccer).
        Cricket is governed by the International Cricket Council (ICC), which has over one hundred countries and territories in membership, though only twelve currently play Test cricket.
        The game's rules are defined in the Laws of cricket. The game has various formats, ranging from T-10(Ten-10) played in around 90 minutes to Test matches, which can last up to five days."
    </string>

    <string name="origin">"  Cricket was created during Saxon or Norman times by children living in the Weald, an area of dense woodlands and clearings in south-east England that lies across Kent and Sussex. The first definite written reference is from the end of the 16th century.
        There have been several speculations about the game's origins, including some that it was created in France or Flanders. The earliest of these speculative references is from 1300 and concerns the future King Edward II playing at "creag and other games" in both Westminster and Newenden. It has been suggested that "creag" was an Old English word for cricket, but expert opinion is that it was an early spelling of "craic", meaning "fun and games in general".
        It is generally believed that cricket survived as a children's game for many generations before it was increasingly taken up by adults around the beginning of the 17th century. Possibly cricket was derived from bowls, assuming bowls is the older sport, by the intervention of a batsman trying to stop the ball from reaching its target by hitting it away. Playing on sheep-grazed land or in clearings, the original implements may have been a matted lump of sheep's wool (or even a stone or a small lump of wood) as the ball; a stick or a crook or another farm tool as the bat; and a stool or a tree stump or a gate (e.g., a wicket gate) as the wicket.
    </string>

    <string name="name">"  A number of words are thought to be possible sources for the term "cricket". In the earliest definite reference, it was spelled creckett. The name may have been derived from the Middle Dutch krick(-e), meaning a stick; or the Old English cricc or cryce meaning a crutch or staff, or the French word criquet meaning a wooden post. The Middle Dutch word krickstoel means a long low stool used for kneeling in church; this resembled the long low wicket with two stumps used in early cricket. According to Heiner Gillmeister, a European language expert of the University of Bonn, "cricket" derives from the Middle Dutch phrase for hockey, met de (krik ket)sen (i.e., "with the stick chase").
        It is more likely that the terminology of cricket was based on words in use in south-east England at the time and, given trade connections with the County of Flanders, especially in the 15th century when it belonged to the Duchy of Burgundy, many Middle Dutch words found their way into southern English dialects."</string>

    <string name="gambling">"  Cricket thrived after the Restoration in 1660 and is believed to have first attracted gamblers making large bets at this time. It is possible, as believed by some historians, that top-class matches began. In 1664, the "Cavalier" Parliament passed the Gaming Act 1664 which limited stakes to £100, although that was still a fortune at the time, equivalent to about £19,000 in present-day terms . Cricket had become a significant gambling sport by the end of the 17th century, as evidenced in 1697 by a newspaper report of a "great match" played in Sussex which was 11-a-side and played for high stakes of 50 guineas a side.
        With freedom of the press having been granted in 1696, cricket for the first time could be reported in the newspapers. But it was a long time before the newspaper industry adapted sufficiently to provide frequent, comprehensive, coverage. During the first half of the 18th century, press reports tended to focus on the betting rather than the play."</string>

    <string name="patronage">"  Gambling introduced the first patrons because some of the gamblers decided to strengthen their bets by forming their own teams and it is believed the first "county teams" were formed in the aftermath of the Restoration in 1660, especially as members of the nobility were employing "local experts" from village cricket as the earliest professionals.[5] The first known game in which the teams use county names is in 1709, but these types of fixtures were being arranged long before then. The match in 1697 was probably Sussex versus another county.
        The most notable of the early patrons were a group of aristocrats and businessmen who were active from about 1725, which is the time that press coverage became more regular, perhaps as a result of the patrons' influence. These men included the 2nd Duke of Richmond, Sir William Gage, Alan Brodrick and Edwin Stead. For the first time, the press mentions individual players like Thomas Waymark."</string>
    
    <string name="cricket_expansion">"  Cricket was introduced to North America via the English colonies in the 17th century, probably before it had even reached the north of England. In the 18th century it arrived in other parts of the globe. It was introduced to the West Indies by colonists and to the Indian subcontinent by East India Company mariners in the first half of the century. It arrived in Australia almost as soon as colonisation began in 1788. New Zealand and South Africa followed in the early years of the 19th century.
        Cricket never caught on in Canada, despite efforts by the upper class to promote the game as a way of identifying with the "mother country". Canada, unlike Australia and the West Indies, witnessed a continual decline in the popularity of the game during 1860 to 1960. Linked in the public consciousness to an upper-class sport, the game never became popular with the general public. In the summer season it had to compete with baseball. During the First World War, Canadian units stationed in France played baseball instead of cricket."</string>

    <string name="dev_laws">"  It's not clear when the basic rules of cricket such as bat and ball, the wicket, pitch dimensions, overs, how out, etc. were originally formulated. In 1728, the Duke of Richmond and Alan Brodick drew up Articles of Agreement to determine the code of practice in a particular game and this became a common feature, especially around payment of stake money and distributing the winnings given the importance of gambling.
        In 1744, the Laws of Cricket were codified for the first time and then amended in 1774, when innovations such as lbw, middle stump and maximum bat width were added. These laws stated that "the principals shall choose from amongst the gentlemen present two umpires who shall absolutely decide all disputes". The codes were drawn up by the so-called "Star and Garter Club" whose members ultimately founded the Marylebone Cricket Club at Lord's in 1787. The MCC immediately became the custodian of the Laws and has made periodic revisions and recodifications subsequently."</string>

    <string name="int_cric">"  In 1859, a team of leading English professionals set off to North America on the first-ever overseas tour and, in 1862, the first English team toured Australia. Between May and October 1868, a team of Aboriginal Australians toured England in what was the first Australian cricket team to travel overseas."</string>

    <string name="int_cric2">"  In 1877, an England touring team in Australia played two matches against full Australian XIs that are now regarded as the inaugural Test matches. The following year, the Australians toured England for the first time and the success of this tour ensured a popular demand for similar ventures in future. No Tests were played in 1878 but more soon followed and, at The Oval in 1882, the Australian victory in a tense finish gave rise to The Ashes.
        South Africa became the third Test nation in 1889."</string>

    <string name="nineteenth">"  The game also underwent a fundamental change of organisation with the formation for the first time of county clubs. All the modern county clubs, starting with Sussex in 1839, were founded during the 19th century. No sooner had the first county clubs established themselves than they faced what amounted to "player action" as William Clarke created the travelling All-England Eleven in 1846. Though a commercial venture, this team did much to popularise the game in districts which had never previously been visited by high-class cricketers. Other similar teams were created and this vogue lasted for about thirty years. But the counties and MCC prevailed."</string>

    <string name="nineteenth_2">"  The growth of cricket in the mid and late 19th century was assisted by the development of the railway network. For the first time, teams from a long distance apart could play one other without a prohibitively time-consuming journey. Spectators could travel longer distances to matches, increasing the size of crowds. Army units around the Empire had time on their hands, and encouraged the locals so they could have some entertaining competition. Most of the Empire embraced cricket, with the exception of Canada.
        In 1864, another bowling revolution resulted in the legalisation of overarm and in the same year Wisden Cricketers' Almanack was first published. W. G. Grace began his long and influential career at this time, his feats doing much to increase cricket's popularity. He introduced technical innovations which revolutionised the game, particularly in batting."</string>

    <string name="growth">"  Cricket rose to prominence in Britain during a period where the British Empire became the largest empire in the world. British colonial authorities often collaborated with native elites, who were encouraged to adopt British cultural traditions such as cricket, which during the 19th century was promoted as an emblematic element of Victorian masculinity.[38] Throughout the British empire, cricket was included as part of the physical activities which students at colonial schools engaged in.[39][40] For the colonial subjects of the British Empire, cricket grew in popularity for a variety of reasons. For native elites, playing the sport was a method of anglicising themselves, while for anti-colonial nationalists, playing cricket provided a venue for them to counter emasculating colonial stereotypes."</string>

    <string name="natchamp">"  A significant development in domestic cricket occurred in 1890 when the official County Championship was constituted in England. Soon afterwards, in May 1894, the sport's first-class standard was officially defined.[44] This organisational initiative has been repeated in other countries. Australia established the Sheffield Shield in 1892–93. Other national competitions to be established were the Currie Cup in South Africa, the Plunket Shield in New Zealand and the Ranji Trophy in India. The ICC re-defined first-class status in 1947 as a global concept"</string>

    <string name="natchamp2">"  The period from 1890 to the outbreak of the First World War has become one of nostalgia, ostensibly because the teams played cricket according to "the spirit of the game", but more realistically because it was a peacetime period that was shattered by the First World War. The era has been called The Golden Age of cricket and it featured numerous great names such as Grace, Wilfred Rhodes, C. B. Fry, Ranjitsinhji and Victor Trumper."</string>

    <string name="growth_int_cric">"  Cricket was introduced to various colonies around the world. The Imperial Cricket Conference (ICC) was founded in 1909 with England, Australia and South Africa as the founding members. The ICC included the Marylebone Cricket club, the Australian Board of Control for International Cricket, and the South African Cricket Association as its original associations . The conference aimed to regulate international cricket among three nations, which were considered to be of equal status at the time.
        In 1926, both New Zealand and the West Indies were admitted as members, allowing them to play Test cricket against the other sides. However, at this time in the West Indies, cricket was primarily dominated by the white population. Originally, the ICC was not interested in broadening the international popularity of cricket. The organization was reluctant to invite non-commonwealth nations to play. New Zealand was restricted to play three-day test matches. New Zealand and India both became Test playing nations before World War II and Pakistan joined soon afterwards in 1952.
        At the initial suggestion of Pakistan, the ICC was expanded to include non-Test playing countries from 1965, with Associate members being admitted. At the same time the organisation changed its name to the International Cricket Conference. The first limited-overs World Cups were played during the 1970s and Sri Lanka became the first Associate member to be raised to Test playing status in 1982. Because the ICC was predominantly a Western organization, the founding countries decided who was allowed to join the conference or engage in test cricket. There was no desire or attempt to create a set of Associate nations that would play in Test status, which is why countries such as Sri Lanka were not permitted to partake until the 1980s.
        The international game continued to grow with the introduction of Affiliate Member status in 1984, a level of membership designed for sides with less history of playing cricket. In 1989 the ICC renamed itself the International Cricket Council. Zimbabwe became Full Members in 1992 and Bangladesh in 2000 before Afghanistan and Ireland were both admitted as Test sides in 2018, bringing the number of full members of the ICC to 12."</string>

    <string name="world_series">"  The money problems of top cricketers were also the root cause of another cricketing crisis that arose in 1977 when the Australian media magnate Kerry Packer fell out with the Australian Cricket Board over TV rights. Taking advantage of the low remuneration paid to players, Packer retaliated by signing several of the best players in the world to a privately run cricket league outside the structure of international cricket. World Series Cricket hired some of the banned South African players and allowed them to show off their skills in an international arena against other world-class players. The schism lasted only until 1979 and the "rebel" players were allowed back into established international cricket, though many found that their national teams had moved on without them. Long-term results of World Series Cricket have included the introduction of significantly higher player salaries and innovations such as coloured kit and night games."</string>

    <string name="expansion">"  In June 2001, the ICC introduced a "Test Championship Table" and, in October 2002, a "One-day International Championship Table". As indicated by ICC rankings,[63] the various cricket formats have continued to be a major competitive sport in most former British Empire countries, notably the Indian subcontinent, and new participants including the Netherlands. In 2017, the number of countries with full ICC membership was increased to twelve by the addition of Afghanistan and Ireland.[64] The ICC expanded its development programme, aiming to produce more national teams capable of competing at the various formats. Development efforts are focused on African and Asian nations, and on the United States. In 2004, the ICC Intercontinental Cup brought first-class cricket to 12 nations, mostly for the first time."</string>

    <string name="ipl">"  In April 2007, Essel Group launched the Indian Cricket League (ICL), in partnership with IL&amp;FS. The ICL was not recognized by the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) or the International Cricket Council (ICC). Moreover, the BCCI was unhappy about its committee members joining the ICL executive board. In response, the BCCI increased the prize money for its domestic tournaments and imposed lifetime bans on players who joined the ICL, which it considered a rebel league."</string>
    
    <string name="no_of_players">"  A match is played between two sides, each of eleven players, one of whom shall be captain. By agreement a match may be played between sides of fewer than, or more than, eleven players, but not more than eleven players may field at any time. If, during the match and for whatever reason, a side is reduced to fewer than the original number of nominated players, the match shall continue as long as it is possible to do so under the Laws or any agreements made before the toss."</string>
    
    <string name="nom_and_rep1">"<b>1.2.1</b> Each captain shall nominate his/her players in writing to one of the umpires before the toss."</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep2">"<b>1.2.2</b> No player may be replaced after the nomination without the consent of the opposing captain."</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep3">"<b>1.2.3</b> Any replacement player shall be considered the same player as the nominated player he/she replaced for the purposes of these Laws.\n"</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep4">"1.2.3.1 A replacement shall not bat in an innings in which the nominated player he/she is replacing has completed his/her innings.\n "</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep5">"1.2.3.2 Any unserved Penalty time, warnings or suspensions, that applied to the original nominated player will be inherited by his/her replacement."</string>

    <string name="captain">"  <b>1.3.1</b> If at any time the captain is not available, a deputy shall act for him/her.\n
        <b>1.3.2</b> If a captain is not available to nominate the players, then any person associated with that team may act as his/her deputy to do so. See 1.2.\n
        <b>1.3.3</b> At any time after the nomination of the players, only a nominated player can act as deputy in discharging the duties and responsibilities of the captain as stated in these Laws, including at the toss. See Law 13.4 (The toss)."</string>

    <string name="ump1">"Before the match, two umpires shall be appointed, one for each end, to control the match as required by the Laws, with absolute impartiality.  The umpires shall be present on the ground and report to the Executive of the ground at least 45 minutes before the scheduled start of each day’s play."</string>

    <string name="ump2">"An umpire shall not be changed during the match, other than in exceptional circumstances, unless he/she is injured or ill.  If there has to be a change of umpire, the replacement shall act only as the striker’s end umpire unless the captains agree that the replacement should take full responsibility as an umpire. "</string>

    <string name="ump3">"Before the toss the umpires shall\n<b>2.3.1</b> meet with the captains; the umpires shall determine"</string>

    <string name="ump3.1">"2.3.1.1 the balls to be used during the match.  See Law 4 (The ball)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.2">"2.3.1.2 the hours of play and the times and durations of any agreed intervals.  In a match of one day’s duration, no specific time need be agreed for the tea interval.  It may be agreed instead to take this interval between innings.  See Law 11 (Intervals)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.3">"2.3.1.3 which clock or watch and back-up time piece is to be used during the match."</string>
    <string name="ump3.4">"2.3.1.4 the boundary of the field of play and allowances for boundaries, including whether any obstacle within the field of play is to be regarded as a boundary.  See Law 19 (Boundaries)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.5">"2.3.1.5 the use of covers. See Law 10 (Covering the pitch)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.6">"2.3.1.6 any special conditions of play affecting the conduct of the match."</string>
    <string name="ump3.7">"<b>2.3.2</b>  inform the scorers of agreements in 2.3.1.2, 2.3.1.3, 2.3.1.4 and 2.3.1.6."</string>
    
    <string name="ump4">"Before the toss and during the match, the umpires shall satisfy themselves that\n<b>2.4.1</b> the wickets are properly pitched.  See Law 8 (The wickets)"</string>
    <string name="ump4.1">"<b>2.4.2</b> the creases are correctly marked.  See Law 7 (The creases)."</string>
    <string name="ump4.2">"<b>2.4.3</b> the boundary of the field of play complies with the requirements of Laws 19.1 (Determining the boundary of the field of play), 19.2 (Identifying and marking the boundary) and 19.3 (Restoring the boundary)."</string>

    <string name="ump5">"Before the toss and during the match, the umpires shall satisfy themselves that\n<b>2.5.1</b> the conduct of the match is strictly in accordance with the Laws."</string>
    <string name="ump5.1">"<b>2.5.2</b> the implements used in the match conform to the following:"</string>
    <string name="ump5.2">"2.5.2.1 Law 4 (The ball)."</string>
    <string name="ump5.3">"2.5.2.2 externally visible requirements of Law 5 (The bat) and Appendix B."</string>
    <string name="ump5.4">"2.5.2.3 either Laws 8.2 (Size of stumps) and 8.3 (The bails) or, if applicable, Law 8.4 (Junior cricket)."</string>
    <string name="ump5.5">"<b>2.5.3</b> no player uses equipment other than that permitted.  See Appendix A.2.  Note particularly therein the interpretation of ‘protective helmet’."</string>
    <string name="ump5.6">"<b>2.5.4</b> the wicket-keeper’s gloves comply with the requirements of Law 27.2 (Gloves)."</string>

    <string name="ump6">"The umpires shall be the sole judges of fair and unfair play."</string>

    <string name="ump7">"<b>2.7.1</b> It is solely for the umpires together to decide whether either conditions of ground, weather or light or exceptional circumstances mean that it would be dangerous or unreasonable for play to take place.
        Conditions shall not be regarded as either dangerous or unreasonable merely because they are not ideal.
        The fact that the grass and the ball are wet does not warrant the ground conditions being regarded as unreasonable or dangerous."</string>

    <string name="ump7.1">"<b>2.7.2</b> Conditions shall be regarded as dangerous if there is actual and foreseeable risk to the safety of any player or umpire."</string>
    <string name="ump7.2">"<b>2.7.3</b> Conditions shall be regarded as unreasonable if, although posing no risk to safety, it would not be sensible for play to proceed."</string>
    <string name="ump7.3">"<b>2.7.4</b> If the umpires consider the ground is so wet or slippery as to deprive the bowler of a reasonable foothold, the fielders of the power of free movement, or the batter of the ability to play their strokes or to run between the wickets, then these conditions shall be regarded as so bad that it would be dangerous and unreasonable for play to take place."</string>

    <string name="ump8">"<b>2.8.1</b> All references to ground include the pitch.  See Law 6.1 (Area of pitch)."</string>
    <string name="ump8.1">"<b>2.8.2</b> The Umpires shall immediately suspend play, or not allow play to start or to recommence, if either umpire considers that the conditions of ground, weather or light, or any other circumstances are either dangerous or unreasonable."</string>
    <string name="ump8.2">"<b>2.8.3</b> When there is a suspension of play it is the responsibility of the umpires to monitor conditions.  They shall make inspections as often as appropriate, unaccompanied by any players or officials.  Immediately the umpires together agree that the conditions are no longer dangerous or unreasonable they shall call upon the players to resume play."</string>

    <string name="ump9">"The umpires shall stand where they can best see any act upon which their decision may be required.
        Subject to this over-riding consideration, the bowler’s end umpire shall stand in a position so as not to interfere with either the bowler’s run-up or the striker’s view.
        The striker’s end umpire may elect to stand on the off side instead of the on side of the pitch, provided he/she informs the captain of the fielding side, the striker and the other umpire."</string>

    <string name="ump10">"The umpires shall change ends after each side has had one completed innings.  See Law 13.3 (Completed innings)."</string>

    <string name="ump11">"Where there is disagreement or dispute about any matter, the umpires together shall make the final decision.  See also Law 31.6 (Consultation by umpires)."</string>

    <string name="ump12">"An umpire may alter any decision provided that such alteration is made promptly and does not contradict Law 20.6 (Dead ball not to be revoked). This apart, an umpire’s decision, once made, is final."</string>

    <string name="ump13">"<b>2.13.1</b> The following code of signals shall be used by umpires:
        2.13.1.1 Signals made while the ball is in play
        Dead ball - by crossing and re-crossing the wrists below the waist.
        No ball - by extending one arm horizontally.
        Out - by raising an index finger above the head. (If not out, the umpire shall call Not out.)
        Wide - by extending both arms horizontally.
        2.13.1.2 When the ball is dead, the bowler’s end umpire shall repeat the signals in 2.13.1.1, with the exception of the signal for Out, to the scorers.
        2.13.1.3  The signals listed below shall be made to the scorers only when the ball is dead.
        Boundary 4 - by waving an arm from side to side finishing with the arm across the chest.
        Boundary 6 - by raising both arms above the head.
        Bye - by raising an open hand above the head.
        Commencement of last hour - by pointing to a raised wrist with the other hand.
        Five Penalty runs awarded to the batting side - by repeated tapping of one shoulder with the opposite hand.
        Five Penalty runs awarded to the fielding side - by placing one hand on the opposite shoulder.
        Leg bye - by touching a raised knee with the hand.
        New ball - by holding the ball above the head.
        Revoke the last decision - by touching both shoulders, each with the opposite hand.
        Short run - by bending one arm upwards and touching the nearer shoulder with the tips of the fingers.
        The following signals are for Levels 3 and 4 of the player conduct offences.  Each signal has two parts, both of which should be acknowledged separately by the scorers.
        Level 3 conduct
        Part 1 - by putting one arm out to the side of the body and repeatedly raising it and lowering it.
        Part 2 - by raising both hands, all fingers spread, to shoulder height, palms facing towards the scorers.
        Level 4 conduct
        Part 1 - by putting one arm out to the side of the body and repeatedly raising it and lowering it.
        Part 2 - by raising an index finger, held at shoulder height, to the side of the body.
        2.13.1.4  All the signals in 2.13.1.3 are to be made by the bowler’s end umpire except that for Short run, which is to be signalled by the umpire at the end where short running occurs.  However, the bowler’s end umpire shall be responsible both for the final signal of Short run to the scorers and, if more than one run is short, for informing them as to the number of runs to be recorded."</string>

    <string name="ump13.1">"<b>2.13.2</b> The umpire shall wait until each signal to the scorers has been separately acknowledged by a scorer before allowing play to proceed.
        If several signals are to be used, they SHALL be given in the order that the events occurred."</string>

    <string name="unp14">"Throughout the Laws, wherever the umpires are to receive information from captains or other players, it will be sufficient for one umpire to be so informed and for him/her to inform the other umpire."</string>
    <string name="ump15">"Consultation between umpires and scorers on doubtful points is essential.  The umpires shall, throughout the match, satisfy themselves as to the correctness of the number of runs scored, the wickets that have fallen and, where appropriate, the number of overs bowled.  They shall agree these with the scorers at least at every interval, other than a drinks interval, and at the conclusion of the match.  See Laws 3.2 (Correctness of scores), 16.8 (Correctness of result) and 16.10 (Result not to be changed)."</string>

    <string name="score">"Two scorers shall be appointed to record all runs scored, all wickets taken and, where appropriate, number of overs bowled."</string>
    <string name="score1">"The scorers shall frequently check to ensure that their records agree. They shall agree with the umpires, at least at every interval, other than drinks intervals, and at the conclusion of the match, the runs scored, the wickets that have fallen and, where appropriate, the number of overs bowled. See Law 2.15 (Correctness of scores)."</string>
    <string name="score2">"The scorers shall accept all instructions and signals given to them by the umpires and shall immediately acknowledge each separate signal."</string>

    <string name="ball">"The ball, when new, shall weigh not less than 5.5 ounces/155.9 g, nor more than 5.75 ounces/163 g, and shall measure not less than 8.81 in/22.4 cm, nor more than 9 in/22.9 cm in circumference."</string>
    <string name="ball1">"<b>4.2.1</b> All balls to be used in the match, having been determined by the umpires, shall be in the possession of the umpires before the toss and shall remain under their control throughout the match."</string>
    <string name="ball2">"<b>4.2.2</b> The umpire shall take possession of the ball in use at the fall of each wicket, at the start of any interval and at any interruption of play."</string>
    <string name="ball3">"Unless an agreement to the contrary has been made before the match, either captain may demand a new ball at the start of each innings."</string>
    <string name="ball4">"In a match of more than one day’s duration, the captain of the fielding side may demand a new ball when the number of overs, excluding any part overs, bowled with the old one is equal to or greater than 80 overs. The umpire shall inform the other umpire and indicate to the batters and the scorers whenever a new ball is taken into play."</string>
    <string name="ball5">"If, during play, the ball cannot be found or recovered or the umpires agree that it has become unfit for play through normal use, the umpires shall replace it with a ball which has had wear comparable with that which the previous ball had received before the need for its replacement. When the ball is replaced, the umpire shall inform the batters and the fielding captain.</string>
    <string name="ball6">"The specifications as described in 4.1 shall apply to men’s cricket only. The following specifications shall apply to:\n\n<b>4.6.1</b> Women’s cricket"</string>
    <string name="ball7">"Weight: from 4.94 ounces/140 g to 5.31 ounces/151 g\nCircumference: from 8.25 in/21.0 cm to 8.88 in/22.5 cm."</string>
    <string name="ball8">"<b>4.6.2</b> Junior cricket – Under 13"</string>
    <string name="ball9">" Weight: from 4.69 ounces/133 g to 5.06 ounces/144 g\nCircumference: from 8.06 in/20.5 cm to 8.69 in/22.0 cm."</string>
    
    <string name="bat">"<b>5.1.1</b> The bat consists of two parts, a handle and a blade."</string>
    <string name="bat1">"<b>5.1.2</b> The basic requirements and measurements of the bat are set out in this Law with detailed specifications in Appendix B."</string>
    <string name="bat2">"<b>5.2.1</b> The handle is to be made principally of cane and/or wood."</string>
    <string name="bat3">"<b>5.2.2</b> The part of the handle that is wholly outside the blade is defined to be the upper portion of the handle.  It is a straight shaft for holding the bat."</string>
    <string name="bat4">"<b>5.2.3</b> The upper portion of the handle may be covered with a grip as defined in Appendix B.2.2."</string>
    <string name="bat5">"<b>5.3.1</b> The blade comprises the whole of the bat apart from the handle as defined 5.2 and in Appendix B.3."</string>
    <string name="bat6">"<b>5.3.2</b> The blade shall consist solely of wood."</string>
    <string name="bat7">"<b>5.3.3</b> All bats may have commercial identifications on the blade, the size of which must comply with the relevant specification in Appendix B.6."</string>
    <string name="bat8">" Subject to the specifications in Appendix B.4 and providing 5.5 is not contravened,\n<b>5.4.1</b> solely for the purposes of
        either protection from surface damage to the face, sides and shoulders of the blade
        or repair to the blade after surface damage,
        material that is not rigid, either at the time of its application to the blade or subsequently, may be placed on these surfaces."</string>
    <string name="bat9">"<b>5.4.2</b> for repair of the blade after damage other than surface damage "</string>
    <string name="bat10">"5.4.2.1 solid material may be inserted into the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat11">"5.4.2.2 The only material permitted for any insertion is wood with minimal essential adhesives."</string>
    <string name="bat12">"<b>5.4.3</b>  to prevent damage to the toe, material may be placed on that part of the blade but shall not extend over any part of the face, back or sides of the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat13">"<b>5.5.1</b>  For any part of the bat, covered or uncovered, the hardness of the constituent materials and the surface texture thereof shall not be such that either or both could cause unacceptable damage to the ball."</string>
    <string name="bat14">"<b>5.5.2</b> Any material placed on any part of the bat, for whatever purpose, shall similarly not be such that it could cause unacceptable damage to the ball."</string>
    <string name="bat15">"<b>5.5.3</b> For the purpose of this Law, unacceptable damage is any change that is greater than normal wear and tear caused by the ball striking the uncovered wooden surface of the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat16">"In these Laws,\n<b>5.6.1</b> reference to the bat shall imply that the bat is held in the batter’s hand or a glove worn on his/her hand, unless stated otherwise."</string>
    <string name="bat17">"<b>5.6.2</b> contact between the ball and any of 5.6.2.1 to 5.6.2.4"</string>
    <string name="bat18">"5.6.2.1 the bat itself\n5.6.2.2 the batter’s hand holding the bat\n5.6.2.3 any part of a glove worn on the batter’s hand holding the bat\n5.6.2.4 any additional materials permitted under 5.4 shall be regarded as the ball striking or touching the bat or being struck by the bat."</string>
    <string name="bat19">"<b>5.7.1</b> The overall length of the bat, when the lower portion of the handle is inserted, shall not be more than 38 in/96.52 cm."</string>
    <string name="bat20">"<b>5.7.2</b> The blade of the bat shall not exceed the following dimensions:</string>
    <string name="bat21">"Width: 4.25in / 10.8 cm\nDepth: 2.64in / 6.7 cm\nEdges: 1.56in / 4.0cm.\nFurthermore, it should also be able to pass through a bat gauge as described in Appendix B.8. "</string>
    <string name="bat22">"<b>5.7.3</b> Except for bats of size 6 and less, the handle shall not exceed 52% of the overall length of the bat.."</string>
    <string name="bat23">"<b>5.7.4</b> The material permitted for covering the blade in 5.4.1 shall not exceed 0.04 in/0.1 cm in thickness."</string>
    <string name="bat24">"<b>5.7.5</b> The maximum permitted thickness of protective material placed on the toe of the blade is 0.12 in/0.3 cm."</string>
    <string name="bat25">"<b>5.8.1</b> Types A, B and C are bats conforming to 5.1 to 5.7 inclusive. "</string>
    <string name="bat26">"<b>5.8.2</b> Type A bats may be used at any level of cricket. "</string>
    <string name="bat27">"<b>5.8.3</b> 5.8.3 The specifications for Type D bats are described in Appendix B.7 and are for use by junior players in junior cricket only. "</string>
    <string name="bat28">"<b>5.8.4</b> Bats of Type B, Type C, Type D and any other bats may be used only at or below levels determined by the Governing Body for cricket in the country concerned. "</string>
    <string name="bat29">"<b>5.8.5</b> 5.8.5 Bats that do not qualify for any of the four categories A to D are not recognised in the Laws. "</string>

    <string name="pitch">"The pitch is a rectangular area of the ground 22 yards/20.12 m in length and 10 ft/3.05 m in width.  It is bounded at either end by the bowling creases and on either side by imaginary lines, one each side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps, each parallel to it and 5 ft/1.52 m from it.  If the pitch is next to an artificial pitch which is closer than 5 ft/1.52 m from the middle stumps, the pitch on that side will extend only to the junction of the two surfaces.  See Laws 8.1 (Description, width and pitching), 8.4 (Junior cricket) and 7.2 (The bowling crease)."</string>
    <string name="pitch1">"The umpires shall be the sole judges of the fitness of the pitch for play.  See Laws 2.7 (Fitness for play) and 2.8 (Suspension of play in dangerous or unreasonable conditions)."</string>
    <string name="pitch2">"Before the match, the Ground Authority shall be responsible for the selection and preparation of the pitch.  During the match, the umpires shall control its use and maintenance."</string>
    <string name="pitch3">"The pitch shall not be changed during the match unless the umpires decide that it is dangerous or unreasonable for play to continue on it and then only with the consent of both captains."</string>
    <string name="pitch4">"In the event of a non-turf pitch being used, the artificial surface shall conform to the following measurements:\nLength – a minimum of 58 ft/17.68 m\nWidth – a minimum of 6 ft/1.83 m\nSee Law 9.8 (Non-turf pitches)."</string>
    <string name="pitch5">"The Governing Body for cricket in the country concerned shall determine the length of the pitch for junior cricket."</string>

    <!-- Filter Categories Array -->
    <string-array name="filter_categories">
        <item>Filter Laws</item>
        <item>Setting Up</item>
        <item>Innings and Result</item>
        <item>The Over, Scoring Runs, Dead Ball and Extras</item>
        <item>Players, Substitutes, Runners and Practice</item>
        <item>Appeals and Dismissals</item>
        <item>Unfair Play</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string name="crease">"The positions of a bowling crease, a popping crease and two return creases shall be marked by white lines, as set out in 7.2, 7.3 and 7.4, at each end of the pitch.  See Appendix C."</string>
    <string name="crease2">"The bowling crease, which is the back edge of the crease marking, is the line that marks the end of the pitch, as in Law 6.1 (Area of pitch).  It shall be 8 ft 8 in/2.64 m in length."</string>
    <string name="crease3">"The popping crease, which is the back edge of the crease marking, shall be in front of and parallel to the bowling crease and shall be 4 ft/1.22 m from it.  The popping crease shall be marked to a minimum of 6 ft/1.83 m on either side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps and shall be considered to be unlimited in length."</string>
    <string name="crease4">"The return creases, which are the inside edges of the crease markings, shall be at right angles to the popping crease at a distance of 4 ft 4 in/1.32 m either side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps.  Each return crease shall be marked from the popping crease to a minimum of 8 ft/2.44 m behind it and shall be considered to be unlimited in length."</string>

    <string-array name="issue_categories">
        <item>Select Category</item>
        <item>Bug Report</item>
        <item>Feature Request</item>
        <item>Performance Issue</item>
        <item>UI/UX Issue</item>
        <item>Crash Report</item>
        <item>Data Sync Issue</item>
        <item>Login/Authentication</item>
        <item>Other</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="sachin_born">"24 April 1973, Mumbai, India"</string>
    <string name="sachin_education">"Sharadashram Vidyamandir School, Mumbai"</string>
    <string name="sachin_occupation">"Former Indian Cricketer, Cricket Mentor"</string>
    <string name="sachin_highlights">"Highest run scorer in international cricket, 100 international centuries, 2011 World Cup winner"</string>

    <!-- Shane Warne -->
    <string name="shane_born">"13 September 1969, Victoria, Australia"</string>
    <string name="shane_education">"Mentone Grammar School, Victoria"</string>
    <string name="shane_occupation">"Former Australian Cricketer, Cricket Commentator"</string>
    <string name="shane_highlights">"Over 700 Test wickets, 1999 World Cup winner, Leg-spin legend"</string>

    <!-- Ricky Ponting -->
    <string name="ricky_born">"19 December 1974, Launceston, Tasmania</string>
    <string name="ricky_education">"Brooks High School, Tasmania</string>
    <string name="ricky_occupation">"Former Australian Captain, Cricket Coach</string>
    <string name="ricky_highlights">"Three-time World Cup winner, Second-highest run scorer in Tests, Successful Australian captain</string>

    <!-- Brian Lara -->
    <string name="brian_born">2 May 1969, Santa Cruz, Trinidad and Tobago</string>
    <string name="brian_education">Fatima College, Trinidad</string>
    <string name="brian_occupation">Former West Indies Cricketer</string>
    <string name="brian_highlights">Highest individual Test score (400*), Over 11,000 Test runs</string>

    <!-- Wasim Akram -->
    <string name="wasim_born">3 June 1966, Lahore, Pakistan</string>
    <string name="wasim_education">Government Islamia College, Lahore</string>
    <string name="wasim_occupation">Former Pakistani Cricketer, Cricket Commentator</string>
    <string name="wasim_highlights">Over 900 international wickets, 1992 World Cup winner, Sultan of Swing</string>

    <!-- Jacques Kallis -->
    <string name="jacques_born">"16 October 1975, Cape Town, South Africa"</string>
    <string name="jacques_education">"Wynberg Boys' High School, Cape Town"</string>
    <string name="jacques_occupation">"Former South African Cricketer"</string>
    <string name="jacques_highlights">"Over 10,000 runs and 250 wickets in both Tests and ODIs"</string>

    <!-- Adam Gilchrist -->
    <string name="adam_born">"14 November 1971, Bellingen, Australia"</string>
    <string name="adam_education">"Kadina High School, New South Wales"</string>
    <string name="adam_occupation">"Former Australian Cricketer, Commentator"</string>
    <string name="adam_highlights">"Three-time World Cup winner, Over 5,500 Test runs as wicketkeeper-batsman"</string>

    <!-- Muttiah Muralitharan -->
    <string name="murali_born">"17 April 1972, Kandy, Sri Lanka"</string>
    <string name="murali_education">"St. Anthony's College, Kandy"</string>
    <string name="murali_occupation">"Former Sri Lankan Cricketer"</string>
    <string name="murali_highlights">"Highest wicket-taker in Tests (800 wickets) and ODIs (534 wickets)"</string>

    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <string name="fullscreen_image">Fullscreen Image</string>



    <!-- privacy policy -->
    <string name="privacy_policy_content">" Privacy Policy for CricTech Effective Date: August 7, 2025 Last Updated: August 7, 2025 CricTech Private Ltd ("CricTech", "we", "our", or "us") respects the privacy of users and is committed to protecting it through this Privacy Policy. This document outlines how we collect, use, store, and protect your data when you use our mobile application and related services (collectively referred to as the "App"). 1. Scope of this Policy This Privacy Policy applies to all users of the CricTech mobile application. By using the App, you agree to the terms of this policy. \n\n 2. Information We Collect As of now, CricTech does not collect any personal data from users. The App does not request, store, or transmit any personally identifiable information (such as name, email, age, location, etc.). In future updates, the App may integrate services such as Firebase and other APIs, which may involve data collection. This policy will be updated accordingly before such features go live. \n\n 3. Use of Information Since no personal information is currently collected, CricTech does not use any user data for personalization, targeting, analytics, or communication. \n\n 4. Sharing of Information We do not share any user data with third parties, advertisers, or service providers at this time. \n\n 5. Third-Party Services At present, CricTech does not integrate with any third-party analytics, advertising, or tracking services. However, in the future, we may include services such as: - Firebase (for analytics and crash reporting) - Cricket APIs (for live scores and data) Any integration will be governed by the privacy policies of those third parties, and users will be informed accordingly. \n\n 6. Children's Privacy CricTech is a general-purpose cricket information app and does not contain any harmful content, ads, or gambling features. It is safe for users of all ages, including children. We currently do not collect any personal data from any users, including minors. If that changes in future updates, we'll update this policy and ensure full compliance with relevant laws. \n\n 7. Security Measures We are committed to protecting your information and follow standard security practices to ensure that user data, if collected in the future, is handled safely and in accordance with applicable Indian laws. \n\n 8. User Rights As the App currently does not store or process any user data, user rights such as access, correction, or deletion are not applicable at this time. When data collection begins in future versions, appropriate rights and options will be offered. \n\n 9. Data Retention Since we do not collect any personal data currently, there is no data retained or stored on our servers or third-party services. Future data retention practices will be disclosed if features are added. \n\n 10. Changes to this Policy We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Changes will be communicated via the App, and users are encouraged to review this policy regularly. \n\n 11. Grievance Redressal If you have any questions, concerns, or grievances regarding this Privacy Policy or the use of your data, you may contact our Grievance Officers: Grievance Officers: - Aariz - Krushna - Shravan - Ibrahim Grievance Email: ghulek13@gmail.com Registered Office Address: CricTech Private Ltd, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India \n\n 12. Governing Law This Privacy Policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of India. Any disputes shall fall under the jurisdiction of courts located in Mumbai, Maharashtra, India.\n\n" </string>
    <!--  about us  -->
    <string name="about_us_content">"At CricTech, we believe cricket is more than a game — it's a passion, a culture, and a way of life. Our mission is to bring fans closer to the sport they love through deep insights, timeless content, and a clean, smooth app experience.\n\n While we currently don't provide live scores, our app is packed with powerful cricket content to keep you informed and entertained:\n\n • Ground Insights – Discover the stories and stats behind iconic stadiums worldwide.\n\n • Cricket Terms Simplified – From "Duck" to "Doosra", we decode the game for fans of all levels.\n\n • Tournament Deep Dives – Explore the history and context of IPL, World Cups, BGT, and more.\n\n • Photo Gallery – Relive the biggest moments in cricket with curated image collections.\n\n We're building CricTech as a reliable, blazing-fast platform that celebrates the game — and in the near future, we plan to bring you live scores, real-time updates, and match coverage to complete your cricket experience.\n\n Your feedback matters.\n Help us improve CricTech and shape the future of cricket apps, together.\n\n" </string>
    <!--  Help And Support -->
    <string name="help_and_support_content"> "Welcome to the Help &amp; Support section of CricTech. We are here to guide you and answer common questions about using the app.\n\n What does CricTech offer? \n\n CricTech provides a variety of features designed to enhance your cricket knowledge and experience: \n\n • Cricket Terms – Simplified definitions for fans of all levels. \n\n • Stadium Information – Learn about iconic grounds and their history. \n\n • Umpire &amp; Expert Info – Know more about the people behind the decisions.\n\n • Photo Gallery – View memorable moments in cricket through curated images.\n\n • Highlights &amp; Memes – Enjoy fun, engaging content beyond scores.\n\n • Cricket Basics – Understand the games origin, laws, player roles, match formats, and major tournaments &amp; +leagues. \n\n • Rules &amp; Feedback Guide – Helps users understand how to navigate and use the feedback form. \n\n Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)\n\n Q1. What is CricTech? \n A. CricTech provides all the essential information about cricket, offering great knowledge and stunning photos to enrich your experience.\n\n Q2. Does CricTech follow official rules? \n A. Yes, CricTech respects and follows official cricket rules and guidelines.\n\n Q3. Can I give feedback or report issues? \n A. Yes, you can! We have a feedback form available in the hamburger menu for your suggestions and reports. \n\n Q4. Is CricTech safe to use? \n A. Yes, completely. CricTech boosts your knowledge about the game and does not promote gambling or contain any unsafe content. \n\n Contact Us \n\n If you have any other queries or suggestions, feel free to reach out to us at: crichtech@gmail.com \n\n We're constantly working to make CricTech better. \n \n Thank you for being a part of our journey!\n" </string>
</resources>
