<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CricTech</string>
    <!-- Ground Profile labels -->
    <string name="gp_capacity">Capacity</string>
    <string name="gp_established">Established</string>
    <string name="gp_matches">Matches</string>
    <string name="hide_bottom_view_on_scroll_behavior" translatable="false">com.google.android.material.behavior.HideBottomViewOnScrollBehavior</string>
    <string name="history">"  The sport of cricket has a known history beginning in the late 16th century England. It became an established sport in the country in the 18th century and developed globally in the 19th and 20th centuries. International matches have been played since the 19th-century and formal Test cricket matches are considered to date from 1877. Cricket is the world's second most popular spectator sport, after association football (soccer).
        Cricket is governed by the International Cricket Council (ICC), which has over one hundred countries and territories in membership, though only twelve currently play Test cricket.
        The game's rules are defined in the Laws of cricket. The game has various formats, ranging from T-10(Ten-10) played in around 90 minutes to Test matches, which can last up to five days."
    </string>

    <string name="origin">"  Cricket was created during Saxon or Norman times by children living in the Weald, an area of dense woodlands and clearings in south-east England that lies across Kent and Sussex. The first definite written reference is from the end of the 16th century.
        There have been several speculations about the game's origins, including some that it was created in France or Flanders. The earliest of these speculative references is from 1300 and concerns the future King Edward II playing at "creag and other games" in both Westminster and Newenden. It has been suggested that "creag" was an Old English word for cricket, but expert opinion is that it was an early spelling of "craic", meaning "fun and games in general".
        It is generally believed that cricket survived as a children's game for many generations before it was increasingly taken up by adults around the beginning of the 17th century. Possibly cricket was derived from bowls, assuming bowls is the older sport, by the intervention of a batsman trying to stop the ball from reaching its target by hitting it away. Playing on sheep-grazed land or in clearings, the original implements may have been a matted lump of sheep's wool (or even a stone or a small lump of wood) as the ball; a stick or a crook or another farm tool as the bat; and a stool or a tree stump or a gate (e.g., a wicket gate) as the wicket.
    </string>

    <string name="name">"  A number of words are thought to be possible sources for the term "cricket". In the earliest definite reference, it was spelled creckett. The name may have been derived from the Middle Dutch krick(-e), meaning a stick; or the Old English cricc or cryce meaning a crutch or staff, or the French word criquet meaning a wooden post. The Middle Dutch word krickstoel means a long low stool used for kneeling in church; this resembled the long low wicket with two stumps used in early cricket. According to Heiner Gillmeister, a European language expert of the University of Bonn, "cricket" derives from the Middle Dutch phrase for hockey, met de (krik ket)sen (i.e., "with the stick chase").
        It is more likely that the terminology of cricket was based on words in use in south-east England at the time and, given trade connections with the County of Flanders, especially in the 15th century when it belonged to the Duchy of Burgundy, many Middle Dutch words found their way into southern English dialects."</string>

    <string name="gambling">"  Cricket thrived after the Restoration in 1660 and is believed to have first attracted gamblers making large bets at this time. It is possible, as believed by some historians, that top-class matches began. In 1664, the "Cavalier" Parliament passed the Gaming Act 1664 which limited stakes to pounds100, although that was still a fortune at the time, equivalent to about pounds19,000 in present-day terms . Cricket had become a significant gambling sport by the end of the 17th century, as evidenced in 1697 by a newspaper report of a "great match" played in Sussex which was 11-a-side and played for high stakes of 50 guineas a side.
        With freedom of the press having been granted in 1696, cricket for the first time could be reported in the newspapers. But it was a long time before the newspaper industry adapted sufficiently to provide frequent, comprehensive, coverage. During the first half of the 18th century, press reports tended to focus on the betting rather than the play."</string>

    <string name="patronage">"  Gambling introduced the first patrons because some of the gamblers decided to strengthen their bets by forming their own teams and it is believed the first "county teams" were formed in the aftermath of the Restoration in 1660, especially as members of the nobility were employing "local experts" from village cricket as the earliest professionals.[5] The first known game in which the teams use county names is in 1709, but these types of fixtures were being arranged long before then. The match in 1697 was probably Sussex versus another county.
        The most notable of the early patrons were a group of aristocrats and businessmen who were active from about 1725, which is the time that press coverage became more regular, perhaps as a result of the patrons' influence. These men included the 2nd Duke of Richmond, Sir William Gage, Alan Brodrick and Edwin Stead. For the first time, the press mentions individual players like Thomas Waymark."</string>
    
    <string name="cricket_expansion">"  Cricket was introduced to North America via the English colonies in the 17th century, probably before it had even reached the north of England. In the 18th century it arrived in other parts of the globe. It was introduced to the West Indies by colonists and to the Indian subcontinent by East India Company mariners in the first half of the century. It arrived in Australia almost as soon as colonisation began in 1788. New Zealand and South Africa followed in the early years of the 19th century.
        Cricket never caught on in Canada, despite efforts by the upper class to promote the game as a way of identifying with the "mother country". Canada, unlike Australia and the West Indies, witnessed a continual decline in the popularity of the game during 1860 to 1960. Linked in the public consciousness to an upper-class sport, the game never became popular with the general public. In the summer season it had to compete with baseball. During the First World War, Canadian units stationed in France played baseball instead of cricket."</string>

    <string name="dev_laws">"  It's not clear when the basic rules of cricket such as bat and ball, the wicket, pitch dimensions, overs, how out, etc. were originally formulated. In 1728, the Duke of Richmond and Alan Brodick drew up Articles of Agreement to determine the code of practice in a particular game and this became a common feature, especially around payment of stake money and distributing the winnings given the importance of gambling.
        In 1744, the Laws of Cricket were codified for the first time and then amended in 1774, when innovations such as lbw, middle stump and maximum bat width were added. These laws stated that "the principals shall choose from amongst the gentlemen present two umpires who shall absolutely decide all disputes". The codes were drawn up by the so-called "Star and Garter Club" whose members ultimately founded the Marylebone Cricket Club at Lord's in 1787. The MCC immediately became the custodian of the Laws and has made periodic revisions and recodifications subsequently."</string>

    <string name="int_cric">"  In 1859, a team of leading English professionals set off to North America on the first-ever overseas tour and, in 1862, the first English team toured Australia. Between May and October 1868, a team of Aboriginal Australians toured England in what was the first Australian cricket team to travel overseas."</string>

    <string name="int_cric2">"  In 1877, an England touring team in Australia played two matches against full Australian XIs that are now regarded as the inaugural Test matches. The following year, the Australians toured England for the first time and the success of this tour ensured a popular demand for similar ventures in future. No Tests were played in 1878 but more soon followed and, at The Oval in 1882, the Australian victory in a tense finish gave rise to The Ashes.
        South Africa became the third Test nation in 1889."</string>

    <string name="nineteenth">"  The game also underwent a fundamental change of organisation with the formation for the first time of county clubs. All the modern county clubs, starting with Sussex in 1839, were founded during the 19th century. No sooner had the first county clubs established themselves than they faced what amounted to "player action" as William Clarke created the travelling All-England Eleven in 1846. Though a commercial venture, this team did much to popularise the game in districts which had never previously been visited by high-class cricketers. Other similar teams were created and this vogue lasted for about thirty years. But the counties and MCC prevailed."</string>

    <string name="nineteenth_2">"  The growth of cricket in the mid and late 19th century was assisted by the development of the railway network. For the first time, teams from a long distance apart could play one other without a prohibitively time-consuming journey. Spectators could travel longer distances to matches, increasing the size of crowds. Army units around the Empire had time on their hands, and encouraged the locals so they could have some entertaining competition. Most of the Empire embraced cricket, with the exception of Canada.
        In 1864, another bowling revolution resulted in the legalisation of overarm and in the same year Wisden Cricketers' Almanack was first published. W. G. Grace began his long and influential career at this time, his feats doing much to increase cricket's popularity. He introduced technical innovations which revolutionised the game, particularly in batting."</string>

    <string name="growth">"  Cricket rose to prominence in Britain during a period where the British Empire became the largest empire in the world. British colonial authorities often collaborated with native elites, who were encouraged to adopt British cultural traditions such as cricket, which during the 19th century was promoted as an emblematic element of Victorian masculinity.[38] Throughout the British empire, cricket was included as part of the physical activities which students at colonial schools engaged in.[39][40] For the colonial subjects of the British Empire, cricket grew in popularity for a variety of reasons. For native elites, playing the sport was a method of anglicising themselves, while for anti-colonial nationalists, playing cricket provided a venue for them to counter emasculating colonial stereotypes."</string>

    <string name="natchamp">"  A significant development in domestic cricket occurred in 1890 when the official County Championship was constituted in England. Soon afterwards, in May 1894, the sport's first-class standard was officially defined.[44] This organisational initiative has been repeated in other countries. Australia established the Sheffield Shield in 1892 to 1893. Other national competitions to be established were the Currie Cup in South Africa, the Plunket Shield in New Zealand and the Ranji Trophy in India. The ICC re-defined first-class status in 1947 as a global concept"</string>

    <string name="natchamp2">"  The period from 1890 to the outbreak of the First World War has become one of nostalgia, ostensibly because the teams played cricket according to "the spirit of the game", but more realistically because it was a peacetime period that was shattered by the First World War. The era has been called The Golden Age of cricket and it featured numerous great names such as Grace, Wilfred Rhodes, C. B. Fry, Ranjitsinhji and Victor Trumper."</string>

    <string name="growth_int_cric">"  Cricket was introduced to various colonies around the world. The Imperial Cricket Conference (ICC) was founded in 1909 with England, Australia and South Africa as the founding members. The ICC included the Marylebone Cricket club, the Australian Board of Control for International Cricket, and the South African Cricket Association as its original associations . The conference aimed to regulate international cricket among three nations, which were considered to be of equal status at the time.
        In 1926, both New Zealand and the West Indies were admitted as members, allowing them to play Test cricket against the other sides. However, at this time in the West Indies, cricket was primarily dominated by the white population. Originally, the ICC was not interested in broadening the international popularity of cricket. The organization was reluctant to invite non-commonwealth nations to play. New Zealand was restricted to play three-day test matches. New Zealand and India both became Test playing nations before World War II and Pakistan joined soon afterwards in 1952.
        At the initial suggestion of Pakistan, the ICC was expanded to include non-Test playing countries from 1965, with Associate members being admitted. At the same time the organisation changed its name to the International Cricket Conference. The first limited-overs World Cups were played during the 1970s and Sri Lanka became the first Associate member to be raised to Test playing status in 1982. Because the ICC was predominantly a Western organization, the founding countries decided who was allowed to join the conference or engage in test cricket. There was no desire or attempt to create a set of Associate nations that would play in Test status, which is why countries such as Sri Lanka were not permitted to partake until the 1980s.
        The international game continued to grow with the introduction of Affiliate Member status in 1984, a level of membership designed for sides with less history of playing cricket. In 1989 the ICC renamed itself the International Cricket Council. Zimbabwe became Full Members in 1992 and Bangladesh in 2000 before Afghanistan and Ireland were both admitted as Test sides in 2018, bringing the number of full members of the ICC to 12."</string>

    <string name="world_series">"  The money problems of top cricketers were also the root cause of another cricketing crisis that arose in 1977 when the Australian media magnate Kerry Packer fell out with the Australian Cricket Board over TV rights. Taking advantage of the low remuneration paid to players, Packer retaliated by signing several of the best players in the world to a privately run cricket league outside the structure of international cricket. World Series Cricket hired some of the banned South African players and allowed them to show off their skills in an international arena against other world-class players. The schism lasted only until 1979 and the "rebel" players were allowed back into established international cricket, though many found that their national teams had moved on without them. Long-term results of World Series Cricket have included the introduction of significantly higher player salaries and innovations such as coloured kit and night games."</string>

    <string name="expansion">"  In June 2001, the ICC introduced a "Test Championship Table" and, in October 2002, a "One-day International Championship Table". As indicated by ICC rankings,[63] the various cricket formats have continued to be a major competitive sport in most former British Empire countries, notably the Indian subcontinent, and new participants including the Netherlands. In 2017, the number of countries with full ICC membership was increased to twelve by the addition of Afghanistan and Ireland.[64] The ICC expanded its development programme, aiming to produce more national teams capable of competing at the various formats. Development efforts are focused on African and Asian nations, and on the United States. In 2004, the ICC Intercontinental Cup brought first-class cricket to 12 nations, mostly for the first time."</string>

    <string name="ipl">"  In April 2007, Essel Group launched the Indian Cricket League (ICL), in partnership with IL&amp;FS. The ICL was not recognized by the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) or the International Cricket Council (ICC). Moreover, the BCCI was unhappy about its committee members joining the ICL executive board. In response, the BCCI increased the prize money for its domestic tournaments and imposed lifetime bans on players who joined the ICL, which it considered a rebel league."</string>
    
    <string name="no_of_players">"  A match is played between two sides, each of eleven players, one of whom shall be captain. By agreement a match may be played between sides of fewer than, or more than, eleven players, but not more than eleven players may field at any time. If, during the match and for whatever reason, a side is reduced to fewer than the original number of nominated players, the match shall continue as long as it is possible to do so under the Laws or any agreements made before the toss."</string>
    
    <string name="nom_and_rep1">"<b>1.2.1</b> Each captain shall nominate his/her players in writing to one of the umpires before the toss."</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep2">"<b>1.2.2</b> No player may be replaced after the nomination without the consent of the opposing captain."</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep3">"<b>1.2.3</b> Any replacement player shall be considered the same player as the nominated player he/she replaced for the purposes of these Laws.\n"</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep4">"1.2.3.1 A replacement shall not bat in an innings in which the nominated player he/she is replacing has completed his/her innings.\n "</string>
    <string name="nom_and_rep5">"1.2.3.2 Any unserved Penalty time, warnings or suspensions, that applied to the original nominated player will be inherited by his/her replacement."</string>

    <string name="captain">"  <b>1.3.1</b> If at any time the captain is not available, a deputy shall act for him/her.\n
        <b>1.3.2</b> If a captain is not available to nominate the players, then any person associated with that team may act as his/her deputy to do so. See 1.2.\n
        <b>1.3.3</b> At any time after the nomination of the players, only a nominated player can act as deputy in discharging the duties and responsibilities of the captain as stated in these Laws, including at the toss. See Law 13.4 (The toss)."</string>

    <string name="ump1">"Before the match, two umpires shall be appointed, one for each end, to control the match as required by the Laws, with absolute impartiality.  The umpires shall be present on the ground and report to the Executive of the ground at least 45 minutes before the scheduled start of each day’s play."</string>

    <string name="ump2">"An umpire shall not be changed during the match, other than in exceptional circumstances, unless he/she is injured or ill.  If there has to be a change of umpire, the replacement shall act only as the striker’s end umpire unless the captains agree that the replacement should take full responsibility as an umpire. "</string>

    <string name="ump3">"Before the toss the umpires shall\n<b>2.3.1</b> meet with the captains; the umpires shall determine"</string>

    <string name="ump3.1">"2.3.1.1 the balls to be used during the match.  See Law 4 (The ball)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.2">"2.3.1.2 the hours of play and the times and durations of any agreed intervals.  In a match of one day’s duration, no specific time need be agreed for the tea interval.  It may be agreed instead to take this interval between innings.  See Law 11 (Intervals)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.3">"2.3.1.3 which clock or watch and back-up time piece is to be used during the match."</string>
    <string name="ump3.4">"2.3.1.4 the boundary of the field of play and allowances for boundaries, including whether any obstacle within the field of play is to be regarded as a boundary.  See Law 19 (Boundaries)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.5">"2.3.1.5 the use of covers. See Law 10 (Covering the pitch)."</string>
    <string name="ump3.6">"2.3.1.6 any special conditions of play affecting the conduct of the match."</string>
    <string name="ump3.7">"<b>2.3.2</b>  inform the scorers of agreements in 2.3.1.2, 2.3.1.3, 2.3.1.4 and 2.3.1.6."</string>
    
    <string name="ump4">"Before the toss and during the match, the umpires shall satisfy themselves that\n<b>2.4.1</b> the wickets are properly pitched.  See Law 8 (The wickets)"</string>
    <string name="ump4.1">"<b>2.4.2</b> the creases are correctly marked.  See Law 7 (The creases)."</string>
    <string name="ump4.2">"<b>2.4.3</b> the boundary of the field of play complies with the requirements of Laws 19.1 (Determining the boundary of the field of play), 19.2 (Identifying and marking the boundary) and 19.3 (Restoring the boundary)."</string>

    <string name="ump5">"Before the toss and during the match, the umpires shall satisfy themselves that\n<b>2.5.1</b> the conduct of the match is strictly in accordance with the Laws."</string>
    <string name="ump5.1">"<b>2.5.2</b> the implements used in the match conform to the following:"</string>
    <string name="ump5.2">"2.5.2.1 Law 4 (The ball)."</string>
    <string name="ump5.3">"2.5.2.2 externally visible requirements of Law 5 (The bat) and Appendix B."</string>
    <string name="ump5.4">"2.5.2.3 either Laws 8.2 (Size of stumps) and 8.3 (The bails) or, if applicable, Law 8.4 (Junior cricket)."</string>
    <string name="ump5.5">"<b>2.5.3</b> no player uses equipment other than that permitted.  See Appendix A.2.  Note particularly therein the interpretation of ‘protective helmet’."</string>
    <string name="ump5.6">"<b>2.5.4</b> the wicket-keeper’s gloves comply with the requirements of Law 27.2 (Gloves)."</string>

    <string name="ump6">"The umpires shall be the sole judges of fair and unfair play."</string>

    <string name="ump7">"<b>2.7.1</b> It is solely for the umpires together to decide whether either conditions of ground, weather or light or exceptional circumstances mean that it would be dangerous or unreasonable for play to take place.
        Conditions shall not be regarded as either dangerous or unreasonable merely because they are not ideal.
        The fact that the grass and the ball are wet does not warrant the ground conditions being regarded as unreasonable or dangerous."</string>

    <string name="ump7.1">"<b>2.7.2</b> Conditions shall be regarded as dangerous if there is actual and foreseeable risk to the safety of any player or umpire."</string>
    <string name="ump7.2">"<b>2.7.3</b> Conditions shall be regarded as unreasonable if, although posing no risk to safety, it would not be sensible for play to proceed."</string>
    <string name="ump7.3">"<b>2.7.4</b> If the umpires consider the ground is so wet or slippery as to deprive the bowler of a reasonable foothold, the fielders of the power of free movement, or the batter of the ability to play their strokes or to run between the wickets, then these conditions shall be regarded as so bad that it would be dangerous and unreasonable for play to take place."</string>

    <string name="ump8">"<b>2.8.1</b> All references to ground include the pitch.  See Law 6.1 (Area of pitch)."</string>
    <string name="ump8.1">"<b>2.8.2</b> The Umpires shall immediately suspend play, or not allow play to start or to recommence, if either umpire considers that the conditions of ground, weather or light, or any other circumstances are either dangerous or unreasonable."</string>
    <string name="ump8.2">"<b>2.8.3</b> When there is a suspension of play it is the responsibility of the umpires to monitor conditions.  They shall make inspections as often as appropriate, unaccompanied by any players or officials.  Immediately the umpires together agree that the conditions are no longer dangerous or unreasonable they shall call upon the players to resume play."</string>

    <string name="ump9">"The umpires shall stand where they can best see any act upon which their decision may be required.
        Subject to this over-riding consideration, the bowler’s end umpire shall stand in a position so as not to interfere with either the bowler’s run-up or the striker’s view.
        The striker’s end umpire may elect to stand on the off side instead of the on side of the pitch, provided he/she informs the captain of the fielding side, the striker and the other umpire."</string>

    <string name="ump10">"The umpires shall change ends after each side has had one completed innings.  See Law 13.3 (Completed innings)."</string>

    <string name="ump11">"Where there is disagreement or dispute about any matter, the umpires together shall make the final decision.  See also Law 31.6 (Consultation by umpires)."</string>

    <string name="ump12">"An umpire may alter any decision provided that such alteration is made promptly and does not contradict Law 20.6 (Dead ball not to be revoked). This apart, an umpire’s decision, once made, is final."</string>

    <string name="ump13">"<b>2.13.1</b> The following code of signals shall be used by umpires:
        2.13.1.1 Signals made while the ball is in play
        Dead ball - by crossing and re-crossing the wrists below the waist.
        No ball - by extending one arm horizontally.
        Out - by raising an index finger above the head. (If not out, the umpire shall call Not out.)
        Wide - by extending both arms horizontally.
        2.13.1.2 When the ball is dead, the bowler’s end umpire shall repeat the signals in 2.13.1.1, with the exception of the signal for Out, to the scorers.
        2.13.1.3  The signals listed below shall be made to the scorers only when the ball is dead.
        Boundary 4 - by waving an arm from side to side finishing with the arm across the chest.
        Boundary 6 - by raising both arms above the head.
        Bye - by raising an open hand above the head.
        Commencement of last hour - by pointing to a raised wrist with the other hand.
        Five Penalty runs awarded to the batting side - by repeated tapping of one shoulder with the opposite hand.
        Five Penalty runs awarded to the fielding side - by placing one hand on the opposite shoulder.
        Leg bye - by touching a raised knee with the hand.
        New ball - by holding the ball above the head.
        Revoke the last decision - by touching both shoulders, each with the opposite hand.
        Short run - by bending one arm upwards and touching the nearer shoulder with the tips of the fingers.
        The following signals are for Levels 3 and 4 of the player conduct offences.  Each signal has two parts, both of which should be acknowledged separately by the scorers.
        Level 3 conduct
        Part 1 - by putting one arm out to the side of the body and repeatedly raising it and lowering it.
        Part 2 - by raising both hands, all fingers spread, to shoulder height, palms facing towards the scorers.
        Level 4 conduct
        Part 1 - by putting one arm out to the side of the body and repeatedly raising it and lowering it.
        Part 2 - by raising an index finger, held at shoulder height, to the side of the body.
        2.13.1.4  All the signals in 2.13.1.3 are to be made by the bowler’s end umpire except that for Short run, which is to be signalled by the umpire at the end where short running occurs.  However, the bowler’s end umpire shall be responsible both for the final signal of Short run to the scorers and, if more than one run is short, for informing them as to the number of runs to be recorded."</string>

    <string name="ump13.1">"<b>2.13.2</b> The umpire shall wait until each signal to the scorers has been separately acknowledged by a scorer before allowing play to proceed.
        If several signals are to be used, they SHALL be given in the order that the events occurred."</string>

    <string name="unp14">"Throughout the Laws, wherever the umpires are to receive information from captains or other players, it will be sufficient for one umpire to be so informed and for him/her to inform the other umpire."</string>
    <string name="ump15">"Consultation between umpires and scorers on doubtful points is essential.  The umpires shall, throughout the match, satisfy themselves as to the correctness of the number of runs scored, the wickets that have fallen and, where appropriate, the number of overs bowled.  They shall agree these with the scorers at least at every interval, other than a drinks interval, and at the conclusion of the match.  See Laws 3.2 (Correctness of scores), 16.8 (Correctness of result) and 16.10 (Result not to be changed)."</string>

    <string name="score">"Two scorers shall be appointed to record all runs scored, all wickets taken and, where appropriate, number of overs bowled."</string>
    <string name="score1">"The scorers shall frequently check to ensure that their records agree. They shall agree with the umpires, at least at every interval, other than drinks intervals, and at the conclusion of the match, the runs scored, the wickets that have fallen and, where appropriate, the number of overs bowled. See Law 2.15 (Correctness of scores)."</string>
    <string name="score2">"The scorers shall accept all instructions and signals given to them by the umpires and shall immediately acknowledge each separate signal."</string>

    <string name="ball">"The ball, when new, shall weigh not less than 5.5 ounces/155.9 g, nor more than 5.75 ounces/163 g, and shall measure not less than 8.81 in/22.4 cm, nor more than 9 in/22.9 cm in circumference."</string>
    <string name="ball1">"<b>4.2.1</b> All balls to be used in the match, having been determined by the umpires, shall be in the possession of the umpires before the toss and shall remain under their control throughout the match."</string>
    <string name="ball2">"<b>4.2.2</b> The umpire shall take possession of the ball in use at the fall of each wicket, at the start of any interval and at any interruption of play."</string>
    <string name="ball3">"Unless an agreement to the contrary has been made before the match, either captain may demand a new ball at the start of each innings."</string>
    <string name="ball4">"In a match of more than one day’s duration, the captain of the fielding side may demand a new ball when the number of overs, excluding any part overs, bowled with the old one is equal to or greater than 80 overs. The umpire shall inform the other umpire and indicate to the batters and the scorers whenever a new ball is taken into play."</string>
    <string name="ball5">"If, during play, the ball cannot be found or recovered or the umpires agree that it has become unfit for play through normal use, the umpires shall replace it with a ball which has had wear comparable with that which the previous ball had received before the need for its replacement. When the ball is replaced, the umpire shall inform the batters and the fielding captain.</string>
    <string name="ball6">"The specifications as described in 4.1 shall apply to men’s cricket only. The following specifications shall apply to:\n\n<b>4.6.1</b> Women’s cricket"</string>
    <string name="ball7">"Weight: from 4.94 ounces/140 g to 5.31 ounces/151 g\nCircumference: from 8.25 in/21.0 cm to 8.88 in/22.5 cm."</string>
    <string name="ball8">"<b>4.6.2</b> Junior cricket - Under 13"</string>
    <string name="ball9">" Weight: from 4.69 ounces/133 g to 5.06 ounces/144 g\nCircumference: from 8.06 in/20.5 cm to 8.69 in/22.0 cm."</string>

    <string name="bat">"<b>5.1.1</b> The bat consists of two parts, a handle and a blade."</string>
    <string name="bat1">"<b>5.1.2</b> The basic requirements and measurements of the bat are set out in this Law with detailed specifications in Appendix B."</string>
    <string name="bat2">"<b>5.2.1</b> The handle is to be made principally of cane and/or wood."</string>
    <string name="bat3">"<b>5.2.2</b> The part of the handle that is wholly outside the blade is defined to be the upper portion of the handle.  It is a straight shaft for holding the bat."</string>
    <string name="bat4">"<b>5.2.3</b> The upper portion of the handle may be covered with a grip as defined in Appendix B.2.2."</string>
    <string name="bat5">"<b>5.3.1</b> The blade comprises the whole of the bat apart from the handle as defined 5.2 and in Appendix B.3."</string>
    <string name="bat6">"<b>5.3.2</b> The blade shall consist solely of wood."</string>
    <string name="bat7">"<b>5.3.3</b> All bats may have commercial identifications on the blade, the size of which must comply with the relevant specification in Appendix B.6."</string>
    <string name="bat8">" Subject to the specifications in Appendix B.4 and providing 5.5 is not contravened,\n<b>5.4.1</b> solely for the purposes of
        either protection from surface damage to the face, sides and shoulders of the blade
        or repair to the blade after surface damage,
        material that is not rigid, either at the time of its application to the blade or subsequently, may be placed on these surfaces."</string>
    <string name="bat9">"<b>5.4.2</b> for repair of the blade after damage other than surface damage "</string>
    <string name="bat10">"5.4.2.1 solid material may be inserted into the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat11">"5.4.2.2 The only material permitted for any insertion is wood with minimal essential adhesives."</string>
    <string name="bat12">"<b>5.4.3</b>  to prevent damage to the toe, material may be placed on that part of the blade but shall not extend over any part of the face, back or sides of the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat13">"<b>5.5.1</b>  For any part of the bat, covered or uncovered, the hardness of the constituent materials and the surface texture thereof shall not be such that either or both could cause unacceptable damage to the ball."</string>
    <string name="bat14">"<b>5.5.2</b> Any material placed on any part of the bat, for whatever purpose, shall similarly not be such that it could cause unacceptable damage to the ball."</string>
    <string name="bat15">"<b>5.5.3</b> For the purpose of this Law, unacceptable damage is any change that is greater than normal wear and tear caused by the ball striking the uncovered wooden surface of the blade."</string>
    <string name="bat16">"In these Laws,\n<b>5.6.1</b> reference to the bat shall imply that the bat is held in the batter’s hand or a glove worn on his/her hand, unless stated otherwise."</string>
    <string name="bat17">"<b>5.6.2</b> contact between the ball and any of 5.6.2.1 to 5.6.2.4"</string>
    <string name="bat18">"5.6.2.1 the bat itself\n5.6.2.2 the batter’s hand holding the bat\n5.6.2.3 any part of a glove worn on the batter’s hand holding the bat\n5.6.2.4 any additional materials permitted under 5.4 shall be regarded as the ball striking or touching the bat or being struck by the bat."</string>
    <string name="bat19">"<b>5.7.1</b> The overall length of the bat, when the lower portion of the handle is inserted, shall not be more than 38 in/96.52 cm."</string>
    <string name="bat20">"<b>5.7.2</b> The blade of the bat shall not exceed the following dimensions:</string>
    <string name="bat21">"Width: 4.25in / 10.8 cm\nDepth: 2.64in / 6.7 cm\nEdges: 1.56in / 4.0cm.\nFurthermore, it should also be able to pass through a bat gauge as described in Appendix B.8. "</string>
    <string name="bat22">"<b>5.7.3</b> Except for bats of size 6 and less, the handle shall not exceed 52% of the overall length of the bat.."</string>
    <string name="bat23">"<b>5.7.4</b> The material permitted for covering the blade in 5.4.1 shall not exceed 0.04 in/0.1 cm in thickness."</string>
    <string name="bat24">"<b>5.7.5</b> The maximum permitted thickness of protective material placed on the toe of the blade is 0.12 in/0.3 cm."</string>
    <string name="bat25">"<b>5.8.1</b> Types A, B and C are bats conforming to 5.1 to 5.7 inclusive. "</string>
    <string name="bat26">"<b>5.8.2</b> Type A bats may be used at any level of cricket. "</string>
    <string name="bat27">"<b>5.8.3</b> 5.8.3 The specifications for Type D bats are described in Appendix B.7 and are for use by junior players in junior cricket only. "</string>
    <string name="bat28">"<b>5.8.4</b> Bats of Type B, Type C, Type D and any other bats may be used only at or below levels determined by the Governing Body for cricket in the country concerned. "</string>
    <string name="bat29">"<b>5.8.5</b> 5.8.5 Bats that do not qualify for any of the four categories A to D are not recognised in the Laws. "</string>

    <string name="pitch">"The pitch is a rectangular area of the ground 22 yards/20.12 m in length and 10 ft/3.05 m in width.  It is bounded at either end by the bowling creases and on either side by imaginary lines, one each side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps, each parallel to it and 5 ft/1.52 m from it.  If the pitch is next to an artificial pitch which is closer than 5 ft/1.52 m from the middle stumps, the pitch on that side will extend only to the junction of the two surfaces.  See Laws 8.1 (Description, width and pitching), 8.4 (Junior cricket) and 7.2 (The bowling crease)."</string>
    <string name="pitch1">"The umpires shall be the sole judges of the fitness of the pitch for play.  See Laws 2.7 (Fitness for play) and 2.8 (Suspension of play in dangerous or unreasonable conditions)."</string>
    <string name="pitch2">"Before the match, the Ground Authority shall be responsible for the selection and preparation of the pitch.  During the match, the umpires shall control its use and maintenance."</string>
    <string name="pitch3">"The pitch shall not be changed during the match unless the umpires decide that it is dangerous or unreasonable for play to continue on it and then only with the consent of both captains."</string>
    <string name="pitch4">"In the event of a non-turf pitch being used, the artificial surface shall conform to the following measurements:\nLength - a minimum of 58 ft/17.68 m\nWidth - a minimum of 6 ft/1.83 m\nSee Law 9.8 (Non-turf pitches)."</string>
    <string name="pitch5">"The Governing Body for cricket in the country concerned shall determine the length of the pitch for junior cricket."</string>

    <!-- Filter Categories Array -->
    <string-array name="filter_categories">
        <item>Filter Laws</item>
        <item>Setting Up</item>
        <item>Innings and Result</item>
        <item>The Over, Scoring Runs, Dead Ball and Extras</item>
        <item>Players, Substitutes, Runners and Practice</item>
        <item>Appeals and Dismissals</item>
        <item>Unfair Play</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="crease">"The positions of a bowling crease, a popping crease and two return creases shall be marked by white lines, as set out in 7.2, 7.3 and 7.4, at each end of the pitch.  See Appendix C."</string>
    <string name="crease2">"The bowling crease, which is the back edge of the crease marking, is the line that marks the end of the pitch, as in Law 6.1 (Area of pitch).  It shall be 8 ft 8 in/2.64 m in length."</string>
    <string name="crease3">"The popping crease, which is the back edge of the crease marking, shall be in front of and parallel to the bowling crease and shall be 4 ft/1.22 m from it.  The popping crease shall be marked to a minimum of 6 ft/1.83 m on either side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps and shall be considered to be unlimited in length."</string>
    <string name="crease4">"The return creases, which are the inside edges of the crease markings, shall be at right angles to the popping crease at a distance of 4 ft 4 in/1.32 m either side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps.  Each return crease shall be marked from the popping crease to a minimum of 8 ft/2.44 m behind it and shall be considered to be unlimited in length."</string>

    <string-array name="issue_categories">
        <item>Select Category</item>
        <item>Bug Report</item>
        <item>Feature Request</item>
        <item>Performance Issue</item>
        <item>UI/UX Issue</item>
        <item>Crash Report</item>
        <item>Data Sync Issue</item>
        <item>Login/Authentication</item>
        <item>Other</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="sachin_born">"24 April 1973, Mumbai, India"</string>
    <string name="sachin_education">"Sharadashram Vidyamandir School, Mumbai"</string>
    <string name="sachin_occupation">"Former Indian Cricketer, Cricket Mentor"</string>
    <string name="sachin_highlights">"Sachin Tendulkar was the most complete batter of his time, the most prolific run-maker of all time, and arguably the biggest cricket icon the game has ever known.His batting was based on the purest principles: perfect balance, economy of movement, precision in stroke-making, and that intangible quality given only to genius batters - anticipation.Some of his finest performances came against Australia, the dominant team of his era.\n\nHis century as a 19-year-old on a lightning-fast pitch at the WACA is considered one of the best innings ever to have been played in that country. A few years later he received the ultimate compliment from the ultimate batter: Don Bradman confided to his wife that Tendulkar reminded him of himselfBlessed with the keenest of cricket minds, and driven by a loathing for defeat, Tendulkar established his greatness early. He was only 16 when he made his Test debut, and was hit in the face by Waqar Younis in that game, but continued to bat.He holds the record for most hundreds in both Tests and ODIs - remarkable, considering he didn't score his first ODI hundred until his 79th match.He became the first player to score 100 international centuries.\n\nTendulkar's considerable achievements seem greater still when looked at in the light of the burden of expectation he had to bear from his adoring but somewhat unreasonable followers, who were prone to regarding anything less than a hundred in every innings as a failure. He still remains, by a distance, the most worshipped cricketer in the world.He is  known as the "God of Cricket" and the "Master Blaster"."</string>

    <!-- Shane Warne -->
    <string name="shane_born">"13 September 1969, Victoria, Australia"</string>
    <string name="shane_education">"Mentone Grammar School, Victoria"</string>
    <string name="shane_occupation">"Former Australian Cricketer, Cricket Commentator"</string>
    <string name="shane_highlights">"When Warne likened his life to a soap opera he was selling himself short. His story was part fairytale, part pantomime, part hospital drama, part adult's-only romp, part glittering awards ceremony. He took a Test hat-trick, won the Man-of-the-Match prize in a World Cup final and was the subject of seven books. He was the first cricketer to reach 700 Test wickets. He swatted more runs than any other Test player without making a hundred, and was probably the wiliest captain Australia never had. His ball that gazoodled Mike Gatting in 1993, bouncing outside leg stump and cuffing off, is unanimously esteemed the most famous in history. He revived legspin, thought to be extinct, and is now pre-eminent in a game so transformed that we sometimes wonder where the next champion fast bowlers will come from.\n\nWarne's love of the game went beyond simple things like retirement and it was exemplified by how he was still in the thick of it all in 2008, leading a rag-tag bunch of players at Rajasthan Royals to the Indian Premier League title. Finally, and amid much fanfare, Warne left the field once again, but he didn't go very far. He couldn't. Not with that amazing mind of his, which he put to use as a commentator, often calling the plays before they even happened."</string>

    <!-- Ricky Ponting -->
    <string name="ricky_born">"19 December 1974, Launceston, Tasmania</string>
    <string name="ricky_education">"Brooks High School, Tasmania</string>
    <string name="ricky_occupation">"Former Australian Captain, Cricket Coach</string>
    <string name="ricky_highlights">"Ricky Ponting, the most uncompromising player of his generation, grew into Australia's most successful run-maker and sits below only Bradman among the greatest batters the country has produced.He finished with 27,483 runs and 71 hundreds in international cricket, the second-most prolific Test scorer when he retired, behind Sachin Tendulkar.Ponting played all the shots with a full flourish of the bat - the cover drive and the pull were particularly productive for him - and knew only to attack. His breathtaking, dead-eye fielding was a force in the game by itself.\n\nBetween 2002 and 2008, he only went two years without scoring at least 1000 runs apiece in Tests. In ODIs he pulled the feat off in six years, including 2003, when in the World Cup final he pummelled 140 unbeaten runs against India, taking the title off them before their chase had even started.As captain, Ponting was a little less dominantly successful, but his record was magnificent all the same: 48 wins in 77 Tests gave him a win percentage second only to Steve Waugh in the game's history, despite defeats in three Ashes series and against South Africa and India. He also led Australia to 26 consecutive undefeated (completed) 50-over World Cup games."</string>

    <!-- Brian Lara -->
    <string name="brian_born">2 May 1969, Santa Cruz, Trinidad and Tobago</string>
    <string name="brian_education">Fatima College, Trinidad</string>
    <string name="brian_occupation">Former West Indies Cricketer</string>
    <string name="brian_highlights">"No one since Bradman built massive scores as often and as fast as Brian Lara in his pomp, and with such elegance. Even his stance was thrilling - the bat raised high in the air, the weight poised on a bent front knee, the eyes low and level. Then the guillotine would fall, sending the ball flashing to the boundary.In the space of two months in 1994, Lara's 375 and 501 not out broke world records for the highest Test and first class scores, but sudden fame seemed to turn him into a confused and contradictory figure.\n\nDuring an inventive but largely fruitless spell as captain of a fading West Indies team, Lara reiterated his genius by single handedly defying the 1998 to 1999 Australian tourists with a sequence of 213, 8, 153 not out and 100.Leading a side where he was far and away the best player and where discipline was a constant worry. But then, just when all hope seemed to have deserted West Indies cricket, Lara responded to the prospect of a home series whitewash with an astonishing unbeaten 400 in the final Test against England in Antigua in 2004. In doing so, he became the first man to reclaim the world Test batting record."</string>

    <!-- Wasim Akram -->
    <string name="wasim_born">3 June 1966, Lahore, Pakistan</string>
    <string name="wasim_education">Government Islamia College, Lahore</string>
    <string name="wasim_occupation">Former Pakistani Cricketer, Cricket Commentator</string>
    <string name="wasim_highlights">"A dream cricketer. At his best Wasim Akram plays like most of us would wish to. He has complete mastery over swing and seam, and sometimes moves the ball both ways in one delivery. All this comes at high speed from a quick, ball concealing action, and is backed up by the threat of a dangerous bouncer or deceptive slower delivery. Akram is rated by many as the best left arm fast bowler of all time, and his career record certainly bears that out-along with the high regard of his contemporaries.\n\nHe hit like a kicking horse. He scored a monumental 257 against Zimbabwe in Sheikhupura in 1996 to 1997. He was the natural successor to Imran Khan as Pakistan's leader and captain.He reached the 500-wicket landmark in ODIs in the 2003 World Cup.He is often revered as The Sultan of Swing.He retired after, following a brief spell with Hampshire."</string>

    <!-- Jacques Kallis -->
    <string name="jacques_born">"16 October 1975, Cape Town, South Africa"</string>
    <string name="jacques_education">"Wynberg Boys' High School, Cape Town"</string>
    <string name="jacques_occupation">"Former South African Cricketer"</string>
    <string name="jacques_highlights">"No batsman prizes his wicket more highly, and no wicket in all of cricket is more highly prized. Jacques Kallis is the broad-shouldered colossus of the South African team, a figure whose looming presence inspires calm in some and dread in others.Few players who belong to the modern age are a better fit for the notion of the classical cricketer. Kallis is a fine, forceful batsman who has at his disposal both a rock-solid technique and a mind impervious to distraction. Though his role as a bowler diminishes with each passing season, he will be remembered as a purveyor of sometimes surprising pace and swing, and awkward bounce. In the slips, his sure-handedness and rattlesnake reflexes make ridiculous catches look regulation.\n\nOver the years Kallis has delivered many such innings, performances in which grit is a far more valuable commodity than glitz to a South African team that remains more confident in the field and with its fast bowlers in full cry than as a batting unit.Certainly, his lofted drive, which begins with a menacing backlift before uncoiling into the irresistible momentum of a mighty downward swoop of the bat and finishing in a twirl of Baroque, might be described as Mozart in motion. In the lightning flash of that fleeting instant it really does seem as if Kallis could, in the words of one observer, hit a six whenever he felt like it."</string>

    <!-- Adam Gilchrist -->
    <string name="adam_born">"14 November 1971, Bellingen, Australia"</string>
    <string name="adam_education">"Kadina High School, New South Wales"</string>
    <string name="adam_occupation">"Former Australian Cricketer, Commentator"</string>
    <string name="adam_highlights">"Going in first or seventh, wearing whites or coloureds, Adam Gilchrist was the symbolic heart of 2000s Australia's steamrolling agenda and the most exhilarating cricketer of the modern age. He was simultaneously a cheerful throwback to more innocent times, a flap-eared country boy who walked when given not out in a World Cup semi-final, and one who swatted his second ball for six while sitting on a Test pair.\n\n"Just hit the ball," is how he once described his philosophy on batting, and he seldom strayed from it. Employing a high-on-the-handle grip, Gilchrist poked good balls into gaps and throttled most others, invariably with head straight, wrists soft and balance sublime. Only at the death did he jettison the textbook, whirling his bat like a hammer-thrower. Still he managed to score at a tempo - 81 per 100 balls in Tests, 96 in ODIs - that made Viv Richards and Gilbert Jessop look like sticks in the-mud.His 472 dismissals in ODIs are the most by an Australian keeper."</string>

    <!-- Muttiah Muralitharan -->
    <string name="murali_born">"17 April 1972, Kandy, Sri Lanka"</string>
    <string name="murali_education">"St. Anthony's College, Kandy"</string>
    <string name="murali_occupation">"Former Sri Lankan Cricketer"</string>
    <string name="murali_highlights">"Perhaps no cricketer since Douglas Jardine has polarised opinion quite like Muthiah Muralidaran. For the believers, he's among the greatest to ever spin a ball. For the doubters, he's a charlatan undeserving of the game's greatest records, responsible for changes in the laws that they think have legitimised throwing. What was undeniable was his ability to turn the ball sharply on just about any surface, and bowl the sort of marathon spells that would have seen a lesser man retire after five seasons rather than 18. Whether Sri Lanka played at home, on pitches where he was often unplayable, or overseas, Murali was the go-to man for half a dozen captains.He seldom disappointed.\n\n It was only with his mastering the doosra, the one that went the other way or held its line, that he became Shane Warne's rival in the wicket-taking and greatness stakes.Part of the World Cup-winning side in 1996, he was instrumental in the run to the final 11 years later, and he played his part in some of the country's greatest sporting moments. It was his 16 wickets that helped rout England at The Oval in 1998, back in the days when Sri Lanka were deemed worthy of only one Test. He averaged less than 30 with the ball in every country except India and Australia, and he finished a remarkable Test career with more than 100 wickets against India, England and South Africa."</string>

    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <string name="fullscreen_image">Fullscreen Image</string>



    <!-- privacy policy -->
    <string name="privacy_policy_content">" Privacy Policy for CricTech Effective Date: August 7, 2025 Last Updated: August 7, 2025 CricTech Private Ltd ("CricTech", "we", "our", or "us") respects the privacy of users and is committed to protecting it through this Privacy Policy. This document outlines how we collect, use, store, and protect your data when you use our mobile application and related services (collectively referred to as the "App"). 1. Scope of this Policy This Privacy Policy applies to all users of the CricTech mobile application. By using the App, you agree to the terms of this policy. \n\n 2. Information We Collect As of now, CricTech does not collect any personal data from users. The App does not request, store, or transmit any personally identifiable information (such as name, email, age, location, etc.). In future updates, the App may integrate services such as Firebase and other APIs, which may involve data collection. This policy will be updated accordingly before such features go live. \n\n 3. Use of Information Since no personal information is currently collected, CricTech does not use any user data for personalization, targeting, analytics, or communication. \n\n 4. Sharing of Information We do not share any user data with third parties, advertisers, or service providers at this time. \n\n 5. Third-Party Services At present, CricTech does not integrate with any third-party analytics, advertising, or tracking services. However, in the future, we may include services such as: - Firebase (for analytics and crash reporting) - Cricket APIs (for live scores and data) Any integration will be governed by the privacy policies of those third parties, and users will be informed accordingly. \n\n 6. Children's Privacy CricTech is a general-purpose cricket information app and does not contain any harmful content, ads, or gambling features. It is safe for users of all ages, including children. We currently do not collect any personal data from any users, including minors. If that changes in future updates, we'll update this policy and ensure full compliance with relevant laws. \n\n 7. Security Measures We are committed to protecting your information and follow standard security practices to ensure that user data, if collected in the future, is handled safely and in accordance with applicable Indian laws. \n\n 8. User Rights As the App currently does not store or process any user data, user rights such as access, correction, or deletion are not applicable at this time. When data collection begins in future versions, appropriate rights and options will be offered. \n\n 9. Data Retention Since we do not collect any personal data currently, there is no data retained or stored on our servers or third-party services. Future data retention practices will be disclosed if features are added. \n\n 10. Changes to this Policy We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Changes will be communicated via the App, and users are encouraged to review this policy regularly. \n\n 11. Grievance Redressal If you have any questions, concerns, or grievances regarding this Privacy Policy or the use of your data, you may contact our Grievance Officers: Grievance Officers: - Aariz - Krushna - Shravan - Ibrahim Grievance Email: ghulek13@gmail.com Registered Office Address: CricTech Private Ltd, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India \n\n 12. Governing Law This Privacy Policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of India. Any disputes shall fall under the jurisdiction of courts located in Mumbai, Maharashtra, India.\n\n" </string>
    <!--  about us  -->
    <string name="about_us_content">"At CricTech, we believe cricket is more than a game — it's a passion, a culture, and a way of life. Our mission is to bring fans closer to the sport they love through deep insights, timeless content, and a clean, smooth app experience.\n\n While we currently don't provide live scores, our app is packed with powerful cricket content to keep you informed and entertained:\n\n • Ground Insights – Discover the stories and stats behind iconic stadiums worldwide.\n\n • Cricket Terms Simplified – From "Duck" to "Doosra", we decode the game for fans of all levels.\n\n • Tournament Deep Dives – Explore the history and context of IPL, World Cups, BGT, and more.\n\n • Photo Gallery – Relive the biggest moments in cricket with curated image collections.\n\n We're building CricTech as a reliable, blazing-fast platform that celebrates the game — and in the near future, we plan to bring you live scores, real-time updates, and match coverage to complete your cricket experience.\n\n Your feedback matters.\n Help us improve CricTech and shape the future of cricket apps, together.\n\n" </string>
    <!--  Help And Support -->
    <string name="help_and_support_content"> "Welcome to the Help &amp; Support section of CricTech. We are here to guide you and answer common questions about using the app.\n\n What does CricTech offer? \n\n CricTech provides a variety of features designed to enhance your cricket knowledge and experience: \n\n • Cricket Terms – Simplified definitions for fans of all levels. \n\n • Stadium Information – Learn about iconic grounds and their history. \n\n • Umpire &amp; Expert Info – Know more about the people behind the decisions.\n\n • Photo Gallery – View memorable moments in cricket through curated images.\n\n • Highlights &amp; Memes – Enjoy fun, engaging content beyond scores.\n\n • Cricket Basics – Understand the games origin, laws, player roles, match formats, and major tournaments &amp; +leagues. \n\n • Rules &amp; Feedback Guide – Helps users understand how to navigate and use the feedback form. \n\n Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)\n\n Q1. What is CricTech? \n A. CricTech provides all the essential information about cricket, offering great knowledge and stunning photos to enrich your experience.\n\n Q2. Does CricTech follow official rules? \n A. Yes, CricTech respects and follows official cricket rules and guidelines.\n\n Q3. Can I give feedback or report issues? \n A. Yes, you can! We have a feedback form available in the hamburger menu for your suggestions and reports. \n\n Q4. Is CricTech safe to use? \n A. Yes, completely. CricTech boosts your knowledge about the game and does not promote gambling or contain any unsafe content. \n\n Contact Us \n\n If you have any other queries or suggestions, feel free to reach out to us at: crichtech@gmail.com \n\n We're constantly working to make CricTech better. \n \n Thank you for being a part of our journey!\n" </string>

    <string name="meme_image_description">Meme image</string>

    <string name="wickets">"Two sets of wickets shall be pitched opposite and parallel to each other in the centres of the bowling creases.  Each set shall be 9 in/22.86 cm wide and shall consist of three wooden stumps with two wooden bails on top.  See Appendix D."</string>
    <string name="wickets2">"The tops of the stumps shall be 28 in/71.12 cm above the playing surface and shall be dome shaped except for the bail grooves.  The portion of a stump above the playing surface shall be cylindrical apart from the domed top, with circular section of diameter not less than 1.38 in/3.50 cm nor more than 1.5 in/3.81 cm.  See Appendix D".</string>
    <string name="wickets3">"<b>8.3.1</b>The bails, when in position on top of the stumps,"</string>
    <string name="wickets4">"- shall not project more than 0.5 in/1.27 cm above them.\n- shall fit between the stumps without forcing them out of the vertical."</string>
    <string name="wickets5">"<b>8.3.2</b>Each bail shall conform to the following specifications (see Appendix D):"</string>
    <string name="wickets6">"Overall length - 4.31 in/10.95 cm\nLength of barrel - 2.13 in /5.40 cm\nLonger spigot - 1.38 in/3.50 cm\nShorter spigot - 0.81 in/2.06 cm.\n"</string>
    <string name="wickets7">"<b>8.3.3</b>The two spigots and the barrel shall have the same centre line."</string>
    <string name="wickets8">"<b>8.3.4</b>Devices aimed at protecting player safety by limiting the distance that a bail can travel off the stumps will be allowed, subject to the approval of the Governing Body for the match and the ground authority."</string>
    <string name="wickets9">"The Governing Body for cricket in the country concerned shall determine the dimensions of the stumps and bails."</string>
    <string name="wickets10">"The umpires may agree to dispense with the use of bails, if necessary.  If they so agree then no bails shall be used at either end.  The use of bails shall be resumed as soon as conditions permit.  See Law 29.5 (Dispensing with bails)."</string>

    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area">"The pitch shall not be rolled during the match except as permitted in 9.1.1 and 9.1.2."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area2">"<b>9.1.1</b>During the match the pitch may be rolled at the request of the captain of the batting side, for a period of not more than 7 minutes, before the start of each innings, other than the first innings of the match, and before the start of each subsequent day’s play.  See 9.1.4."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area3">"<b>9.1.2</b>In addition to the rolling permitted above, if, after the toss and before the first innings of the match, the start is delayed, the captain of the batting side may request that the pitch be rolled for not more than 7 minutes.  However, if the umpires together agree that the delay has had no significant effect on the state of the pitch, they shall refuse such request for rolling of the pitch."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area4">"<b>9.1.3</b>If there is more than one roller available the captain of the batting side shall choose which one is to be used."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area5">"<b>9.1.4</b>The rolling permitted (maximum 7 minutes) before play begins on any day shall be started not more than 30 minutes before the time scheduled or rescheduled for play to begin.  The captain of the batting side may, however, delay the start of such rolling until not less than 10 minutes before the time scheduled or rescheduled for play to begin."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area6">"<b>9.2.1</b>The pitch shall be cleared of any debris"</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area7">"<b>9.2.1.1</b>before the start of each day’s play.  This shall be after the completion of mowing and before any rolling, not earlier than 30 minutes nor later than 10 minutes before the time or any rescheduled time for start of play."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area8">"<b>9.2.1.2</b>between innings.  This shall precede rolling if any is to take place."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area9">"<b>9.2.1.3</b>at all intervals for meals."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area10">"<b>9.2.2</b>The clearance of debris in 9.2.1 shall be done by sweeping, except where the umpires consider that this may be detrimental to the surface of the pitch.  In this case the debris must be cleared from that area by hand, without sweeping."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area11">"<b>9.2.3</b>In addition to 9.2.1, debris may be cleared from the pitch by hand, without sweeping, before mowing and whenever either umpire considers it necessary."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area12">"<b>9.3.1</b>Responsibility for mowing"</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area13">"<b>9.3.1.1</b> All mowings which are carried out before the match shall be the sole responsibility of the Ground Authority."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area14">"<b>9.3.1.2</b>All subsequent mowings shall be carried out under the supervision of the umpires."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area15">"<b>9.3.2</b>The pitch and outfield\nIn order that throughout the match the ground conditions should be as nearly the same for both sides as possible, both the pitch and the outfield shall be mown on each day of the match on which play is expected to take place, if ground and weather conditions permit.\nIf, for reasons other than conditions of ground or weather, complete mowing of the outfield is not possible, the Ground Authority shall notify the captains and umpires of the procedure to be adopted for such mowing during the match."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area16">"<b>9.3.3</b>Timing of mowing"</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area17">"<b>9.3.3.1</b>Mowing of the pitch on any day shall be completed not later than 30 minutes before the time scheduled or rescheduled for play to begin on that day, before any sweeping prior to rolling.  If necessary, debris may be removed from the pitch before mowing, by hand, without sweeping.  See 9.2.3."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area18">"<b>9.3.3.2</b>Mowing of the outfield on any day shall be completed not later than 15 minutes before the time scheduled or rescheduled for play to begin on that day."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area19">"The pitch shall not be watered during the match."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area20">"Creases shall be re-marked whenever either umpire considers it necessary."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area21">"The umpires shall ensure that the holes made by the bowlers and batter are cleaned out and dried whenever necessary to facilitate play.\nIn matches of more than one day’s duration, the umpires shall allow, if necessary, the re-turfing of footholes made by the bowlers in their delivery strides, or the use of quick-setting fillings for the same purpose."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area22">"During play, umpires shall allow the players to secure their footholds by the use of sawdust provided that no damage to the pitch is caused and that Law 41 (Unfair play) is not contravened."</string>
    <string name="preparation_and_maintenance_of_playing_area23">"Wherever appropriate, the provisions set out in 9.1 to 9.7 shall apply."</string>

    <string name="covering_the_pitch">"The use of covers before the match is the responsibility of the Ground Authority and may include full covering if required.\nHowever, the Ground Authority shall grant suitable facility to the captains to inspect the pitch before the nomination of their players and to the umpires to discharge their duties as laid down in Laws 2 (The umpires), 6 (The pitch), 7 (The creases), 8 (The wickets), and 9 (Preparation and maintenance of the playing area)."</string>
    <string name="covering_the_pitch2">"Unless determined otherwise before the toss, on each night of the match and in inclement weather at any time during the match"</string>
    <string name="covering_the_pitch3">"<b>10.2.1</b>the whole pitch and a minimum of 4 ft/1.22 m beyond it at each end shall be covered."</string>
    <string name="covering_the_pitch4">"<b>10.2.2</b>the bowlers’ run-ups, where possible, shall be covered."</string>
    <string name="covering_the_pitch5">"<b>10.3.1</b>If after the toss the pitch is covered overnight, the covers shall be removed as soon as practicable on each day that play is expected to take place."</string>
    <string name="covering_the_pitch6">"<b>10.3.2</b>If covers are used during the day as protection from inclement weather, or if inclement weather delays the removal of overnight covers, they shall be removed promptly as soon as conditions allow."</string>

    <string name="intervals">"<b>11.1.1</b>The following shall be classed as intervals:\n- The period between close of play on one day and the start of the next day’s play.\n- Intervals between innings.\n- Intervals for meals.\n- Intervals for drinks.\n- Any other agreed interval."</string>
    <string name="intervals2">"<b>11.1.2</b>Only these intervals shall be considered as scheduled breaks for the purposes of Law 24.2.6."</string>
    <string name="intervals3">"<b>11.2.1</b>An interval for lunch or tea shall be of the duration determined under Law 2.3 (Consultation with captains), taken from the call of Time before the interval until the call of Play on resumption after the interval."</string>
    <string name="intervals4">"<b>11.2.2</b>An interval between innings shall be 10 minutes, commencing from the close of an innings until the call of Play for the start of the next innings. See, however, 11.3, 11.5 and 11.6."</string>
    <string name="intervals5">"In addition to the provisions of 11.5 and 11.6,"</string>
    <string name="intervals6">"<b>11.3.1</b>if an innings ends when 10 minutes or less remains before the time agreed for close of play on any day, there shall be no further play on that day.  No change shall be made to the time for the start of play on the following day on account of the 10 minute interval between innings."</string>
    <string name="intervals7">"<b>11.3.2</b>if a captain declares an innings closed or forfeits an innings during an interruption in play of more than 10 minutes duration, provided that at least 10 minutes remains of the interruption, no adjustment shall be made to the time for resumption of play on account of the 10 minute interval between innings, which shall be considered as included in the interruption. If less than 10 minutes remains of the interruption when the captain declares the innings closed, or forfeits an innings, the next innings shall commence 10 minutes after the declaration or forfeiture is made."</string>
    <string name="intervals8">"<b>11.3.3</b>if a captain declares an innings closed or forfeits an innings during any interval other than an interval for drinks, provided that at least 10 minutes remains of the interval, the interval shall be of the agreed duration and shall be considered to include the 10 minute interval between innings. If less than 10 minutes remains of the interval when the captain declares the innings closed, or forfeits an innings, the interval shall be extended as necessary and the next innings shall commence 10 minutes after the declaration or forfeiture is made."</string>
    <string name="intervals9">"If, at any time during the match,either playing time is lost through adverse conditions of ground, weather or light or in exceptional circumstances,or the players have occasion to leave the field other than at a scheduled interval, the time of the lunch interval or of the tea interval may be changed if the two umpires and both captains so agree, providing the requirements of 11.2 and 11.5, 11.6, 11.7 and 11.8.3 are not contravened."</string>
    <string name="intervals10">"<b>11.5.1</b>If an innings ends when 10 minutes or less remains before the agreed time for lunch, the interval shall be taken immediately.  It shall be of the agreed duration and shall be considered to include the 10 minute interval between innings."</string>
    <string name="intervals11">"<b>11.5.2</b>If because of adverse conditions of ground, weather or light, or in exceptional circumstances, a stoppage occurs when 10 minutes or less remains before the agreed time for lunch, then, whether or not agreement is reached in the circumstances of 11.4, the interval shall be taken immediately.  It shall be of the agreed duration.  Play shall resume at the end of this interval or as soon after as conditions permit."</string>
    <string name="intervals12">"<b>11.5.3</b>If the players have occasion to leave the field for any reason when more than 10 minutes remains before the agreed time for lunch then, unless the umpires and captains together agree to alter it, lunch shall be taken at the agreed time."</string>
    <string name="intervals13">"<b>11.6.1</b>If an innings ends when 30 minutes or less remains before the agreed time for tea, the interval shall be taken immediately.  It shall be of the agreed duration and shall be considered to include the 10 minute interval between innings."</string>
    <string name="intervals14">"<b>11.6.2</b>If, when 30 minutes remains before the agreed time for tea, an interval between innings is already in progress, play shall resume at the end of the 10 minute interval, if conditions permit."</string>
    <string name="intervals15">"<b>11.6.3</b>If, because of adverse conditions of ground, weather or light, or in exceptional circumstances, a stoppage occurs when 30 minutes or less remains before the agreed time for tea, then unless either there is an agreement to change the time for tea, as permitted in 11.4 or the captains agree to forgo the tea interval, as permitted in 11.9 the interval shall be taken immediately.  The interval shall be of the agreed duration. Play shall resume at the end of the interval or as soon after as conditions permit."</string>
    <string name="intervals16">"<b>11.6.4</b>If a stoppage is already in progress when 30 minutes remains before the agreed time for tea, 11.4 shall apply."</string>
    <string name="intervals17">"For the lunch interval and for the tea interval\nif either 9 wickets are already down when 3 minutes remains to the agreed time for the interval, or the 9th wicket falls within this 3 minutes, or at any time up to and including the final ball of the over in progress at the agreed time for the interval, then the provisions of Law 12.5.2 shall not apply and the interval will not be taken until the end of the over that is in progress 30 minutes after the originally agreed time for the interval, unless the players have cause to leave the field of play or the innings is completed earlier.\nFor the purposes of this section of Law, the retirement of a batter is not to be considered equivalent to the fall of a wicket."</string>
    <string name="intervals18">"<b>11.8.1</b>If on any day the umpires determine that there shall be intervals for drinks, the option to take such drinks shall be available to either side.  Each interval shall be kept as short as possible and in any case shall not exceed 5 minutes."</string>
    <string name="intervals19">"<b>11.8.2</b>Unless, as permitted in 11.9, the captains agree to forgo it, a drinks interval shall be taken at the end of the over in progress when the agreed time is reached.  If, however, a wicket falls or a batter retires within 5 minutes of the agreed time then drinks shall be taken immediately.\nNo other variation in the timing of drinks intervals shall be permitted except as provided for in 11.8.3."</string>
    <string name="intervals20">"<b>11.8.3</b>If an innings ends or the players have to leave the field of play for any other reason within 30 minutes of the agreed time for a drinks interval, the umpires and captains together may rearrange the timing of drinks intervals in that session."</string>
    <string name="intervals21">"<b>11.8.4</b>Intervals for drinks may not be taken during the last hour of the match, as defined in Law 12.6 (Last hour of match - number of overs).  Subject to this limitation, the umpires shall determine the times for such intervals, if any, before the toss and on each subsequent day not later than 10 minutes before play is scheduled to start."</string>
    <string name="intervals22">"At any time during the match, the captains may agree to forgo the tea interval or any of the drinks intervals.  The umpires shall be informed of the decision.\nWhen play is in progress, the batter at the wicket may deputise for their captain in making an agreement to forgo a drinks interval in that session."</string>
    <string name="intervals23">"The umpires shall ensure that the scorers are informed of all agreements about hours of play and intervals and of any changes made thereto as permitted under this Law."</string>

    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play">"The bowler’s end umpire shall call Play before the first ball of the match and on the resumption of play after any interval or interruption."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play2">"The bowler’s end umpire shall call Time, when the ball is dead, at the end of any session of play or as required by the Laws. See also Law 20.3 (Call of Over or Time)."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play3">"After the call of Time, the bails shall be removed from both wickets."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play4">"Another over shall always be started at any time during the match, unless an interval is to be taken in the circumstances set out in 12.5.2, if the umpire, walking at normal pace, has arrived at the position behind the stumps at the bowler’s end before the time agreed for the next interval, or for the close of play, has been reached."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play5">"Other than at the end of the match,"</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play6">"<b>12.5.1</b>if the agreed time for an interval is reached during an over, the over shall be completed before the interval is taken, except as provided for in 12.5.2."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play7">"<b>12.5.2</b>when less than 3 minutes remains before the time agreed for the next interval, the interval shall be taken immediately if either a batter is dismissed or retires or the players have occasion to leave the field whether this occurs during an over or at the end of an over.Except at the end of an innings, if an over is thus interrupted it shall be completed on the resumption of play."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play8">"When one hour of Playing time of the match remains, according to the agreed hours of play, the over in progress shall be completed.  The next over shall be the first of a minimum of 20 overs which must be bowled, provided that a result is not reached earlier and provided that there is no interval or interruption in play.\nThe bowler’s end umpire shall indicate the commencement of this 20 overs to the players and to the scorers.  The period of play thereafter shall be referred to as the last hour, whatever its actual duration.\nWhen the minimum number of overs have been bowled in the last hour, further overs can be started only if the original time for the close of play has not been reached.  See 12.7 and 12.8."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play9">"If there is an interruption in play during the last hour of the match, the minimum number of overs to be bowled shall be reduced from 20 as follows."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play10">"<b>12.7.1</b>The time lost for an interruption is counted from the call of Time until the time for resumption as decided by the umpires."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play11">"<b>12.7.2</b>One over shall be deducted for every complete 3 minutes of time lost."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play12">"<b>12.7.3</b>In the case of more than one such interruption, the minutes lost shall not be aggregated; the calculation shall be made for each interruption separately."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play13">"<b>12.7.4</b>If, when one hour of Playing time remains, an interruption is already in progress"</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play14">"<b>12.7.4.1</b>only the time lost after this moment shall be counted in the calculation."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play15">"<b>12.7.4.2</b>the over in progress at the start of the interruption shall be completed on resumption and shall not count as one of the minimum number of overs to be bowled."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play16">"<b>12.7.4.5</b>If, after the start of the last hour, an interruption occurs during an over, the over shall be completed on resumption of play.  The two part-overs shall between them count as one over of the minimum number to be bowled."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play17">"If an innings ends so that a new innings is to be started during the last hour of the match, the interval starts with the end of the innings and is to end 10 minutes later."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play18">"<b>12.8.1</b>If this interval is already in progress at the start of the last hour then, to determine the number of overs to be bowled in the new innings, calculations are to be made as set out in 12.7."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play19">"<b>12.8.2</b>If the innings ends after the last hour has started, two calculations are to be made, as set out in 12.8.3 and 12.8.4.  The greater of the numbers yielded by these two calculations is to be the minimum number of overs to be bowled in the new innings."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play20">"<b>12.8.3</b>Calculation based on overs remaining:\n- At the conclusion of the innings, the number of overs that remain to be bowled, of the minimum in the last hour, to be noted.\n- If this is not a whole number it is to be rounded up to the next whole number.\n- Three overs, for the interval, to be deducted from the resulting number to determine the number of overs still to be bowled."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play21">"<b>12.8.4</b>Calculation based on time remaining:\n- At the conclusion of the innings, the time remaining until the agreed time for close of play to be noted.\n- 10 minutes, for the interval, to be deducted from this time to determine the Playing time remaining.\n- A calculation to be made of one over for every complete 3 minutes of the Playing time remaining, plus one more over if a further part of 3 minutes remains."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play22">"<b>12.9.1</b>The match is concluded"</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play23">"<b>12.9.1.1</b>as soon as a result as defined in Laws 16.1 to 16.4 and 16.5.1 (The result) is reached."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play24">"<b>12.9.1.2</b>as soon as both the minimum number of overs for the last hour are completed and the agreed time for close of play is reached,unless a result is reached earlier."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play25">"<b>12.9.1.3</b>in the case of an agreement under Law 13.1.2, as soon as the final innings is completed as defined in Law 13.3.5."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play26">"<b>12.9.2</b>The match is concluded if, without a conclusion having been reached under 12.9.1, the players leave the field for adverse conditions of ground, weather or light, or in exceptional circumstances, and no further play is possible."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play27">"The over in progress at the close of play on the final day shall be completed unless either a result has been reached or the players have occasion to leave the field.  In this case there shall be no resumption of play except in the circumstances of Law 16.9 (Mistakes in scoring) and the match shall be at an end."</string>
    <string name="start_and_cessation_of_play28">"If, for any reason, a bowler is unable to complete an over during the last hour, Law 17.8 (Bowler incapacitated or suspended during an over) shall apply.  The separate parts of such an over shall count as one over of the minimum to be bowled."</string>

    <string name="innings">"<b>13.1.1</b>A match shall be one or two innings for each side according to agreement reached before the match."</string>
    <string name="innings2">"<b>13.1.2</b>It may be agreed to limit any innings to a number of overs or to a period of time.  If such an agreement is made then"</string>
    <string name="innings3">"<b>13.1.2.1</b>in a one-innings match a similar agreement shall apply to both innings."</string>
    <string name="innings4">"<b>13.1.2.2</b>in a two-innings match similar agreements shall apply to the first innings of each side or to the second innings of each side or to both innings of each side.\nFor both one-innings and two-innings matches, the agreement must also include criteria for determining the result when neither of Laws 16.1 (A Win - two-innings match) or 16.2 (A Win - one-innings match) applies."</string>
    <string name="innings5">"In a two-innings match each side shall take their innings alternately except in the cases provided for in Law 14 (The follow-on) or in Law 15.2 (Forfeiture of an innings)."</string>
    <string name="innings6">"A side’s innings is to be considered as completed if any of the following applies:"</string>
    <string name="innings7">"<b>13.3.1</b>the side is all out."</string>
    <string name="innings8">"<b>13.3.2</b>at the fall of a wicket or the retirement of a batter, further balls remain to be bowled but no further batter is available to come in."</string>
    <string name="innings9">"<b>13.3.3</b>the captain declares the innings closed."</string>
    <string name="innings10">"<b>13.3.4</b>the captain forfeits the innings."</string>
    <string name="innings11">"<b>13.3.5</b>in the case of an agreement under 13.1.2,either the prescribed number of overs has been bowled or  the prescribed time has expired as appropriate."</string>
    <string name="innings12">"The captains shall toss a coin for the choice of innings, on the field of play and in the presence of one or both of the umpires, not earlier than 30 minutes, nor later than 15 minutes before the scheduled or any rescheduled time for the start of play.  Note, however, the provisions of Law 1.3 (Captain)."</string>
    <string name="innings13">"As soon as the toss is completed, the captain of the side winning the toss shall decide whether to bat or to field and shall notify the opposing captain and the umpires of this decision.  Once notified, the decision cannot be changed."</string>

    <string name="follow_on">"<b>14.1.1</b>In a two-innings match of 5 days or more, the side which bats first and leads by at least 200 runs shall have the option of requiring the other side to follow their innings."</string>
    <string name="follow_on2">"<b>14.1.2</b>The same option shall be available in two-innings matches of shorter duration with the minimum leads as follows:\n- 150 runs in a match of 3 or 4 days;\n- 100 runs in a 2-day match;\n- 75 runs in a 1-day match."</string>
    <string name="follow_on3">"A captain shall notify the opposing captain and the umpires of his/her intention to take up this option. Once notified, the decision cannot be changed."</string>
    <string name="follow_on4">"If no play takes place on the first day of a match of more than one day’s duration, 14.1 shall apply in accordance with the number of days remaining from the start of play. The day on which play first commences shall count as a whole day for this purpose, irrespective of the time at which play starts.\nPlay will have taken place as soon as, after the call of Play, the first over has started.  See Law 17.2 (Start of an over)."</string>

    <string name="declaration_and_forfeiture">"The captain of the side batting may declare an innings closed, when the ball is dead, at any time during the innings. A declared innings shall be considered to be a completed innings."</string>
    <string name="declaration_and_forfeiture2">"A captain may forfeit either of his/her side’s innings at any time before the commencement of that innings.  A forfeited innings shall be considered to be a completed innings."</string>
    <string name="declaration_and_forfeiture3">"A captain shall notify the opposing captain and the umpires of any decision to declare or to forfeit an innings.  Once notified, the decision cannot be changed."</string>

    <string name="the_result">"The side which has scored a total of runs in excess of that scored in the two completed innings of the opposing side shall win the match.  See Law 13.3 (Completed innings).  Note also 16.6."</string>
    <string name="the_result2">"The side which has scored in its one innings a total of runs in excess of that scored by the opposing side in its one completed innings shall win the match.  See Law 13.3 (Completed innings).  Note also 16.6."</string>
    <string name="the_result3">"Regardless of any agreement under Law 13.1.2 (Number of innings),"</string>
    <string name="the_result4">"<b>16.3.1</b>a match shall be lost by a side which"</string>
    <string name="the_result5">"<b>16.3.1.1</b>concedes defeat"</string>
    <string name="the_result6">"<b>16.3.1.2</b>in the opinion of the umpires refuses to play.  If so, the umpires shall award the match to the other side."</string>
    <string name="the_result7">"<b>16.3.2</b>if an umpire considers that an action by any player or players might constitute a refusal by either side to play then the umpires together shall ascertain the cause of the action.  If they then decide together that this action does constitute a refusal to play by one side, they shall so inform the captain of that side.  If the captain persists in the action the umpires shall award the match in accordance with 16.3.1.  See also Law 42.6.1 (Captain refusing to remove a player from the field)."</string>
    <string name="the_result8">"<b>16.3.3</b>if action as in 16.3.2 takes place after play has started and does not constitute a refusal to play,\nPlaying time shall be counted as lost from the call of Time to the call of Play, excluding intervals (Law 11) and suspensions of play (Law 2.8).\nthe time for close of play on that day shall be extended by this length of time.\nif applicable, no overs shall be deducted during the last hour of the match solely on account of this time."</string>
    <string name="the_result9">"For any match in which there is an agreement under Law 13.1.2 (Number of innings), if the result is not determined in any of the ways stated in 16.1, 16.2 or 16.3, then the result shall be as laid down in that agreement."</string>
    <string name="the_result10">"<b>16.5.1</b> A Tie\nThe result of a match shall be a Tie when all innings have been completed and the scores are equal."</string>
    <string name="the_result11">"<b>16.5.2</b>A Draw\nThe result of a match shall be a Draw when it is not determined in any of the ways stated in 16.1, 16.2, 16.3, 16.4, 16.5.1, or when Law 42.6.2 (Captain refusing to remove a player from the field) is applied."</string>
    <string name="the_result12">"<b>16.6.1</b>As soon as a result is reached as defined in 16.1, 16.2, 16.3, 16.4 or 16.5.1, the match is at an end.  Nothing that happens thereafter, except as in Law 41.17.2 (Penalty runs), shall be regarded as part of it.  Note also 16.9."</string>
    <string name="the_result13">"<b>16.6.2</b>The side batting last will have scored enough runs to win only if its total of runs is sufficient without including any runs completed by the batter before the completion of a catch, or the obstruction of a catch, from which the striker could be dismissed."</string>
    <string name="the_result14">"<b>16.6.3</b>If a boundary is scored before the batter have completed sufficient runs to win the match, the whole of the boundary allowance shall be credited to the side’s total and, in the case of a hit by the bat, to the striker’s score."</string>
    <string name="the_result15">"If the side batting last wins the match without losing all its wickets, the result shall be stated as a win by the number of wickets still then to fall.\nIf, without having scored a total of runs in excess of the total scored by the opposing side, the innings of the side batting last has been completed, but as the result of an award of 5 Penalty runs its total of runs is then sufficient to win, the result shall be stated as a win to that side by Penalty runs.\nIf the side fielding last wins the match, the result shall be stated as a win by runs.\nIf the match is decided by one side conceding defeat or refusing to play, the result shall be stated as Match Conceded or Match Awarded, as the case may be."</string>
    <string name="the_result16">"Any decision as to the correctness of the scores shall be the responsibility of the umpires.  See Law 2.15 (Correctness of scores)."</string>
    <string name="the_result17">"If, after the players and umpires have left the field in the belief that the match has been concluded, the umpires discover that a mistake in scoring has occurred which affects the result then, subject to 16.10, they shall adopt the following procedure."</string>
    <string name="the_result18">"<b>16.9.1</b>If, when the players leave the field, the side batting last has not completed its innings and either  the number of overs to be bowled in the last hour, or in that innings, has not been completed or        the agreed time for close of play, or for the end of the innings, has not been reached then, unless one side concedes defeat, the umpires shall order play to resume.\nUnless a result is reached sooner, play will then continue, if conditions permit, until the prescribed number of overs has been completed and either time for close of play has been reached or the allotted time for the innings has expired, as appropriate.  The number of overs and time remaining shall be taken as they were at the call of Time for the supposed conclusion of the match.  No account shall be taken of the time between that moment and the resumption of play."</string>
    <string name="the_result19">"<b>16.9.2</b>If, at this call of Time, the overs have been completed and no Playing time remains, or if the side batting last has completed its innings, the umpires shall immediately inform both captains of the necessary corrections to the scores and to the result."</string>
    <string name="the_result20">"Once the umpires have agreed with the scorers the correctness of the scores at the conclusion of the match - see Laws 2.15 (Correctness of scores) and 3.2 (Correctness of scores) - the result cannot thereafter be changed."</string>

    <string name="the_over">"The ball shall be bowled from each end alternately in overs of 6 balls."</string>
    <string name="the_over2">"An over has started when the bowler starts his/her run-up or, if there is no run-up, starts his/her action for the first delivery of that over."</string>
    <string name="the_over3">"<b>17.3.1</b>A ball shall not count as one of the 6 balls of the over unless it is delivered, even though, as in Law 38.3 (Non-striker leaving his/her ground early) a batter may be dismissed or some other incident occurs without the ball having been delivered."</string>
    <string name="the_over4">"<b>17.3.2</b> A ball delivered by the bowler shall not count as one of the 6 balls of the over"</string>
    <string name="the_over5">"<b>17.3.2.1</b>if it is called dead, or is to be considered dead, before the striker has had an opportunity to play it.  See Law 20.7 (Dead ball; ball counting as one of over)."</string>
    <string name="the_over6">"<b>17.3.2.2</b>if it is called dead in the circumstances of Law 20.4.2.6.  Note also the special provisions of Law 20.4.2.5 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball)."</string>
    <string name="the_over7">"<b>17.3.2.3</b>if it is a No ball.  See Law 21 (No ball)."</string>
    <string name="the_over8">"<b>17.3.2.4</b>if it is a Wide.  See Law 22 (Wide ball)."</string>
    <string name="the_over9">"<b>17.3.2.5</b>when any of Laws 24.4 (Player returning without permission), 28.2 (Fielding the ball), 41.4 (Deliberate attempt to distract striker), or 41.5 (Deliberate distraction, deception or obstruction of a batter) is applied."</string>
    <string name="the_over10">"<b>17.3.3</b>Any deliveries other than those listed in 17.3.1 and 17.3.2 shall be known as valid balls.  Only valid balls shall count towards the 6 balls of the over."</string>
    <string name="the_over11">"When 6 valid balls have been bowled and when the ball becomes dead, the umpire shall call Over before leaving the wicket.  See also Law 20.3 (Call of Over or Time)."</string>
    <string name="the_over12">"<b>17.5.1</b>If the umpire miscounts the number of valid balls, the over as counted by the umpire shall stand."</string>
    <string name="the_over13">"<b>17.5.2</b>If, having miscounted, the umpire allows an over to continue after 6 valid balls have been bowled, he/she may subsequently call Over when the ball becomes dead after any delivery, even if that delivery is not a valid ball."</string>
    <string name="the_over14">"A bowler shall be allowed to change ends as often as desired, provided he/she does not bowl two overs consecutively, nor bowl parts of each of two consecutive overs, in the same innings."</string>
    <string name="the_over15">"<b>17.7.1</b>Other than at the end of an innings, a bowler shall finish an over in progress unless incapacitated or suspended under any of the Laws."</string>
    <string name="the_over16">"<b>17.7.2</b>If for any reason, other than the end of an innings, an over is left uncompleted at the start of an interval or interruption, it shall be completed on resumption of play."</string>
    <string name="the_over17">"If for any reason a bowler is incapacitated while running up to deliver the first ball of an over, or is incapacitated during an over, the umpire shall call and signal Dead ball. If a bowler is incapacitated or suspended during an over, another bowler shall complete the over from the same end, provided that he/she does not bowl two overs consecutively, nor bowl parts of each of two consecutive overs, in that innings."</string>

    <string name="scoring_runs">"The score shall be reckoned by runs.  A run is scored"</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs2">"<b>18.1.1</b>so often as the batter, at any time while the ball is in play, have crossed and made good their ground from end to end."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs3">"<b>18.1.2</b>when a boundary is scored.  See Law 19 (Boundaries)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs4">"<b>18.1.3</b>when Penalty runs are awarded.  See 18.6."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs5">"Wherever in these Laws provision is made for the scoring of runs or awarding of penalties, such runs and penalties will be subject to any provisions that may be applicable for a run to be disallowed or a run not to be scored (see Appendix A.11) or for the non-award of penalties.\nWhen runs are disallowed, the one-run penalty for No ball or Wide shall stand and 5-run penalties shall be allowed, except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs6">"<b>18.3.1</b>A run is short if a batter fails to make good his/her ground in turning for a further run."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs7">"<b>18.3.2</b> Although a short run shortens the succeeding one, the latter if completed shall not be regarded as short.  A striker setting off for the first run from in front of the popping crease may do so also without penalty."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs8">"Except in the circumstances of 18.5,"</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs9">"<b>18.4.1</b>if either batter runs a short run, the umpire concerned shall, unless a boundary is scored, call and signal Short run as soon as the ball becomes dead and that run shall not be scored."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs10">"<b>18.4.2</b>if, after either or both batters run short, a boundary is scored the umpire concerned shall disregard the short running and shall not call or signal Short run, unless the boundary is a result of an overthrow or wilful act of a fielder. See Law 19.8 (Overthrow or wilful act of fielder)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs11">"<b>18.4.3</b>if both batters run short in one and the same run, this shall be regarded as only one short run."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs12">"<b>18.4.4</b>if more than one run is short then, subject to 18.4.2 and 18.4.3, all runs called as short shall not be scored."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs13">"<b>18.4.5</b>if there has been more than one short run, the umpire shall inform the scorers as to the number of runs to be recorded."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs14">"<b>18.5.1</b> If either umpire considers that one or both batters deliberately ran short at that umpire’s end, the umpire concerned shall, when the ball is dead, call and signal Short run and inform the other umpire of what has occurred and apply 18.5.2."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs15">"<b>18.5.2</b>The bowler’s end umpire shall\n- disallow all runs to the batting side\n- return any not out batter to his/her original end\n- signal No ball or Wide to the scorers, if applicable repeat the Short run signal to the scorers\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the fielding side\n- award any other 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side)\n- inform the scorers of the number of runs to be recorded\n- inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for this action."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs16">"<b>18.5.3</b>The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team.</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs17">"Runs shall be awarded for penalties under 18.5, and Laws 21 (No ball), 22 (Wide ball), 24.4 (Player returning without permission), 26.4 (Penalties for contravention), 27.4.2 (Illegal movement by Wicketkeeper), 28.2 (Fielding the ball), 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side), 28.6.3 (Ilegal movement by Fielder), 41 (Unfair play) and 42 (Players’ conduct). Note, however, the restrictions on the award of Penalty runs under 18.5, and Laws 23.3 (Leg byes not to be awarded), 25.7 (Restriction on the striker’s runner), 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side), 34 (Hit the ball twice), 41.14 (Batter damaging the pitch) and 41.15 (Striker in protected area)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs18">"Runs shall be scored for boundary allowances under Law 19 (Boundaries)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs19">"When a batter is dismissed, any runs for penalties awarded to either side shall stand.  No other runs shall be credited to the batting side, except as follows."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs20">"<b>18.8.1</b>If a batter is dismissed Obstructing the field, the batting side shall also score any runs completed before the offence.\nIf, however, the obstruction prevented a catch being made, no runs other than penalties shall be scored."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs21">"<b>18.8.2</b> If a batter is dismissed Run out, the batting side shall also score any runs completed before the wicket was put down.\nIf, however, a striker who has a runner is himself/herself dismissed Run out under Law 25.6.5 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner), any runs completed by the runner and the other batter shall be disallowed."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs22">"When the ball becomes dead for any reason other than the fall of a wicket, or is called dead by an umpire, unless there is specific provision otherwise in the Laws, any runs for penalties awarded to either side shall be scored.  Note however the provisions of Laws 23.3 (Leg byes not to be awarded) and 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side).\nAdditionally the batting side shall be credited with,all runs completed by the batter before the incident or call of Dead ball and the run in progress if the batter shad already crossed at the instant of the incident or call of Dead ball.Note specifically, however, the provisions of Law 41.5.8 (Deliberate distraction, deception or obstruction of a batter)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs23">"Unless stated otherwise in any of the Laws,"</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs24">"<b>18.10.1</b>if the ball is struck by the bat, all runs scored by the batting side shall be credited to the striker, except for the following:\n- an award of 5 Penalty runs, which shall be scored as Penalty runs\n- the one run penalty for a No ball, which shall be scored as a No balls extra."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs25">"<b>18.10.2</b>if the ball is not struck by the bat, runs shall be scored as Penalty runs, Byes, Leg byes, No ball extras or Wides as the case may be.  If Byes or Leg byes accrue from a No ball, only the one run penalty for No ball shall be scored as such, and the remainder as Byes or Leg byes as appropriate."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs26">"<b>18.10.3</b>the bowler shall be debited with:\n- all runs scored by the striker\n- all runs scored as No ball extras\n- all runs scored as Wides."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs27">"<b>18.11.1</b>When the striker is dismissed in any of the circumstances in 18.11.1.1 to 18.11.1.8, the not out batter shall return to his/her original end."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs28">"<b>18.11.1.1</b>A dismissal in the circumstances of Law 25.6.4 or 25.6.5 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs29">"<b>18.11.1.2</b>Bowled."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs30">"<b>18.11.1.3</b>Stumped."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs31">"<b>18.11.1.4</b>Hit the ball twice."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs32">"<b>18.11.1.5</b> LBW."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs33">"<b>18.11.1.6</b>Hit wicket."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs34">"<b>18.11.1.7</b>Caught."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs35">"<b>18.11.1.8</b> Obstructing the field, where the obstruction or distraction prevents the striker being out Caught."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs36">"<b>18.11.2</b>The batter shall return to their original ends in any of the cases of 18.11.2.1 to 18.11.2.3."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs37">"<b>18.11.2.1</b>A boundary is scored, unless it is as a result of an overthrow or wilful act of a fielder (see Law 19.8)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs38">"<b>18.11.2.2</b>Runs are disallowed for any reason."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs39">"<b>18.11.2.3</b>A decision by the batter at the wicket to do so, under Law 41.5 (Deliberate distraction, deception or obstruction of a batter)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs40">"<b>18.12.1</b>When a batter is dismissed in any of the ways in 18.12.1.1 to 18.12.1.2, the not out batter shall return to the wicket he/she has left but only if the batter had not already crossed at the instant of the incident causing the dismissal.  If runs are to be disallowed, however, the not out batter shall return to his/her original end."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs41">"<b>18.12.1.1</b>Obstructing the field, where the obstruction or distraction does not prevent the striker being out Caught."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs42">"<b>18.12.1.2</b>Run out other than under Law 25.6.4 or 25.6.5 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner)."</string>
    <string name="scoring_runs43">"<b>18.12.2</b>If, while a run is in progress, the ball becomes dead for any reason other than the dismissal of a batter, the batter shall return to the wickets they had left, but only if they had not already crossed in running when the ball became dead.If, however, any of the circumstances of 18.11.2.1 to 18.11.2.3 apply, the batter shall return to their original ends."</string>

    <string name="boundaries">"<b>19.1.1</b>Before the toss, the umpires shall determine the boundary of the field of play, which shall be fixed for the duration of the match.  See Law 2.3.1.4 (Consultation with captains)."</string>
    <string name="boundaries2">"<b>19.1.2</b>The boundary shall be determined such that no part of any sight-screen will, at any stage of the match, be within the field of play."</string>
    <string name="boundaries3">"<b>19.2.1</b>Wherever practicable, the boundary shall be marked by means of a continuous white line or by an object in contact with the ground."</string>
    <string name="boundaries4">"<b>19.2.2</b>If the boundary is marked by means of a white line,"</string>
    <string name="boundaries5">"<b>19.2.2.1</b> the edge of the line nearest the pitch shall be the boundary."</string>
    <string name="boundaries6">"<b>19.2.2.2</b> an object such as a flag, post or board, used merely to highlight the position of a line marked on the ground, must be placed beyond the boundary and is not itself to be regarded as being the boundary."</string>
    <string name="boundaries7">"<b>19.2.3</b>If the boundary is marked by means of an object that is in contact with the ground the boundary will be the edge of the grounded part of the object which is nearest the pitch."</string>
    <string name="boundaries8">"<b>19.2.4</b>Where there is no white line or object providing continuous marking, objects such as flags, posts or boards may be used to mark specific points on the boundary.  The boundary shall be the imaginary straight line on the ground joining the two nearest marked points."</string>
    <string name="boundaries9">"<b>19.2.5</b>A boundary that cannot be identified as in 19.2.2, 19.2.3 or 19.2.4 shall be determined by the umpires before the toss."</string>
    <string name="boundaries10">"<b>19.2.6</b> An obstacle within the field of play, other than as in 19.2.7, shall not be regarded as a boundary unless so determined by the umpires before the toss.  See Law 2.3.1.4 (Consultation with captains)."</string>
    <string name="boundaries11">"<b>19.2.7</b> A person, animal or object coming onto, or coming over the field of play while the ball is in play shall not be regarded as a boundary unless the umpires determine otherwise at the time that contact between the ball and such a person, animal or object is made. The decision shall be made for each separate occurrence. See also Law 20.4.2.12 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball)."</string>
    <string name="boundaries12">"If a solid object used to mark the boundary is disturbed for any reason, then"</string>
    <string name="boundaries13">"<b>19.3.1</b>the boundary shall be considered to be in its original position."</string>
    <string name="boundaries14">"<b>19.3.2</b>the object shall be returned to its original position as soon as is practicable; if play is taking place, this shall be as soon as the ball is dead."</string>
    <string name="boundaries15">"<b>19.3.3</b>if some part of a fence or other marker has come within the field of play, that part shall be removed from the field of play as soon as is practicable; if play is taking place, this shall be as soon as the ball is dead."</string>
    <string name="boundaries16">"<b>19.4.1</b>The ball in play is grounded beyond the boundary if it touches\n- the boundary or any part of an object used to mark the boundary;\n- the ground beyond the boundary;\n- any object that is grounded beyond the boundary."</string>
    <string name="boundaries17">"<b>19.4.2</b>The ball in play is to be regarded as being grounded beyond the boundary if\n- a fielder, grounded beyond the boundary as in 19.5, touches the ball;\n- a fielder, after catching the ball within the boundary, becomes grounded beyond the boundary while in contact with the ball, before completing the catch."</string>
    <string name="boundaries18">"<b>19.5.1</b>A fielder is grounded beyond the boundary if some part of his/her person is in contact with any of the following:\n- the boundary or any part of an object used to mark the boundary;\n- the ground beyond the boundary;\n- any object that is in contact with the ground beyond the boundary;\n- another fielder who is grounded beyond the boundary, if the umpire considers that it was the intention of either fielder that the contact should assist in the fielding of the ball."</string>
    <string name="boundaries19">"<b>19.5.2</b>A fielder who is not in contact with the ground is considered to be grounded beyond the boundary if his/her final contact with the ground, before his/her first contact with the ball after it has been delivered by the bowler, was not entirely within the boundary."</string>
    <string name="boundaries20">"<b>19.6.1</b>Before the toss the umpires shall determine the runs to be allowed for boundaries with both captains.  In deciding the allowances the umpires and captains shall be guided by the prevailing custom of the ground."</string>
    <string name="boundaries21">"<b>19.6.2</b>Unless determined differently under 19.6.1, 6 runs shall be allowed for a boundary 6; and 4 runs for a boundary 4.  See also 19.7."</string>
    <string name="boundaries22">"<b>19.7.1</b>A Boundary 6 will be scored if and only if the ball has been struck by the bat and is first grounded beyond the boundary without having been in contact with the ground within the field of play.  This shall apply even if the ball has previously touched a fielder."</string>
    <string name="boundaries23">"<b>19.7.2</b>A Boundary 4 will be scored when a ball that is grounded beyond the boundary\n- whether struck by the bat or not, was first grounded within the boundary, or\n- has not been struck by the bat."</string>
    <string name="boundaries24">"<b>19.7.3</b>When a boundary is scored, the batting side, except in the circumstances of 19.8, shall be awarded whichever is the greater of"</string>
    <string name="boundaries25">"<b>19.7.3.1</b>the allowance for the boundary"</string>
    <string name="boundaries26">"<b>19.7.3.2</b>the runs completed by the batters together with the run in progress if they had already crossed at the instant the boundary is scored."</string>
    <string name="boundaries27">"<b>19.7.4</b>When the runs in 19.7.3.2 exceed the boundary allowance they shall replace the boundary allowance for the purposes of Law 18.12.2 (Batter returning to wicket he/she has left)."</string>
    <string name="boundaries28">"<b>19.7.5</b>The scoring of Penalty runs by either side is not affected by the scoring of a boundary."</string>
    <string name="boundaries29">"If the boundary results from an overthrow or from the wilful act of a fielder, the runs scored shall be any runs for penalties awarded to either side and the allowance for the boundary and the runs completed by the batters, together with the run in progress if they had already crossed at the instant of the throw or act.Law 18.12.2 (Batter returning to wicket he/she has left) shall apply as from the instant of the throw or act."</string>

    <string name="dead_ball">"<b>20.1.1</b> The ball becomes dead when"</string>
    <string name="dead_ball2">"<b>20.1.1.1</b> is finally settled in the hands of the wicket-keeper or of the bowler."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball3">"<b>20.1.1.2</b>a boundary is scored.  See Law 19.7 (Runs scored from boundaries)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball4">"<b>20.1.1.3</b>a batter is dismissed.  The ball will be deemed to be dead from the instant of the incident causing the dismissal."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball5">"<b>20.1.1.4</b>whether played or not it becomes trapped between the bat and person of a batter or between items of his/her clothing or equipment."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball6">"<b>20.1.1.5</b>whether played or not it lodges in the clothing or equipment of a batter or the clothing of an umpire."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball7">"<b>20.1.1.6</b>under either of Laws 24.4 (Player returning without permission) or 28.2 (Fielding the ball) there is an offence resulting in an award of Penalty runs. The ball shall not count as one of the over."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball8">"<b>20.1.1.7</b>there is contravention of Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball9">"<b>20.1.1.8</b>the match is concluded in any of the ways stated in Law 12.9 (Conclusion of match)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball10">"<b>20.1.2</b>The ball shall be considered to be dead when it is clear to the bowler’s end umpire that the fielding side and both batters at the wicket have ceased to regard it as in play."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball11">"Whether the ball is finally settled or not is a matter for the umpire alone to decide."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball12">"Neither the call of Over (see Law 17.4), nor the call of Time (see Law 12.2) is to be made until the ball is dead, either under 20.1 or under 20.4."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball13">"<b>20.4.1</b>When the ball has become dead under 20.1, the bowler’s end umpire may call and signal Dead ball if it is necessary to inform the players."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball14">"<b>20.4.2</b>Where either umpire is required to call and signal Dead ball under 20.4.2.1 to 20.4.2.14, the ball will be considered to be dead at the instant of the incident causing the ball to become dead. However, where the Law specifically provides for the call to be delayed, so as not to disadvantage the non-offending side, under Law 25.7 (Restriction on the striker’s runner), Law 34.4 (Runs permitted from the ball lawfully struck more than once), Law 41.2.1 (Unfair actions) and Law 42.1.2 (Unacceptable conduct), the ball will be considered to be dead at the point of the call.\nEither umpire shall call and signal Dead ball when"</string>
    <string name="dead_ball15">"<b>20.4.2.1</b>intervening in a case of unfair play."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball16">"<b>20.4.2.2</b> a possibly serious injury to a player or umpire occurs."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball17">"<b>20.4.2.3</b>leaving his/her normal position for consultation."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball18">"<b>20.4.2.4</b>one or both bails fall from the striker’s wicket before the striker has had the opportunity of playing the ball."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball19">"<b>20.4.2.5</b>the striker is not ready for the delivery of the ball and, if the ball is delivered, makes no attempt to play it. Provided the umpire is satisfied that the striker had adequate reason for not being ready, the ball shall not count as one of the over"</string>
    <string name="dead_ball20">"<b>20.4.2.6</b>the striker is distracted by any noise or movement or in any other way while preparing to receive, or receiving a delivery. This shall apply whether the source of the distraction is within the match or outside it. Note also 20.4.2.7. The ball shall not count as one of the over."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball21">"<b>20.4.2.7</b>there is an instance of a deliberate attempt to distract under either of Laws 41.4 (Deliberate attempt to distract striker) or 41.5 (Deliberate distraction, deception or obstruction of batter). The ball shall not count as one of the over."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball22">"<b>20.4.2.8</b>the bowler drops the ball accidentally before delivery."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball23">"<b>20.4.2.9</b>the bowler throws the ball towards the striker’s end before entering his/her delivery stride"</string>
    <string name="dead_ball24">"<b>20.4.2.10</b> the ball does not leave the bowler’s hand for any reason other than an attempt to run out the nonstriker under Law 38.3 (Non-striker leaving his/her ground early)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball25">"<b>20.4.2.11</b>satisfied that the ball in play cannot be recovered."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball26">"<b>20.4.2.12</b>he/she considers that either side has been disadvantaged by a person, animal or other object within, or over, the field of play. However, if both umpires consider the ball would have reached the boundary regardless of the intervention, the boundary shall be awarded. See Law 19.2.7 (Identifying and marking the boundary)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball27">"<b>20.4.2.13</b>the striker attempts to play the ball and no part of his/her bat or person, whether grounded or raised, remains within the pitch as defined in Law 6.1 (Area of pitch)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball28">"<b>20.4.2.14</b> he/she is required to do so under any of the Laws not included above."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball29">"The ball ceases to be dead - that is, it comes into play - when the bowler starts his/her run-up or, if there is no run-up, starts his/her bowling action."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball30">"Once the ball is dead, no revoking of any decision can bring the ball back into play for that delivery."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball31">"<b>20.7.1</b>When a ball which has been delivered is called dead or is to be considered dead then, other than as in 20.7.2,"</string>
    <string name="dead_ball32">"<b>20.7.1.1</b>it will not count in the over if the striker has not had an opportunity to play it."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball33">"<b>20.7.1.2</b>unless No ball or Wide ball has been called, it will be a valid ball if the striker has had an opportunity to play it, except in the circumstances of 20.4.2.6 and Laws 24.4 (Player returning without permission), 28.2 (Fielding the ball), 41.4 (Deliberate attempt to distract striker) and 41.5 (Deliberate distraction, deception or obstruction of batter)."</string>
    <string name="dead_ball34">"<b>20.7.2</b>In 20.4.2.5, the ball will not count in the over only if both conditions of not attempting to play the ball and having an adequate reason for not being ready are met. Otherwise the delivery will be a valid ball."</string>


    <string name="no_ball">"<b>21.1.1</b>The umpire shall ascertain whether the bowler intends to bowl right handed or left handed, over or round the wicket, and shall so inform the striker.\nIt is unfair if the bowler fails to notify the umpire of a change in his/her mode of delivery.  In this case the umpire shall call and signal No ball."</string>
    <string name="no_ball2">"<b>21.1.2</b>Underarm bowling shall not be permitted except by special agreement before the match."</string>
    <string name="no_ball3">"For a delivery to be fair in respect of the arm the ball must not be thrown.\nA ball is fairly delivered in respect of the arm if, once the bowler’s arm has reached the level of the shoulder in the delivery swing, the elbow joint is not straightened partially or completely from that instant until the ball has left the hand.  This definition shall not debar a bowler from flexing or rotating the wrist in the delivery swing.\nAlthough it is the primary responsibility of the striker’s end umpire to assess the fairness of a delivery in this respect, there is nothing in this Law to debar the bowler’s end umpire from calling and signalling No ball if he/she considers that the ball has been thrown."</string>
    <string name="no_ball4">"<b>21.3.1</b> After the bowler has entered his/her delivery stride, if in the opinion of either umpire the ball has been thrown or, unless permitted by agreement in 21.1.2, delivered underarm, that umpire shall call and signal No ball and, when the ball is dead, inform the other umpire of the reason for the call.\nThe bowler’s end umpire shall then \n- warn the bowler, indicating that this is a first and final warning.This warning shall apply to that bowler throughout the innings.\n- inform the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action.\n- inform the batters at the wicket of what has occurred."</string>
    <string name="no_ball5">"<b>21.3.2</b> If either umpire considers that, in that innings, a further delivery by the same bowler is thrown or, unless permitted by agreement in 21.1.2, delivered underarm, he/she shall call and signal No ball and when the ball is dead inform the other umpire of the reason for the call.\nThe bowler’s end umpire shall then\n- direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling.The over shall, if applicable, be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled the previous over or part thereof nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.The bowler thus suspended shall not bowl again in that innings.\n- inform the batters at the wicket and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for this action."</string>
    <string name="no_ball6">"<b>21.3.3</b>The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="no_ball7">"If the bowler throws the ball towards the striker’s end before entering the delivery stride, it is not a No ball and the procedure stated in 21.3 shall not apply. However, either umpire shall call and signal Dead Ball under Law 20.4.2.9."</string>
    <string name="no_ball8">"For a delivery to be fair in respect of the feet, in the delivery stride"</string>
    <string name="no_ball9">"<b>21.5.1</b>the bowler’s back foot must land within and not touching the return crease appertaining to his/her stated mode of delivery."</string>
    <string name="no_ball10">&quot;&lt;b&gt;21.5.2&lt;/b&gt;the bowler&apos;s front foot must land with some part of the foot, whether grounded or raised
-on the same side of the imaginary line joining the two middle stumps as the return crease described in 21.5.1, and
-       behind the popping crease.
If the bowler&apos;s end umpire is not satisfied that all of these three conditions have been met, he/she shall call and signal No ball.  See Law 41.8 (Bowling of deliberate front foot No ball).&quot;</string>
    <string name="no_ball11">"If the ball is delivered and if the non-striker is not dismissed under Law 41.16 (Non-striker leaving his/her ground early), either umpire shall call and signal No ball if the bowler breaks the wicket at any time after the ball comes into play and before completion of the stride after the delivery stride. This shall include any clothing or other object that falls from his/her person and breaks the wicket. See Appendix A.12. Laws 20.4.2.8, 20.4.2.10 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball) and 21.12 will apply."</string>
    <string name="no_ball12">"The umpire shall call and signal No ball if a ball which he/she considers to have been delivered, without having previously touched bat or person of the striker,\n- bounces more than once or rolls along the ground before it reaches the popping crease\n or\n- pitches wholly or partially off the pitch as defined in Law 6.1 (Area of pitch) before it reaches the line of the striker’s wicket.  When a non-turf pitch is being used, this will apply to any ball that wholly or partially pitches off the artificial surface."</string>
    <string name="no_ball13">"If a ball delivered by the bowler comes to rest in front of the line of the striker’s wicket or is so far from the pitch that the striker would need to leave the pitch to attempt to play the ball (see Law 25.8 - Striker’s right to play the ball), without having previously touched the bat or person of the striker, the umpire shall call and signal No ball and immediately call and signal Dead ball."</string>
    <string name="no_ball14">"If, except in the circumstances of Law 27.3 (Position of wicket-keeper), a ball delivered by the bowler makes contact with any part of a fielder’s person before it either makes contact with the striker’s bat or person, or it passes the striker’s wicket, the umpire shall call and signal No ball and immediately call and signal Dead ball."</string>
    <string name="no_ball15">"The umpire shall call and signal No ball for any delivery which, after pitching, passes or would have passed over head height of the striker standing upright at the popping crease."</string>
    <string name="no_ball16">"In addition to the instances above, No ball is to be called and signalled as required by the following Laws.\nLaw 27.3 - Position of wicket-keeper\nLaw 28.4 - Limitation of on side fielders\nLaw 28.5 - Fielders not to encroach on pitch\nLaw 41.6 - Bowling of dangerous and unfair short pitched deliveries\nLaw 41.7 - Bowling of dangerous and unfair non-pitching deliveries\nLaw 41.8 - Bowling of deliberate front foot No ball.</string>
    <string name="no_ball17">"An umpire shall revoke the call of No ball if Dead ball is called under any of Laws 20.4.2.4, 20.4.2.5, 20.4.2.6, 20.4.2.8 or 20.4.2.10 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball)."</string>
    <string name="no_ball18">"A call of No ball shall over-ride the call of Wide ball at any time.  See Laws 22.1(Judging a Wide) and 22.2 (Call and signal of Wide ball)."</string>
    <string name="no_ball19">"The ball does not become dead on the call of No ball."</string>
    <string name="no_ball20">"A penalty of one run shall be awarded instantly on the call of No ball.  Unless the call is revoked, the penalty shall stand even if a batter is dismissed.  It shall be in addition to any other runs scored, any boundary allowance and any other runs awarded for penalties."</string>
    <string name="no_ball21">"The one run penalty shall be scored as a No ball extra and shall be debited against the bowler.  If other Penalty runs have been awarded to either side these shall be scored as stated in Law 41.17 (Penalty runs).  Any runs completed by the batters or any boundary allowance shall be credited to the striker if the ball has been struck by the bat; otherwise they shall also be scored as Byes or Leg byes as appropriate."</string>
    <string name="no_ball22">"A No ball shall not count as one of the over.  See Law 17.3 (Validity of balls)."</string>
    <string name="no_ball23">"When No ball has been called, neither batters shall be out under any of the Laws except 34 (Hit the ball twice), 37 (Obstructing the field) or 38 (Run out)."</string>

    <string name="wide">"<b>22.1.1</b>If the bowler bowls a ball, not being a No ball, the umpire shall adjudge it a Wide if, according to the definition in 22.1.2, the ball passes wide of where the striker is standing or has stood at any point after the ball came into play for that delivery, and which also would have passed wide of the striker standing in a normal batting position."</string>
    <string name="wide2">"<b>22.1.2</b> The ball will be considered as passing wide of the striker unless it is sufficiently within reach for him/her to be able to hit it with the bat by means of a normal cricket stroke."</string>
    <string name="wide3">"If the umpire adjudges a delivery to be a Wide he/she shall call and signal Wide ball as soon as the ball passes the striker’s wicket.  It shall, however, be considered to have been a Wide from the instant that the bowler entered his/her delivery stride, even though it cannot be called Wide until it passes the striker’s wicket."</string>
    <string name="wide4">"<b>22.3.1</b>The umpire shall revoke the call of Wide ball if there is then any contact between the ball and the striker’s bat or person before the ball comes into contact with any fielder."</string>
    <string name="wide5">"<b>22.3.2</b>The umpire shall revoke the call of Wide ball if a delivery is called a No ball.  See Law 21.13 (No ball to over-ride Wide)."</string>
    <string name="wide6">"<b>22.4.1</b>The umpire shall not adjudge a delivery as being a Wide, if the striker, by moving,either  causes the ball to pass wide of him/her, as defined in 22.1.2 or brings the ball sufficiently within reach to be able to hit it by means of a normal cricket stroke."</string>
    <string name="wide7">"<b>22.4.2</b>The umpire shall not adjudge a delivery as being a Wide if the ball touches the striker’s bat or person, but only as the ball passes the striker."</string>
    <string name="wide8">"The ball does not become dead on the call of Wide ball."</string>
    <string name="wide9">"A penalty of one run shall be awarded instantly on the call of Wide ball.  Unless the call is revoked, see 22.3, this penalty shall stand even if a batter is dismissed, and shall be in addition to any other runs scored, any boundary allowance and any other runs awarded for penalties."</string>
    <string name="wide10">"All runs completed by the batters or a boundary allowance, together with the penalty for the Wide, shall be scored as Wide balls.  Apart from any award of 5 Penalty runs, all runs resulting from a Wide shall be debited against the bowler."</string>
    <string name="wide11">"A Wide shall not count as one of the over.  See Law 17.3 (Validity of balls)."</string>
    <string name="wide12">"When Wide ball has been called, neither batter shall be out under any of the Laws except 35 (Hit wicket), 37 (Obstructing the field), 38 (Run out) or 39 (Stumped)."</string>

    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye">"If the ball, delivered by the bowler, not being a Wide, passes the striker without touching his/her bat or person, any runs completed by the batters from that delivery, or a boundary allowance, shall be credited as Byes to the batting side. Additionally, if the delivery is a No ball, the one run penalty for such a delivery shall be incurred."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye2">"<b>23.2.1</b> If a ball delivered by the bowler first strikes the person of the striker, runs shall be scored only if the umpire is satisfied that the striker has either attempted to play the ball with the bat or tried to avoid being hit by the ball."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye3">"<b>23.2.2</b>If the umpire is satisfied that either of these conditions has been met runs shall be scored as follows."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye4">"<b>23.2.2.1</b>If there is either no subsequent contact with the striker’s bat or person,or only inadvertent contact with the striker’s bat or person any runs completed by the batters or a boundary allowance shall be credited to the striker in the case of subsequent contact with his/her bat but otherwise to the batting side as in 23.2.3."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye5">"<b>23.2.1.2</b>If the striker wilfully makes a lawful second strike, Laws 34.3 (Ball lawfully struck more than once) and 34.4 (Runs permitted from ball lawfully struck more than once) shall apply."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye6">"<b>23.2.3</b>The runs in 23.2.2.1, unless credited to the striker, shall be scored as Leg byes.\nAdditionally, if the delivery is a No ball, the one run penalty for the No ball shall be incurred."</string>
    <string name="bye_and_leg_bye7">"If in the circumstance of 23.2.1 the umpire considers that neither of the conditions therein has been met, then Leg byes shall not be awarded.\nThe umpire shall then\n-       disallow all runs to the batting side;\n-       return any not out batter to his/her original end;\n-       signal No ball to the scorers if applicable;\n-       award any 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side)."</string>

    <string name="substitutes">"<b>24.1.1</b>The umpires shall allow a substitute fielder"</string>
    <string name="substitutes2">"<b>24.1.1.1</b>if they are satisfied that a fielder has been injured or become ill and that this occurred during the match, or"</string>
    <string name="substitutes3">"<b>24.1.1.2</b>for any other wholly acceptable reason.\nIn all other circumstances, a substitute is not allowed."</string>
    <string name="substitutes4">"<b>24.1.2</b>A substitute shall not bowl or act as captain but may act as wicket-keeper only with the consent of the umpires.  Note, however, Law 42.7.1 (Additional points relating to Level 3 and Level 4 offences)."</string>
    <string name="substitutes5">"<b>24.1.3</b>A nominated player may bowl or field even though a substitute has previously acted for him/her, subject to 24.2, 24.3 and Law 42.4 (Level 3 offences and action by umpires)."</string>
    <string name="substitutes6">"<b>24.2.1</b>A player going briefly outside the boundary while carrying out any duties as a fielder is not absent from the field of play nor, for the purposes of this Law, is he/she to be regarded as having left the field of play."</string>
    <string name="substitutes7">"<b>24.2.2</b>If a fielder fails to take the field at the start of play or at any later time, or leaves the field during play,"</string>
    <string name="substitutes8">"<b>24.2.2.1</b>an umpire shall be informed of the reason for this absence."</string>
    <string name="substitutes9">"<b>24.2.2.2</b> he/she shall not thereafter come on to the field of play during a session of play without the consent of the umpire.  See 24.4.  The umpire shall give such consent as soon as it is practicable."</string>
    <string name="substitutes10">"<b>24.2.2.3</b>he/she shall not be permitted to bowl, until having been back on the field of play for a period of time known as Penalty time as described in 24.2.3 to 24.2.7 and 24.3."</string>
    <string name="substitutes11">"<b>24.2.3</b>A player’s unserved Penalty time shall be limited to a maximum of 90 minutes."</string>
    <string name="substitutes12">"<b>24.2.4</b>If the player leaves the field before having served all of his/her Penalty time, the balance is carried forward as unserved Penalty time."</string>
    <string name="substitutes13">"<b>24.2.5</b>The player shall not bowl until all of his/her Penalty time has been served. On any occasion of absence, the amount of Playing time for which the player is off the field shall be added to any Penalty time that remains unserved, subject to 24.2.3."</string>
    <string name="substitutes14">"<b>24.2.6</b>If there is an unscheduled break in play, the stoppage time shall count as Penalty time served, provided that,"</string>
    <string name="substitutes15">"<b>24.2.6.1</b>the fielder who was on the field of play at the start of the break either takes the field on the resumption of play, or his/her side is now batting."</string>
    <string name="substitutes16">"<b>24.2.6.2</b> the fielder who was already off the field at the start of the break notifies an umpire in person as soon as he/she is able to participate, and either takes the field on the resumption of play, or his/her side is now batting.  Stoppage time before an umpire has been so notified shall not count towards unserved Penalty time."</string>
    <string name="substitutes17">"<b>24.2.7</b> Any unserved Penalty time shall be carried forward into the next and subsequent days and innings of the match, as applicable."</string>
    <string name="substitutes18">"<b>24.2.8</b>If a Level 3 offence under Law 42.4 (Level 3 offences and action by umpires) is committed by a fielder, the period of time spent off the field of play as a result of the suspension shall not be added to any unserved Penalty time if he/she takes the field at the end of the period of suspension."</string>
    <string name="substitutes19">"<b>24.2.9</b>If a Level 3 offence under Law 42.4 (Level 3 offences and action by umpires) is committed by a substitute, the following shall apply."</string>
    <string name="substitutes20">"<b>24.2.9.1</b> The period of time spent off the field as a result of the suspension shall not be added to any Penalty time that remains unserved if the nominated player takes the field at the end of the period of suspension.  However, any time spent off the field prior to the offence causing the suspension will remain as unserved Penalty time, subject to 24.2.3."</string>
    <string name="substitutes21">"<b>24.2.9.2</b>If the nominated player does not take the field at the end of the period of suspension, then the entire period of his/her absence will be treated as Penalty time, up to a maximum of 90 minutes."</string>
    <string name="substitutes22">"A nominated player’s absence will not incur Penalty time if,"</string>
    <string name="substitutes23">"<b>24.3.1</b>he/she has suffered an external blow during the match and, as a result, has justifiably left the field or is unable to take the field."</string>
    <string name="substitutes24">"<b>24.3.2</b>in the opinion of the umpires, the player has been absent or has left the field for other wholly acceptable reasons, which shall not include illness or internal injury."</string>
    <string name="substitutes25">"If a player comes on to the field of play in contravention of 24.2.2 and comes into contact with the ball while it is in play, the ball shall immediately become dead.\n- The umpires shall signal No ball or Wide to the scorers, if applicable.\n- The umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side.\n- Runs completed by the batters shall be scored together with the run in progress if they had already crossed at the instant of the offence.\n- The ball shall not count as one of the over.\n- The umpire shall inform the other umpire, the captain of the fielding side, the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for this action.\n- The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>

    <string name="runners">"Only a nominated player may bat or act as a runner and, subject to 25.3 and 25.5.2, may do so even though a substitute fielder has previously acted for him/her."</string>
    <string name="runners2">"The innings of the first two batters, and that of any new batter on the resumption of play after a call of Time, shall commence at the call of Play. At any other time, a batter’s innings shall be considered to have commenced when that batter first steps onto the field of play."</string>
    <string name="runners3">"<b>25.3.1</b>If a member of the batting side has unserved Penalty time, see Law 24.2.7 (Fielder absent or leaving the field of play), that player shall not be permitted to bat or act as a runner until that Penalty time has been served.  However, even if the unserved Penalty time has not expired, that player may bat after his/her side has lost 5 wickets."</string>
    <string name="runners4">"<b>25.3.2</b>A member of the batting side’s Penalty time is served during Playing time, subject to the conditions in 25.3.2.1 and 25.3.2.2."</string>
    <string name="runners5">"<b>25.3.2.1</b>The period of time while serving a suspension for a Level 3 offence under Law 42.4 (Level 3 offences and action by umpires) does not count as Penalty time served."</string>
    <string name="runners6">"<b>25.3.2.2</b>In the event of an unscheduled stoppage, the stoppage time after the batter notifies an umpire in person that he/she is able to participate shall count as Penalty time served."</string>
    <string name="runners7">"<b>25.3.3</b> If any unserved Penalty time remains at the end of a team’s innings, it shall be carried forward to the next and subsequent innings of the match if appropriate."</string>
    <string name="runners8">"<b>25.4.1</b>A batter may retire at any time during his/her innings when the ball is dead. The umpires, before allowing play to proceed, shall be informed of the reason for a batter retiring."</string>
    <string name="runners9">"<b>25.4.2</b> If a batter retires because of illness, injury or any other unavoidable cause, that batter is entitled to resume his/her innings. If for any reason this does not happen, that batter is to be recorded as ‘Retired - not out’."</string>
    <string name="runners10">"<b>25.4.3</b>If a batter retires for any reason other than as in 25.4.2, the innings of that batter may be resumed only with the consent of the opposing captain. If for any reason his/her innings is not resumed, that batter is to be recorded as ‘Retired - out’."</string>
    <string name="runners11">"<b>25.4.4</b>If after retiring a batter resumes his/her innings, subject to the requirements of 25.4.2 and 25.4.3, it shall be only at the fall of a wicket or the retirement of another batter."</string>
    <string name="runners12">"<b>25.5.1</b>The umpires shall allow a runner for a batter if they are satisfied"</string>
    <string name="runners13">"<b>25.5.1.1</b>that the batter has sustained an injury that affects his/her ability to run and that this occurred during the match."</string>
    <string name="runners14">"<b>25.5.1.2</b> for any other wholly acceptable reason.\nIn all other circumstances, a runner is not allowed."</string>
    <string name="runners15">"<b>25.5.2</b>A runner shall"</string>
    <string name="runners16">"<b>25.5.2.1</b>be a member of the batting side."</string>
    <string name="runners17">"<b>25.5.2.2</b>if possible, have already completed his/her innings; when this is not possible, if circumstances change such that a dismissed batter can act as runner, then the runner must be changed immediately."</string>
    <string name="runners18">"<b>25.5.2.3</b> be changed only with the consent of the umpires."</string>
    <string name="runners19">"<b>25.5.2.4</b> wear external protective equipment equivalent to that worn by the batter for whom he/she runs and shall carry a bat."</string>
    <string name="runners20">"<b>25.5.2.5</b>not have any unserved Penalty time as described in Law 24.2.7 (Fielder absent or leaving the field of play)."</string>
    <string name="runners21">"<b>25.5.3</b>A batter’s runner is subject to the Laws and will be regarded as a batter except where there are special provisions for his/her role as a runner. See Law 30.2 (Which is a batter’s ground)."</string>
    <string name="runners22">"<b>25.6.1</b>A batter who has a runner will suffer the penalty for any infringement of the Laws by the runner as if he/she, the batter, had been responsible for the infringement. In particular he/she will be out if the runner is out under either of Laws 37 (Obstructing the field) or 38 (Run out)."</string>
    <string name="runners23">"<b>25.6.2</b>When a batter who has a runner is the striker he/she remains subject to the Laws and will be liable to the penalties that any infringement of them demands. In the case of Run out and Stumped, however, special provisions, set out in 25.6.3, 25.6.4 and 25.6.5, apply to him/her as a striker who has a runner."</string>
    <string name="runners24">"<b>25.6.3</b>When a batter who has a runner is the striker, his/her ground is always at the wicket-keeper’s end."</string>
    <string name="runners25">"<b>25.6.4</b>If the striker who has a runner is in his/her ground, and the runner is out of his/her ground at the wicket-keeper’s end when the wicket is fairly broken at that end, the conditions of Law 38 (Run out) shall apply.</string>
    <string name="runners26">"<b>25.6.5</b>If the striker who has a runner is out of his/her ground and the wicket at the wicket-keeper’s end is fairly broken, the striker is liable to be out under Laws 38 (Run out) or 39 (Stumped). If the runner is also out of his/her ground at the wicket-keeper’s end, then only Law 38 (Run out) can apply."</string>
    <string name="runners27">"<b>25.6.6</b>If a striker who has a runner is dismissed as in 25.6.5, the umpire shall\n- disallow all runs to the batting side\n- return any not out batter to his/her original end\n- award any 5-run Penalty that is applicable."</string>
    <string name="runners28">"<b>25.6.7</b>When a batter who has a runner is not the striker, he/she"</string>
    <string name="runners29">"<b>25.6.7.1</b> remains subject to Law 37 (Obstructing the field) but is otherwise out of the match."</string>
    <string name="runners30">"<b>25.6.7.2</b>shall stand where directed by the striker’s end umpire so as not to interfere with play."</string>
    <string name="runners31">"<b>25.6.7.3</b> will be liable, even though out of the match as in 25.6.7.1, to any penalty demanded by the Laws should he/she commit any act of unfair play."</string>
    <string name="runners32">"<b>25.7.1</b>Once the ball comes into play, the runner for an injured batter who is the striker shall have part of his/her person or bat grounded behind the popping crease until the ball reaches the striker or passes the popping crease, whichever is the sooner."</string>
    <string name="runners33">&quot;&lt;b&gt;25.7.2&lt;/b&gt;If the striker&apos;s end umpire considers the runner for an injured striker to be in breach of this restriction then, if the ball does not become dead for any other reason, he/she shall call and signal Dead ball as soon as the ball reaches the boundary or at the completion of the first run. However, he/she shall delay the call of Dead ball to allow the opportunity for a catch to be completed.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall
- disallow all runs to the batting side
- return any not out batter to his/her original end
- award any 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side).&quot;</string>
    <string name="runners34">"The striker has a right to play the ball, or to make a legitimate second strike, after it has been delivered, without interference from the wicket-keeper or any other fielder. See Law 27.5 (Restrictions on actions of wicket-keeper) and Law 27.6 (Interference with wicket-keeper by striker). However, the striker may only attempt to play the ball if some of his/her bat or person, whether grounded or raised, remains within the pitch, as defined in Law 6.1 (Area of pitch). Should no part of the striker’s bat or person remain within the pitch, whilst the striker is playing the ball, either umpire shall immediately call and signal Dead ball."</string>

    <string name="practice_on_the_field">"<b>26.1.1</b>There shall not be any practice on the pitch at any time on any day of the match."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field2">"<b>26.1.2</b> There shall not be any practice on the rest of the square at any time on any day of the match, except with the approval of the umpires."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field3">"<b>26.2.1</b>On any day of the match, all forms of practice are permitted on the outfield\n- before the start of play,\n- after the close of play and\n- during the lunch and tea intervals or between innings,\nproviding the umpires are satisfied that such practice will not cause significant deterioration in the condition of the outfield."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field4">"<b>26.2.2</b> Between the call of Play and the call of Time, practice shall be permitted on the outfield, providing that all of the following conditions are met:\n- only the fielders as defined in Appendix A.7 participate in such practice.\n- no ball other than the match ball is used for this practice.\n- no bowling practice takes place in the area between the square and the boundary in a direction parallel to the match pitch.\n- the umpires are satisfied that it will not contravene either of Laws 41.3 (The match ball - changing its condition) or 41.9 (Time wasting by the fielding side). If there is such a contravention, the sanctions in Law 41 shall be applied. However, any warning given shall apply to further instances under both Law 26 and Law 41 (Unfair play)."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field5">"A bowler is permitted to have a trial run-up provided the umpire is satisfied that it will not contravene either of Laws 41.9 (Time wasting by the fielding side) or 41.12 (Fielder damaging the pitch)."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field6">"All forms of practice are subject to the provisions of Laws 41.3 (The match ball - changing its condition), 41.9 (Time wasting by the fielding side) and 41.12 (Fielder damaging the pitch)."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field7">"<b>26.4.1</b> If there is a contravention of any of the provisions of 26.1 or 26.2, the umpire shall\n- warn the player that the practice is not permitted;\n- inform the other umpire and, as soon as practicable, both captains of the reason for this action."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field8">"<b>26.4.1.1</b>If the contravention is by a batter at the wicket, the umpire shall inform the other batter and each incoming batter that the warning has been issued. The warning shall apply to the team of that player throughout the match."</string>
    <string name="practice_on_the_field9">"<b>26.4.2</b>If during the match there is any further contravention by any player of that team, the umpire shall\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing side;\n- inform the other umpire, the scorers and, as soon as practicable, both captains, and, if the contravention is during play, the batters at the wicket.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>

    <string name="wicket_keeper">"The wicket-keeper is the only fielder permitted to wear gloves and external leg guards. If these are worn, they are to be regarded as part of his/her person for the purposes of Law 28.2 (Fielding the ball).  If by the wicket-keeper’s actions and positioning when the ball comes into play it is apparent to the umpires that he/she will not be able to carry out the normal duties of a wicket-keeper, he/she shall forfeit this right and also the right to be recognised as a wicket-keeper for the purposes of Laws 33.2 (A fair catch), 39 (Stumped), 28.1 (Protective equipment), 28.4 (Limitation of on-side fielders) and 28.5 (Fielders not to encroach on pitch)."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper2">"<b>27.2.1</b>If, as permitted under 27.1, the wicket-keeper wears gloves, they shall have no webbing between the fingers except joining index finger and thumb, where webbing may be inserted as a means of support."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper3">"<b>27.2.2</b>If used, the webbing shall be a single piece of non-stretch material which, although it may have facing material attached, shall have no reinforcements or tucks."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper4">"<b>27.2.3</b>The top edge of the webbing shall not protrude beyond the straight line joining the top of the index finger to the top of the thumb and shall be taut when a hand wearing the glove has the thumb fully extended. See Appendix E."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper5">"<b>27.3.1</b>The wicket-keeper shall remain wholly behind the wicket at the striker’s end from the moment the ball comes into play until a ball delivered by the bowler\ntouches the bat or person of the striker or\npasses the wicket at the striker’s end or\nthe striker attempts a run."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper6">"<b>27.3.2</b>In the event of the wicket-keeper contravening this Law, the striker’s end umpire shall call and signal No ball as soon as applicable after the delivery of the ball."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper7">"<b>27.4.1</b>After the ball comes into play and before it reaches the striker, it is unfair if the wicket-keeper significantly alters his/her position in relation to the striker’s wicket, except for the following:"</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper8">"<b>27.4.1.1</b>movement of a few paces forward for a slower delivery, unless in so doing it brings him/her within reach of the wicket."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper9">"<b>27.4.1.2</b> lateral movement in response to the direction in which the ball has been delivered."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper10">"<b>27.4.1.3</b>movement in response to the stroke that the striker is playing or that his/her actions suggest he/she intends to play.  However the provisions of Law 27.3 shall apply."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper11">&quot;&lt;b&gt;27.4.2&lt;/b&gt;In the event of unfair movement by the wicket-keeper, either umpire shall call and signal Dead ball and inform the other umpire of the reason for doing so. The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then:&quot;</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper12">"<b>27.4.2.1</b>award the one-run penalty for Wide or No ball, if applicable"</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper13">"<b>27.4.2.2</b>award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side"</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper14">"<b>27.4.2.3</b>inform the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper15">"<b>27.4.2.4</b> inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper16">"If, in the opinion of either umpire, the wicket-keeper interferes with the striker’s right to play the ball and to guard his/her wicket, Law 20.4.2.6 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball) shall apply.\nIf, however, either umpire considers that the interference by the wicket-keeper was wilful, then Law 41.4 (Deliberate attempt to distract striker) shall also apply."</string>
    <string name="wicket_keeper17">"If, in playing at the ball or in the legitimate defence of his/her wicket, the striker interferes with the wicket-keeper, he/she shall not be out except as provided for in Law 37.3 (Obstructing a ball from being caught)."</string>

    <string name="fielder">"No fielder other than the wicket-keeper shall be permitted to wear gloves or external leg guards.  In addition, protection for the hand or fingers may be worn only with the consent of the umpires."</string>
    <string name="fielder2">"<b>28.2.1</b>A fielder may field the ball with any part of his/her person (see Appendix A.12), except as in 28.2.1.2.  However, he/she will be deemed to have fielded the ball illegally if, while the ball is in play he/she wilfully"</string>
    <string name="fielder3">"<b>28.2.1.1</b>uses anything other than part of his/her person to field the ball."</string>
    <string name="fielder4">"<b>28.2.1.2</b>extends his/her clothing with his/her hands and uses this to field the ball."</string>
    <string name="fielder5">"<b>28.2.1.3</b>discards a piece of clothing, equipment or any other object which subsequently makes contact with the ball."</string>
    <string name="fielder6">"<b>28.2.2</b>It is not illegal fielding if the ball in play makes contact with a piece of clothing, equipment or any other object which has accidentally fallen from the fielder’s person, or been dropped by an umpire."</string>
    <string name="fielder7">"<b>28.2.3</b>If a fielder illegally fields the ball, the ball shall immediately become dead and\n- the penalty for a No ball or a Wide shall stand.\n- any runs completed by the batter shall be credited to the batting side, together with the run in progress if the batters had already crossed at the instant of the offence.\n- the ball shall not count as one of the over.\nIn addition the umpire shall\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side.\n- inform the other umpire and the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action.\n- inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="fielder8">"<b>28.3.1</b>Protective helmets, when not in use by fielders, may not be placed on the ground, above the surface except behind the wicket-keeper and in line with both sets of stumps."</string>
    <string name="fielder9">"<b>28.3.2</b>If the ball while in play strikes the protective helmet, placed as described in 28.3.1, the ball shall immediately become dead and, unless 28.3.3 applies:\n- the umpire shall signal No ball or Wide to the scorers, if applicable\n- the umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side\n- any runs completed by the batters before the ball strikes the protective helmet shall be scored, together with the run in progress if the batters had already crossed at the instant of the ball striking the protective helmet."</string>
    <string name="fielder10">"<b>28.3.3</b>If the ball while in play strikes a helmet, placed as described in 28.3.1 and the circumstances of Law 23.3 (Leg byes not to be awarded), 25.7 (Restriction on the striker’s runner) or Law 34 (Hit the ball twice) apply, the umpire shall\n- disallow all runs to the batting side\n- return any not out batter to his/her original end\n- signal No ball or Wide ball to the scorers if applicable\n- award any 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under 28.3.2."</string>
    <string name="fielder11">"At the instant of the bowler’s delivery there shall not be more than two fielders, other than the wicket-keeper, behind the popping crease on the on side.  A fielder will be considered to be behind the popping crease unless the whole of his/her person whether grounded or in the air is in front of this line.\nIn the event of infringement of this Law by any fielder, the striker’s end umpire shall call and signal No ball."</string>
    <string name="fielder12">"While the ball is in play and until the ball has made contact with the striker’s bat or person, or has passed the striker’s bat, no fielder, other than the bowler, may have any part of his/her person grounded on or extended over the pitch.\nIn the event of infringement of this Law by any fielder other than the wicket-keeper, the bowler’s end umpire shall call and signal No ball as soon as possible after delivery of the ball.  Note, however, Law 27.3 (Position of wicket-keeper)."</string>
    <string name="fielder13">"<b>28.6.1</b> Any movement by any fielder, excluding the wicket-keeper, after the ball comes into play and before the ball reaches the striker, is unfair except for the following:"</string>
    <string name="fielder14">"<b>28.6.1.1</b> minor adjustments to stance or position in relation to the striker’s wicket."</string>
    <string name="fielder15">"<b>28.6.1.2</b>movement by any fielder, other than a close fielder, towards the striker or the striker’s wicket that does not significantly alter the position of the fielder."</string>
    <string name="fielder16">"<b>28.6.1.3</b> movement by any fielder in response to the stroke that the striker is playing or that his/her actions suggest he/she intends to play."</string>
    <string name="fielder17">"<b>28.6.2</b> In all circumstances Law 28.4 (Limitation of on side fielders) shall apply."</string>
    <string name="fielder18">"<b>28.6.3</b>In the event of such unfair movement, either umpire shall call and signal Dead ball and inform the other umpire of the reason for doing so. The bowler’s end umpire shall then:"</string>
    <string name="fielder19">"<b>28.6.3.1</b>award the one-run penalty for Wide or No ball, if applicable"</string>
    <string name="fielder20">"<b>28.6.3.2</b>award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side"</string>
    <string name="fielder21">"<b>28.6.3.3</b>inform the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action."</string>
    <string name="fielder22">"<b>28.6.3.4</b>inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="fielder23">"<b>28.6.4</b> Note also the provisions of Law 41.4 (Deliberate attempt to distract striker).  See also Law 27.4 (Movement by wicket-keeper)."</string>

    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken">"The wicket is broken when at least one bail is completely removed from the top of the stumps, or one or more stumps is removed from the ground."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken2">"<b>29.2.1</b>The wicket is broken fairly if a bail is completely removed from the top of the stumps, or a stump is struck out of the ground."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken3">"<b>29.2.1.1</b>by the ball,"</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken4">"<b>29.2.1.2</b> by the striker’s bat if held or by any part of the bat that he/she is holding,"</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken5">"<b>29.2.1.3</b> for the purpose of this law only, by the striker’s bat not in hand, or by any part of the bat which has become detached,"</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken6">"<b>29.2.1.4</b>by the striker’s person or by any part of his/her clothing or equipment becoming detached from his/her person. However, any detached equipment shall not include the striker’s protective helmet, or any part thereof, as defined in Appendix A.2.3,"</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken7">"<b>29.2.1.5</b>by a fielder with his/her hand or arm, providing that the ball is held in the hand or hands so used, or in the hand of the arm so used."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken8">"<b>29.2.1.6</b>The wicket is also broken fairly if a fielder strikes or pulls a stump out of the ground as in 29.2.1.5."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken9">"<b>29.2.2</b>The disturbance of a bail, whether temporary or not, shall not constitute its complete removal from the top of the stumps, but if a bail in falling lodges between two of the stumps this shall be regarded as complete removal."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken10">"If one bail is off, it shall be sufficient for the purpose of breaking bail or to strike or pull any of the three stumps out of the ground, in any of the ways stated in 29.2."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken11">"If a wicket is broken while the ball is in play, it shall not be remade by an umpire until the ball is dead. See Law 20 (Dead ball). Any fielder may, however, while the ball is in play,\n- replace a bail or bails on top of the stumps.\n- put back one or more stumps into the ground where the wicket originally stood."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken12">"If the umpires have agreed to dispense with bails in accordance with Law 8.5 (Dispensing with bails), it is for the umpire concerned to decide whether or not the wicket has been broken."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken13">"<b>29.5.1</b>After a decision to play without bails, the wicket has been broken fairly if the umpire concerned is satisfied that the wicket has been struck by the ball, by the striker’s bat, person or items of his/her clothing or equipment as described in 29.2.1.2, 29.2.1.3 or 29.2.1.4, or by a fielder in the manner described in 29.2.1.5."</string>
    <string name="the_wicket_is_broken14">"<b>29.5.2</b> If the wicket has already been broken, 29.5.1 shall apply to any stump or stumps still in the ground. Any fielder may replace a stump or stumps, in accordance with 29.4, in order to have an opportunity of breaking the wicket fairly."</string>

    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground">"<b>30.1.1</b>A batter shall be considered to be out of his/her ground unless some part of his/her person or bat is grounded behind the popping crease at that end."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground2">"<b>30.1.2</b> However, a batter shall not be considered to be out of his/her ground if, in running or diving towards his/her ground and beyond, and having grounded some part of his/her person or bat beyond the popping crease, there is subsequent loss of contact between the ground and any part of his/her person or bat, or between the bat and person."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground3">"<b>30.2.1</b>If only one batter is within a ground, it is his/her ground and will remain so even if he/she is later joined there by the other batter."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground4">"<b>30.2.2</b> If both batters are in the same ground and one of them subsequently leaves it, the ground belongs to the batter who remains in it."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground5">"<b>30.2.3</b>If there is no batter in either ground, then each ground belongs to whichever batter is nearer to it, or, if the batters are level, to whichever batter was nearer to it immediately prior to their drawing level."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground6">"<b>30.2.4</b>If a ground belongs to one batter then, unless there is a striker who has a runner, the other ground belongs to the other batter, irrespective of his/her position."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground7">"<b>30.2.5</b>When a batter who has a runner is striker, his/her ground is always at the wicket-keeper’s end.  However, 30.2.1, 30.2.2, 30.2.3 and 30.2.4 will still apply, but only to the runner and the non-striker, so that that ground will also belong to either the non-striker or the runner, as the case may be."</string>
    <string name="batter_out_of_his_ground8">"The non-striker, when standing at the bowler’s end, should be positioned on the opposite side of the wicket to that from which the ball is being delivered, unless a request to do otherwise is granted by the umpire."</string>

    <string name="appeals">"Neither umpire shall give a batter out, even though he/she may be out under the Laws, unless appealed to by a fielder.  This shall not debar a batter who is out under any of the Laws from leaving the wicket without an appeal having been made.  Note, however, the provisions of 31.7."</string>
    <string name="appeals2">"A batter is dismissed if he/she is either given out by an umpire, on appeal or out under any of the Laws and leaves the wicket as in 31.1."</string>
    <string name="appeals3">"For an appeal to be valid, it must be made before the bowler begins his/her run-up or, if there is no run-up, his/her bowling action to deliver the next ball, and before Time has been called.\nThe call of Over does not invalidate an appeal made prior to the start of the following over, provided Time has not been called.  See Laws 12.2 (Call of Time) and 17.2 (Start of an over)."</string>
    <string name="appeals4">"An appeal “How’s That?” covers all ways of being out."</string>
    <string name="appeals5">"The striker’s end umpire shall answer all appeals arising out of any of Laws 35 (Hit wicket), 39 (Stumped) or 38 (Run out) when this occurs at the wicket-keeper’s end.  The bowler’s end umpire shall answer all other appeals.\nWhen an appeal is made, each umpire shall answer on any matter that falls within his/her jurisdiction.\nWhen a batter has been given Not out, either umpire may answer an appeal, made in accordance with 31.3, if it is on a further matter and is within his/her jurisdiction."</string>
    <string name="appeals6">"Each umpire shall answer appeals on matters within his/her own jurisdiction.  If an umpire is doubtful about any point that the other umpire may have been in a better position to see, he/she shall consult the latter on this point of fact and shall then give the decision.  If, after consultation, there is still doubt remaining, the decision shall be Not out."</string>
    <string name="appeals7">"An umpire shall intervene if satisfied that a batter, not having been given out, has left the wicket under a misapprehension of being out.  The umpire intervening shall call and signal Dead ball to prevent any further action by the fielding side and shall recall the batter.\nA batter may be recalled at any time up to the instant when the ball comes into play for the next delivery, unless it is the final wicket of the innings, in which case it should be up to the instant when the umpires leave the field."</string>
    <string name="appeals8">"The captain of the fielding side may withdraw an appeal only after obtaining the consent of the umpire within whose jurisdiction the appeal falls. If such consent is given, the umpire concerned shall, if applicable, revoke the decision and recall the batter.\nThe withdrawal of an appeal must be before the instant when the ball comes into play for the next delivery or, if the innings has been completed, the instant when the umpires leave the field."</string>

    <string name="bowled">"<b>32.1.1</b> The striker is out Bowled if his/her wicket is fairly broken by a ball delivered by the bowler, not being a No ball, even if it first touches the striker’s bat or person."</string>
    <string name="bowled2">"<b>32.1.2</b>However, the striker shall not be out Bowled if before striking the wicket the ball has been in contact with any other player or an umpire.  The striker will, however, be subject to Laws 37 (Obstructing the field), 38 (Run out) and 39 (Stumped)."</string>
    <string name="bowled3">"The striker is out Bowled if his/her wicket is fairly broken as in 32.1, even though a decision against him/her for any other method of dismissal would be justified."</string>

    <string name="caught">"The striker is out Caught if a ball delivered by the bowler, not being a No ball, touches his/her bat without having previously been in contact with any fielder, and is subsequently held by a fielder as a fair catch, as described in 33.2 and 33.3, before it touches the ground."</string>
    <string name="caught2">"<b>33.2.1</b> A catch will be fair only if, in every case either the ball, at any time or any fielder in contact with the ball,is not grounded beyond the boundary before the catch is completed.  Note Laws 19.4 (Ball grounded beyond the boundary) and 19.5 (Fielder grounded beyond the boundary)."</string>
    <string name="caught3">"<b>33.2.2</b>Furthermore, a catch will be fair if any of the following conditions applies:"</string>
    <string name="caught4">"<b>33.2.2.1</b>the ball is held in the hand or hands of a fielder, even if the hand holding the ball is touching the ground, or is hugged to the body, or lodges in the external protective equipment worn by a fielder, or lodges accidentally in a fielder’s clothing."</string>
    <string name="caught5">"<b>33.2.2.2</b> a fielder catches the ball after it has been lawfully struck more than once by the striker, but only if it has not been grounded since it was first struck.  See Law 34 (Hit the ball twice)."</string>
    <string name="caught6">"<b>33.2.2.3</b>a fielder catches the ball after it has touched the wicket, an umpire, another fielder, a runner or the other batter."</string>
    <string name="caught7">"<b>33.2.2.4</b> a fielder catches the ball after it has crossed the boundary in the air, provided that the conditions in 33.2.1 are met."</string>
    <string name="caught8">"<b>33.2.2.5</b>the ball is caught off an obstruction within the boundary that is not designated a boundary by the umpires."</string>
    <string name="caught9">"The act of making a catch shall start from the time when the ball first comes into contact with a fielder’s person and shall end when a fielder obtains complete control over both the ball and his/her own movement."</string>
    <string name="caught10">"If the striker is dismissed Caught, runs from that delivery completed by the batters before the completion of the catch shall not be scored but any runs for penalties awarded to either side shall stand. Law 18.11 (Batter returning to wicket he/she has left) shall apply from the instant of the completion of the catch."</string>
    <string name="caught11">"If the criteria of 33.1 are met and the striker is not out Bowled, then he/she is out Caught, even though a decision against either batter for another method of dismissal would be justified."</string>

    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice">"<b>34.1.1</b>The striker is out Hit the ball twice if, while the ball is in play, it strikes any part of his/her person or is struck by his/her bat and, before the ball has been touched by a fielder, the striker wilfully strikes it again with his/her bat or person, other than a hand not holding the bat, except for the sole purpose of guarding his/her wicket.  See 34.3 and Law 37 (Obstructing the field)."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice2">"<b>34.1.2</b> For the purpose of this Law ‘struck’ or ‘strike’ shall include contact with the person of the striker."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice3">"<b>34.1.3</b>This Law will apply whether or not No ball is called."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice4">"The striker will not be out under this Law if he/she"</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice5">"<b>34.2.1</b>strikes the ball a second or subsequent time in order to return the ball to any fielder.  Note, however, the provisions of Law 37.4 (Returning the ball to a fielder)."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice6">"<b>34.2.2</b>wilfully strikes the ball after it has touched a fielder.  Note, however the provisions of Law 37.1 (Out Obstructing the field)."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice7">"The striker may, solely in order to guard his/her wicket and before the ball has been touched by a fielder, lawfully strike the ball a second or subsequent time with the bat, or with any part of his/her person other than a hand not holding the bat.\nThe striker may guard his/her wicket even if the delivery is a No ball. However, the striker may not prevent the ball from being caught by striking the ball more than once in defence of his/her wicket. See Law 37.3 (Obstructing a ball from being caught)."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice8">"When the ball is lawfully struck more than once, as permitted in 34.3, if the ball does not become dead for any reason, the umpire shall call and signal Dead ball as soon as the ball reaches the boundary or at the completion of the first run. However, he/she shall delay the call of Dead ball to allow the opportunity for a catch to be completed.\nThe umpire shall\n- disallow all runs to the batting side\n- return any not out batter to his/her original end\n- signal No ball to the scorers if applicable.\n- award any 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side)."</string>
    <string name="hit_the_ball_twice9">"The bowler does not get credit for the wicket."</string>

    <string name="hit">&quot;&lt;b&gt;35.1.1&lt;/b&gt; The striker is out hit wicket if, after the bowler has entered the delivery stride and while the ball is in play, his/her wicket is broken by either the striker&apos;s bat or person as described in Laws 29.2.1.2 to 29.2.1.4 (Breaking the wicket fairly) in any of the following circumstances:</string>"
    <string name="hit2">"<b>35.1.1.1</b>in the course of any action taken by him/her in preparing to receive or in receiving a delivery,"</string>
    <string name="hit3">"<b>35.1.1.2</b> in setting off for the first run immediately after playing or playing at the ball,"</string>
    <string name="hit4">"<b>35.1.1.3</b>if no attempt is made to play the ball, in setting off for the first run, providing that in the opinion of the umpire this is immediately after the striker has had the opportunity of playing the ball,"</string>
    <string name="hit5">"<b>35.1.1.4</b>in lawfully making a second or further stroke for the purpose of guarding his/her wicket within the provisions of Law 34.3 (Ball lawfully struck more than once)."</string>
    <string name="hit6">"<b>35.1.2</b> If the striker puts his/her wicket down in any of the ways described in Laws 29.1.1.2 to 29.1.1.4 before the bowler has entered the delivery stride, either umpire shall call and signal Dead ball."</string>
    <string name="hit7">"The striker is not out under this Law should his/her wicket be put down in any of the ways referred to in 35.1 if any of the following applies:\n- it occurs after the striker has completed any action in receiving the delivery, other than in 35.1.1.2 to 35.1.1.4.\n- it occurs when the striker is in the act of running, other than setting off immediately for the first run.\n- it occurs when the striker is trying to avoid being run out or stumped.\n- it occurs when the striker is trying to avoid a throw in at any time.\n- the bowler after entering the delivery stride does not deliver the ball.  In this case either umpire shall immediately call and signal Dead ball.  See Law 20.4 (Umpire calling and signalling Dead ball).\n- the delivery is a No ball."</string>
    <string name="hit8">"No runs shall be scored when the striker is dismissed Hit wicket other than one-run penalty for a Wide and any award of 5 Penalty runs."</string>

    <string name="LBW">"The striker is out LBW if all the circumstances set out in 36.1.1 to 36.1.5 apply."</string>
    <string name="LBW2">"<b>36.1.1</b>The bowler delivers a ball, not being a No ball"</string>
    <string name="LBW3">"<b>36.1.2</b>the ball, if it is not intercepted full-pitch, pitches in line between wicket and wicket or on the off side of the striker’s wicket"</string>
    <string name="LBW4">"<b>36.1.3</b> the ball not having previously touched his/her bat, the striker intercepts the ball, either full-pitch or after pitching, with any part of his/her person"</string>
    <string name="LBW5">"<b>36.1.4</b> the point of impact, even if above the level of the bails,either is between wicket and wicket or if the striker has made no genuine attempt to play the ball with the bat, is between wicket and wicket or outside the line of the off stump."</string>
    <string name="LBW6">"<b>36.1.5</b>but for the interception, the ball would have hit the wicket."</string>
    <string name="LBW7">"<b>36.2.1</b>In assessing points in 36.1.3, 36.1.4 and 36.1.5, only the first interception is to be considered."</string>
    <string name="LBW8">"<b>36.2.2</b> In assessing point 36.1.3, if the ball makes contact with the striker’s person and bat simultaneously, this shall be considered as the ball having first touched the bat."</string>
    <string name="LBW9">"<b>36.2.3</b> In assessing point 36.1.5, it is to be assumed that the path of the ball before interception would have continued after interception, irrespective of whether the ball might have pitched subsequently or not."</string>
    <string name="LBW10">"The off side of the striker’s wicket shall be determined by the striker’s batting position at the moment the ball comes into play for that delivery.  See Appendix A.13."</string>

    <string name="obstructing_the_field">"<b>37.1.1</b>Either batter is out Obstructing the field if, except in the circumstances of 37.2, and while the ball is in play, he/she wilfully attempts to obstruct or distract the fielding side by word or action. See also Law 34 (Hit the ball twice)."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field2">"<b>37.1.2</b>The striker is out Obstructing the field if, except in the circumstances of 37.2, in the act of receiving a ball delivered by the bowler, he/she wilfully strikes the ball with a hand not holding the bat. This will apply whether it is the first strike or a second or subsequent strike. The act of receiving the ball shall extend both to playing at the ball and to striking the ball more than once in defence of his/her wicket."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field3">"<b>37.1.3</b>This Law will apply whether or not No ball is called."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field4">"A batter shall not be out Obstructing the field if the obstruction or distraction is accidental,\nor the obstruction is in order to avoid injury,\nor in the case of the striker, he/she makes a second or subsequent strike to guard his/her wicket lawfully as in Law 34.3 (Ball lawfully struck more than once).\nHowever, see 37.3."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field5">"<b>37.3.1</b>If the delivery is not a No ball, the striker is out Obstructing the field if wilful obstruction or distraction by either batter prevents the striker being out Caught."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field6">"<b>37.3.2</b>37.3.1 shall apply even if an obstruction is caused by the striker in lawfully guarding his/her wicket under the provision of Law 34.3 (Ball lawfully struck more than once)."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field7">"<b>37.3.3</b> If an obstruction or distraction takes place from a No ball then the batter who caused the obstruction or distraction will be out Obstructing the field.\nHowever, the striker is not out if the obstruction of a catch occurs while defending his/her wicket from a No ball with a lawful second strike."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field8">"Either batter is out Obstructing the field if, at any time while the ball is in play and, without the consent of a fielder, he/she uses the bat or any part of his/her person to return the ball to any fielder."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field9">"When either batter is dismissed Obstructing the field,"</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field10">"<b>37.5.1</b>unless the obstruction or distraction prevents the striker being out Caught, any runs completed by the batters before the offence shall be scored, together with any one-run Penalty for No ball or Wide, or any other award of 5 Penalty runs to either side. See Laws 18.6 (Runs awarded for penalties) and 18.8 (Runs scored when a batter is dismissed)."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field11">"<b>37.5.2</b> if the obstruction or distraction prevents the striker being out Caught, any runs completed by the batters shall not be scored but any award of 5 Penalty runs to either side shall stand. Law 18.11 (Batter returning to original end) will apply."</string>
    <string name="obstructing_the_field12">"The bowler does not get credit for the wicket."</string>

    <string name="run_out">"Either batter is out Run out, except as in 38.2, if, at any time while the ball is in play, he/she is out of his/her ground and his/her wicket is fairly broken by the action of a fielder even though No ball has been called, except in the circumstances of 38.2.2.2, and whether or not a run is being attempted."</string>
    <string name="run_out2">"<b>38.2.1</b>A batter is not out Run out in the circumstances of 38.2.1.1 or 38.2.1.2."</string>
    <string name="run_out3">"<b>38.2.1.1</b> He/She has been within his/her ground and has subsequently left it to avoid injury, when the wicket is broken.\nNote also the provisions of Law 30.1.2 (When out of his/her ground)."</string>
    <string name="run_out4">"<b>38.2.1.2</b>The ball, delivered by the bowler, has not made contact with a fielder before the wicket is broken."</string>
    <string name="run_out5">"<b>38.2.2</b> The striker is not out Run out in any of the circumstances in 38.2.2.1 and 38.2.2.2."</string>
    <string name="run_out6">"<b>38.2.2.1</b>He/She is out Stumped.  See Laws 25.6.5 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner) and 39.1.2 (Out Stumped)."</string>
    <string name="run_out7">"<b>38.2.2.2</b>No ball has been called and he/she is out of his/her ground not attempting a run and the wicket is fairly broken by the wicket-keeper without the intervention of another fielder.\nHowever, if the striker has a runner and the runner is out of his/her ground, then only 38.1 applies."</string>
    <string name="run_out8">"<b>38.3.1</b>At any time from the moment the ball comes into play until the instant when the bowler would normally have been expected to release the ball, the non-striker is liable to be Run out if he/she is out of his/her ground. In these circumstances the non-striker will be out Run out if he/she is out of his/her ground when his/her wicket is broken by the bowler throwing the ball at the stumps or by the bowler’s hand holding the ball, whether or not the ball is subsequently delivered."</string>
    <string name="run_out9">"<b>38.3.1.1</b>The instant when the bowler would normally have been expected to release the ball is defined as the moment the bowler’s arm reaches the highest point of his/her normal bowling action in the delivery swing."</string>
    <string name="run_out10">"<b>38.3.1.2</b> Even if the non-striker had left his/her ground before the instant at which the bowler would normally have been expected to release the ball, once the bowler has reached that point it is no longer possible for the bowler to run out the non-striker under this Law."</string>
    <string name="run_out11">"<b>38.3.2</b> If the ball is not delivered,\n- if there is an appeal, the umpire shall make his/her decision on the Run out.\n- if there is no appeal, or if the decision is not out, he/she shall call and signal Dead ball as soon as possible.\n- the ball shall not count as one in the over."</string>
    <string name="run_out12">"<b>38.3.3</b>If the ball is delivered and there is an appeal,\n- the umpire shall make his/her decision on the Run out.\n- if the non-striker is not dismissed, the ball remains in play and Law 21.6 (Bowler breaking wicket in delivering ball) shall apply.\n- if the non-striker is dismissed, the ball shall not count as one in the over."</string>
    <string name="run_out13">"The batter out in the circumstances of 38.1 is the one whose ground is at the end where the wicket is broke.  See Laws 25.6 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner) and 30.2 (Which is a batter’s ground)."</string>
    <string name="run_out14">"If either batter is dismissed Run out, the run in progress when the wicket is broken shall not be scored, but any runs completed by the batters shall stand, together with any runs for penalties awarded to either side.  See Laws 18.6 (Runs awarded for penalties) and 18.8 (Runs scored when a batter is dismissed).\nIf, however, a striker who has a runner is himself/herself dismissed Run out and runs are completed by the runner and the other batter before the wicket is broken.\n- all runs to the batting side from that delivery shall be disallowed.\n- the one run penalty for No ball shall stand and 5 run penalties shall be allowed.\n- the umpire shall return the non-striker to his/her original end.\nSee Law 25.6 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner)."</string>
    <string name="run_out15">"The bowler does not get credit for the wicket."</string>

    <string name="stumped">"<b>39.1.1</b>The striker is out Stumped, except as in 39.3, if a ball which is delivered is not called No ball and  he/she is out of his/her ground, other than as in 39.3.1 and  he/she has not attempted a run when his/her wicket is fairly put down by the wicket-keeper without the intervention of another fielder. Note, however Laws 25.6.2 and 25.6.5 (Dismissal and conduct of a batter and his/her runner) and 27.3 (Position of wicket-keeper)."</string>
    <string name="stumped2">"<b>39.1.2</b>The striker is out Stumped if all the conditions of 39.1.1 are satisfied, even though a decision of Run out would be justified."</string>
    <string name="stumped3">"If the wicket is put down by the ball, it shall be regarded as having been put down by the wicket-keeper if the ball:rebounds on to the stumps from any part of the wicket-keeper’s person or equipment or  has been kicked or thrown on to the stumps by the wicket-keeper."</string>
    <string name="stumped4">"<b>39.3.1</b>The striker will not be out Stumped if, after having received the delivery, he/she has left his/her ground in order to avoid injury."</string>
    <string name="stumped5">"<b>39.3.2</b>If the striker is not out Stumped he/she may, except in the circumstances of Law 38.2.2.2 (Batsman not out Run out), be out Run out if the conditions of Law 38.1 (Out Run out) apply."</string>
    <string name="stumped6">"When a striker is dismissed Stumped from a Wide ball, the one-run penalty shall stand. Note Laws 12.9 (Conclusion of match), 16.6 (Winning hit or extras) and 22.2 (Call and signal of Wide ball) mean that if the penalty for a Wide concludes the match, then a stumping is not possible, but the one-run penalty for the Wide remains."</string>

    <string name="timed_out">"<b>40.1.1</b>After the fall of a wicket or the retirement of a batter, the incoming batter must, unless Time has been called, be ready to receive the ball, or for the other batter to be ready to receive the next ball within 3 minutes of the dismissal or retirement. If this requirement is not met, the incoming batter will be out, Timed out."</string>
    <string name="timed_out2">"<b>40.1.2</b>In the event of an extended delay in which no batter comes to the wicket, the umpires shall adopt the procedure of Law 16.3 (Umpires awarding a match).  For the purposes of that Law the start of the action shall be taken as the expiry of the 3 minutes referred to above."</string>
    <string name="timed_out3">"The bowler does not get credit for the wicket."</string>

    <string name="unfair_play">"The captains are responsible for ensuring that play is conducted within The Spirit of Cricket, as described in The Preamble - The Spirit of Cricket, as well as within the Laws."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play2">"<b>41.2.1</b>The umpires shall be the sole judges of fair and unfair play. If an umpire considers that any action by a player, not covered in the Laws, is unfair, he/she shall call and signal Dead ball, if appropriate, as soon as it becomes clear that the call will not disadvantage the non-offending side, and report the matter to the other umpire."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play3">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.2.1.1&lt;/b&gt;If this is a first offence by that side, the bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then
- summon the offending player&apos;s captain and issue a first and final warning which shall apply to all members of the team for the remainder of the match
- warn the offending player&apos;s captain that any further such offence by any member of his/her team shall result in the award of 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play4">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.2.1.2&lt;/b&gt;If this is a second or subsequent offence by that side, the bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then
- summon the offending player&apos;s captain and inform him/her that there has been a further such offence.
- award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing side.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play5">"<b>41.2.1.3</b>The umpires together shall report the incident as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play6">"<b>41.3.1</b>The umpires shall make frequent and irregular inspections of the ball. In addition, they shall immediately inspect the ball if they suspect anyone of attempting to change the condition of the ball, except as permitted in 41.3.2."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play7">"<b>41.3.2</b>It is an offence for any player to take any action which changes the condition of the ball.\nExcept in carrying out his/her normal duties, a batter is not allowed to wilfully damage the ball. See also Law 5.5 (Damage to the ball).\nA fielder may, however"</string>
    <string name="unfair_play8">"<b>41.3.2.1</b>polish the ball on his/her clothing provided that no artificial substance is used, that the only natural substance used is sweat, and that such polishing wastes no time."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play9">"<b>41.3.2.2</b> remove mud from the ball under the supervision of an umpire."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play10">"<b>41.3.2.3</b>dry a wet ball on a piece of cloth that has been approved by the umpires."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play11">"<b>41.3.3</b>The umpires shall consider the condition of the ball to have been unfairly changed if any action by any player does not comply with the conditions in 41.3.2."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play12">"<b>41.3.4</b> If the umpires consider that the condition of the ball has been unfairly changed by a member or members of either side, they shall ask the captain of the opposing side if he/she would like the ball to be replaced. If necessary, in the case of the batting side, the batters at the wicket may deputise for their captain."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play13">"<b>41.3.4.1</b> If a replacement ball is requested, the umpires shall select and bring into use immediately, a ball which shall have wear comparable to that of the previous ball immediately prior to the contravention."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play14">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.3.4.2&lt;/b&gt;  Regardless of whether a replacement ball has been chosen to be used, the bowler&apos;s end umpire shall
- award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing side.
- if appropriate, inform the batters at the wicket and the captain of the fielding side that the ball has been changed and the reason for their action.
- inform the captain of the batting side as soon as practicable of what has occurred.
The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play15">"<b>41.3.5</b> If the umpires agree that in the match there has been any further instance by that team of unfairly changing the condition of the ball, they shall"</string>
    <string name="unfair_play16">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.3.5.1&lt;/b&gt;  repeat the procedure in 41.3.4.1 and 41.3.4.2.
If the further offence is committed by the fielding side, additionally the bowler&apos;s end umpire shall&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play17">"<b>41.3.5.2</b> direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend immediately from bowling the bowler who delivered the preceding ball; he/she shall not be allowed to bowl again in the match. inform the batters at the wicket and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for the action. if necessary, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play18">"<b>41.4.1</b> It is unfair for any fielder deliberately to attempt to distract the striker while he/she is preparing to receive or receiving a delivery."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play19">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.4.2&lt;/b&gt;  If either umpire considers that any action by a fielder is such an attempt, he/she shall immediately call and signal Dead ball and inform the other umpire of the reason for the call.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side.inform the captain of the fielding side, the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for the action.Neither batter shall be dismissed from that delivery and the ball shall not count as one of the over. However, if either umpire had reason to call and signal No ball, he/she shall do so regardless of the attempt to distract, and this call shall stand.
Together with the other umpire report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play20">"<b>41.5.1</b>In addition to 41.4, it is unfair for any fielder wilfully to attempt, by word or action, to distract, deceive or obstruct either batter after the striker has received the ball."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play21">"<b>41.5.2</b> It is for either one of the umpires to decide whether any distraction, deception or obstruction is wilful or not."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play22">"<b>41.5.3</b>If either umpire considers that a fielder has caused or attempted to cause such a distraction, deception or obstruction, he/she shall immediately call and signal Dead ball and inform the other umpire of the reason for the call."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play23">"<b>41.5.4</b>Neither batter shall be dismissed from that delivery."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play24">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.5.5&lt;/b&gt;If an obstruction involves physical contact, the umpires together shall decide whether or not an offence under Law 42 (Players&apos; conduct) has been committed.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play25">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.5.5.1&lt;/b&gt;If an offence under Law 42 (Players&apos; conduct) has been committed, they shall apply the relevant procedures in Law 42 and shall also apply each of 41.5.7 to 41.5.9.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play26">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.5.5.2&lt;/b&gt;  If they consider that there has been no offence under Law 42 (Players&apos; conduct), they shall apply each of 41.5.6 to 41.5.10.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play27">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.5.6&lt;/b&gt;The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall Signal No ball or Wide to the scorers, if applicable, award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side, inform the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action and as soon as practicable inform the captain of the batting side.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play28">"<b>41.5.7</b> The ball shall not count as one of the over."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play29">"<b>41.5.8</b>  Any runs completed by the batters before the offence shall be scored, together with any runs for penalties awarded to either side. Additionally, the run in progress shall be scored whether or not the batters had already crossed at the instant of the offence."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play30">"<b>41.5.9</b> The batters at the wicket shall decide which of them is to face the next delivery."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play31">"<b>41.5.10</b> The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play32">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.6.1&lt;/b&gt;The bowling of short pitched deliveries is dangerous if the bowler&apos;s end umpire considers that, taking into consideration the skill of the striker, by their speed, length, height and direction they are likely to inflict physical injury on him/her. The fact that the striker is wearing protective equipment shall be disregarded.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play33">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.6.2&lt;/b&gt; The bowler&apos;s end umpire may consider that the bowling of short pitched deliveries, although not dangerous under 41.6.1, is unfair if they repeatedly pass above head height of the striker standing upright at the crease. See also Law 21.10 (Ball bouncing over head height of striker).&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play34">"<b>41.6.3</b>As soon as the umpire decides that the bowling of short pitched deliveries has become dangerous under 41.6.1, or unfair under 41.6.2, he/she shall call and signal No ball.When the ball is dead, the umpire shall caution the bowler, indicating that this is a first and final warning, and inform the other umpire, the captain of the fielding side and the batters of what has occurred.This caution shall apply to that bowler throughout the innings."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play35">"<b>41.6.4</b>  Should there be any further such delivery by the same bowler in that innings, the umpire shall\n- call and signal No ball\n- when the ball is dead, direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling\n  - inform the other umpire for the reason for this action. The bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.\nIf applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.\n- The umpire shall inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play36">"<b>41.6.5</b>The warning sequence in 41.6.3 and 41.6.4 is independent of the warning and action sequence in 41.7."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play37">"<b>41.7.1</b> Any delivery, which passes or would have passed, without pitching, above waist height of the striker standing upright at the popping crease, is unfair. Whenever such a delivery is bowled, the umpire shall call and signal No ball."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play38">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.7.2&lt;/b&gt; The bowling of a delivery as defined in 41.7.1 is also dangerous if the bowler&apos;s end umpire considers that there is a risk of injury to the striker. In making that judgement the umpire shall:
- disregard any protective equipment worn by the striker be mindful of:
- the speed, height and direction of the delivery the skill of the striker
- the repeated nature of such deliveries.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play39">"<b>41.7.3</b>If the umpire considers a non-pitching delivery, or a series of non-pitching deliveries, to be dangerous under 41.7.2, when the ball is dead, the umpire shall repeat the No ball signal to the scorers and then caution the bowler, indicating that this is a first and final warning. The umpire shall also inform the other umpire, the captain of the fielding side and the batters of what has occurred. This caution shall apply to that bowler throughout the innings."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play40">"<b>41.7.4</b>  Should there be any further dangerous such delivery by the same bowler in that innings, the umpire shall call and signal No ball when the ball is dead, direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling inform the other umpire for the reason for this action. The bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.\nIf applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.\nAdditionally, the umpire shall inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play41">"<b>41.7.5</b>The warning and action sequences in 41.7.3 and 41.7.4 are independent of those in 41.6."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play42">"<b>41.7.6</b> If the umpire considers that a bowler deliberately bowled a non-pitching delivery, deemed to be unfair as defined in 41.7.1, then the caution and warning in 41.7.3 shall be dispensed with. The umpire shall immediately call and signal No ball.\nwhen the ball is dead, direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling and inform the other umpire for the reason for this action.\nThe bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.\nIf applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.\ninform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play43">"If the umpire considers that the bowler has delivered a deliberate front-foot No ball, he/she shall - \nimmediately call and signal No ball.\n- when the ball is dead, direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling\n- inform the other umpire for the reason for this action.\nThe bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.\nIf applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.\n- inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play44">"<b>41.9.1</b>It is unfair for any fielder to waste time."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play45">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.9.2&lt;/b&gt; If either umpire considers that the progress of an over is unnecessarily slow, or time is being wasted in any other way, by the captain of the fielding side or by any other fielder, at the first instance the umpire concerned shall
- if the ball is in play, call and signal Dead ball.
- inform the other umpire of what has occurred.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then
- warn the captain of the fielding side, indicating that this is a first and final warning.
- inform the batters of what has occurred.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play46">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.9.3&lt;/b&gt;  If either umpire considers that there is any further waste of time in that innings by any fielder, the umpire concerned shall if the ball is in play, call and signal Dead ball. inform the other umpire of what has occurred.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then either if the waste of time is not during an over, award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side and inform the captain of the fielding side of the reason for this action or    if the waste of time is during the course of an over, direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling.
 The bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.
If applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over.
Additionally the umpire shall inform the batters and, as soon as is practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.
The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play47">"<b>41.10.1</b> It is unfair for a batter to waste time. In normal circumstances, the striker should always be ready to take strike when the bowler is ready to start his/her run-up."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play48">"<b>41.10.2</b> Should either batter waste time by failing to meet this requirement, or in any other way, the following procedure shall be adopted. At the first instance, either before the bowler starts his/her run-up or when the ball becomes dead, as appropriate, the umpire shall\n- warn both batters and indicate that this is a first and final warning. This warning shall apply throughout the innings. The umpire shall so inform each incoming batter.\n- inform the other umpire of what has occurred.\n- inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play49">"<b>41.10.3</b>If there is any further time wasting by any batter in that innings, the umpire shall, at the appropriate time while the ball is dead\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the fielding side.\n- inform the other umpire of the reason for this action.\n- inform the other batter, the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play50">"The protected area is defined as that area of the pitch contained within a rectangle bounded at each end by imaginary lines parallel to the popping creases and 5 ft/1.52 m in front of each, and on the sides by imaginary lines, one each side of the imaginary line joining the centres of the two middle stumps, each parallel to it and 1 ft/30.48 cm from it."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play51">"<b>41.12.1</b> It is unfair to cause deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch. A fielder will be deemed to be causing avoidable damage if either umpire considers that his/her presence on the pitch is without reasonable cause."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play52">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.12.2&lt;/b&gt; If a fielder causes deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch, other than as in 41.13.1, at the first instance the umpire seeing the contravention shall, when the ball is dead, inform the other umpire. The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then caution the captain of the fielding side and indicate that this is a first and final warning. This warning shall apply throughout the innings.inform the batters of what has occurred.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play53">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.12.3&lt;/b&gt;  If, in that innings, there is any further instance of deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch, by any fielder, the umpire seeing the contravention shall, when the ball is dead, inform the other umpire. The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then signal No ball or Wide to the scorers, if applicable. award 5 Penalty runs to the batting side.
award any other 5-run Penalty that is applicable.
inform the fielding captain of the reason for this action. inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.
The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and,if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play54">"<b>41.13.1</b> It is unfair for a bowler to enter the protected area in his/her follow-through without reasonable cause, whether or not the ball is delivered."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play55">"<b>41.13.2</b>  If a bowler contravenes this Law, at the first instance and when the ball is dead, the umpire shall\n- caution the bowler and inform the other umpire of what has occurred.\nThis caution shall apply to that bowler throughout the innings.\n- inform the captain of the fielding side and the batters of what has occurred."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play56">"<b>41.13.3</b> If, in that innings, the same bowler again contravenes this Law, the umpire shall repeat the above procedure indicating that this is a final warning. This warning shall also apply throughout the innings."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play57">"<b>41.13.4</b>  If, in that innings, the same bowler contravenes this Law a third time, when the ball is dead, the umpire shall,direct the captain of the fielding side to suspend the bowler immediately from bowling. If applicable, the over shall be completed by another bowler, who shall neither have bowled any part of the previous over, nor be allowed to bowl any part of the next over. The bowler thus suspended shall not be allowed to bowl again in that innings.inform the other umpire of the reason for this action. inform the batters and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play58">"<b>41.14.1</b> It is unfair to cause deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch. If the striker enters the protected area in playing or playing at the ball, he/she must move from it immediately thereafter. A batter will be deemed to be causing avoidable damage if either umpire considers that his/her presence on the pitch is without reasonable cause."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play59">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.14.2&lt;/b&gt;If either batter causes deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch, other than as in 41.15, at the first instance the umpire seeing the contravention shall, when the ball is dead, inform the other umpire of the occurrence. The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then warn both batters that the practice is unfair and indicate that this is a first and final warning. This warning shall apply throughout the innings. The umpire shall so inform each incoming batter.inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.</string>
    <string name="unfair_play60">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.14.3&lt;/b&gt; If there is any further instance of deliberate or avoidable damage to the pitch by any batter in that innings, the umpire seeing the contravention shall, when the ball is dead, inform the other umpire of the occurrence.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall disallow all runs to the batting side return any not out batter to his/her original end signal No ball or Wide to the scorers if applicable. award 5 Penalty runs to the fielding side.award any other 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side).
inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for this action.
The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and,if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play61">"<b>41.15.1</b>The striker shall not adopt a batting position in the protected area or so close to it that frequent encroachment is inevitable.The striker may make a mark on the pitch, for the purpose of indicating his/her batting position, provided that no mark is unreasonably close to the protected area."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play62">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.15.2&lt;/b&gt; If there is breach of any of the conditions in 41.15.1 by the striker, the umpire seeing the contravention shall, if the bowler has not entered his/her delivery stride, immediately call and signal Dead ball, otherwise, he/she shall wait until the ball is dead and then inform the other umpire of the occurrence.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then warn the striker that the practice is unfair and indicate that this is a first and final warning. This warning shall apply throughout the innings. The umpire shall so inform the non-striker and each incoming batter. inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of what has occurred.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play63">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.15.3&lt;/b&gt;If there is any further breach of any of the conditions in 41.15.1 by any batter in that innings, the umpire seeing the contravention shall, if the bowler has not entered his/ her delivery stride, immediately call and signal Dead ball,otherwise, he/she shall wait until the ball is dead and then inform the other umpire of the occurrence.
The bowler&apos;s end umpire shall then disallow all runs to the batting side return any not out batter to his/her original end signal No ball or Wide to the scorers if applicable. award 5 Penalty runs to the fielding side. award any other 5-run Penalty that is applicable except for Penalty runs under Law 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side). inform the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side of the reason for this action.
The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play64">"It is unfair for the batters to attempt to steal a run during the bowler's run-up. Unless the bowler attempts to run out the non-striker - see Law 38.3 (Non-striker leaving his/her ground early) - the umpire shall\n- call and signal Dead ball as soon as the batters cross in such an attempt.\n- inform the other umpire of the reason for this action.\nThe bowler's end umpire shall then\n- return the batters to their original ends and disallow the attempted run.\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the fielding side.\n- award any other 5-run Penalty that is applicable.\n- inform the batters, the captain of the fielding side and, as soon as practicable, the captain of the batting side, of the reason for this action.\nThe umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending side and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play65">"<b>41.17.1</b> When Penalty runs are awarded to either side, when the ball is dead the umpire shall signal the Penalty runs to the scorers. See Law 2.13 (Signals)."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play66">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.17.2&lt;/b&gt; Penalty runs shall be awarded in each case where the Laws require the award, even if a result has already been achieved. See Law 16.6 (Winning hit or extras).
Note, however, that the restrictions on awarding Penalty runs, in Laws 23.3 (Leg byes not to be awarded), 25.7 (Restriction on the striker&apos;s runner), 28.3 (Protective helmets belonging to the fielding side) and 34.4 (Runs permitted from ball lawfully struck more than once) will apply.&quot;</string>
    <string name="unfair_play67">"<b>41.17.3</b>When 5 Penalty runs are awarded to the batting side, they shall be scored as Penalty extras and shall be in addition to any other penalties.they are awarded when the ball is dead and shall not be regarded as runs scored from either the immediately preceding delivery or the immediately following delivery, and shall be in addition to any runs from those deliveries. the batters shall not change ends solely by reason of the 5-run penalty."</string>
    <string name="unfair_play68">&quot;&lt;b&gt;41.17.4&lt;/b&gt;When 5 Penalty runs are awarded to the fielding side, they shall be added as Penalty extras to that side&apos;s total of runs in its most recently completed innings. If the fielding side has not completed an innings, the 5 Penalty runs shall be added to the score in its next innings.&quot;</string>

    <string name="players_conduct">"<b>42.1.1</b> The umpires shall act upon any unacceptable conduct.  Four Levels of offence and the corresponding actions by the umpires are identified as Level 1, Level 2, Level 3 and Level 4 offences in 42.2 to 42.5."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct2">"<b>42.1.2</b> If either umpire considers that the conduct of a player, at any time during the match, is unacceptable, the umpire concerned shall call and signal Dead ball.  This call may be delayed until the umpire is satisfied that it will not disadvantage the non-offending side."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct3">"<b>42.1.3</b>The umpire concerned shall report the matter to the other umpire and together they shall decide whether misconduct has occurred.  If so, they shall determine into which of the Levels the conduct falls, as set out in 42.2 to 42.5 below, and then apply the related sanctions."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct4">"<b>42.1.4</b>  Any call of No ball or Wide before the offence shall stand."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct5">"<b>42.1.5</b>For each Level 1 to 4,\nPlaying time shall be counted as lost from the call of Time to the call of Play, excluding intervals (Law 11) and suspensions of play (Law 2.8).\nthe time for close of play on that day shall be extended by this length of time.\nif applicable, no overs shall be deducted during the last hour of the match solely on account of this time."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct6">"<b>42.2.1</b>Any of the following actions by a player shall constitute a Level 1 offence:\n- wilfully mistreating any part of the cricket ground, equipment or implements used in the match\n- showing dissent at an umpire’s decision by word or action\n- using language that, in the circumstances, is obscene, offensive or insulting\n- making an obscene gesture\n- appealing excessively\n- advancing towards an umpire in an aggressive manner when appealing\n- any other misconduct, the nature of which is, in the opinion of the umpires, equivalent to a Level 1 offence."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct7">"<b>42.2.2</b> If such an offence is committed, 42.2.2.1 to 42.2.2.6 shall be implemented as appropriate, according to whether or not it is the first offence at any Level."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct8">"<b>42.2.2.1</b>The umpire shall call Time, if necessary."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct9">"<b>42.2.2.2</b>Together the umpires shall summon and inform the offending player’s captain that an offence at this Level has occurred."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct10">"<b>42.2.2.3</b>If the Level 1 offence is the first offence, at any Level, by that team, the umpire shall"</string>
    <string name="players_conduct11">"<b>42.2.2.3.1</b> issue a first and final warning which shall apply to all members of the team for the remainder of the match."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct12">"<b>42.2.2.3.2</b>warn the offending player’s captain that any further Level 1 offence by any member of his/her team shall result in the award of 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct13">"<b>42.2.2.4</b> If the Level 1 offence follows an offence, at any Level, by that team, the umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct14">"<b>42.2.2.5</b> As soon as practicable the umpire shall call Play."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct15">"<b>42.2.2.6</b>The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending player’s team and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such further action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct16">"<b>42.3.1</b>   Any of the following actions by a player shall constitute a Level 2 offence:\n- showing serious dissent at an umpire’s decision by word or action\n- making inappropriate and deliberate physical contact with another player\n- throwing the ball at a player, umpire or another person in an inappropriate and dangerous manner\n- using language or gesture to another player, umpire, team official or spectator that, in the circumstances, is obscene or of a seriously insulting nature\n- or any other misconduct, the nature of which is, in the opinion of the umpires, equivalent to a Level 2 offence."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct17">"<b>42.3.2</b> If such an offence is committed, 42.3.2.1 to 42.3.2.6 shall be implemented."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct18">"<b>42.3.2.1</b> The umpire shall call Time, if necessary."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct19">"<b>42.3.2.2</b> Together the umpires shall summon and inform the offending player’s captain that an offence at this Level has occurred."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct20">"<b>42.3.2.3</b>The umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct21">"<b>42.3.2.4</b>The umpire shall warn the offending player’s captain that any future Level 1 offence by any member of his/her team shall result in the award of 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct22">"<b>42.3.2.5</b>As soon as practicable the Umpire shall call Play."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct23">"<b>42.3.2.6</b>The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending player’s team and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such further action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct24">"<b>42.4.1</b> Either of the following actions by a player shall constitute a Level 3 offence:\n-   intimidating an umpire by language or gesture\n-   threatening to assault a player or any other person except an umpire. See 42.5.1."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct25">"<b>42.4.2</b> If such an offence is committed, 42.4.2.1 to 42.4.2.8 shall be implemented."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct26">"<b>42.4.2.1</b>The umpire shall call Time, if necessary."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct27">"<b>42.4.2.2</b>Together the umpires shall summon and inform the offending player’s captain that an offence at this Level has occurred."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct28">"<b>42.4.2.3</b>The umpires shall direct the captain to remove the offending player immediately from the field of play for a period in accordance with the following:"</string>
    <string name="players_conduct29">"<b>42.4.2.3.1</b>In a match where the innings are not limited to a number of overs, the player shall be suspended from the field of play for 10 overs. Any balls remaining in the over in progress at the time of suspension shall not count towards the overs for which the player is suspended."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct30">"<b>42.4.2.3.2</b> In a match where the innings are limited to a number of overs, the player shall be suspended for one fifth of the number of overs allocated to the current innings at its commencement. If, in calculating the length of the suspension, a part-over results, it shall be considered as a whole over. Any balls remaining in the over in progress at the time of suspension shall not count towards the overs for which the player is suspended."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct31">"<b>42.4.2.3.3</b> If the offending player is a fielder, no substitute shall be allowed for him/her. The offending player may return to the field of play after serving the period of suspension and may bowl immediately."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct32">"<b>42.4.2.3.4</b>If a bowler is suspended mid-over, then that over must be completed by a different bowler, who shall not have bowled the previous over nor shall he/she bowl the next over."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct33">"<b>42.4.2.3.5</b> If the offending player is a not out batter, he/she shall be replaced by another member of his/her team. The offending player may return to bat after having served the suspension only at the fall of a wicket. If no batter is available to bat during a batter’s suspension, the innings is completed.  If the offending player does not continue his/her innings for whatever reason, he/she is to be recorded as Retired - not out."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct34">"<b>42.4.2.3.6</b> If the offending player is a dismissed member of the batting side, the period of suspension will not commence until the start of the next innings.  Furthermore, in these circumstances, the offending player may not act as a runner during the innings when he/she was suspended."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct35">"<b>42.4.2.3.7</b> Warn the offending player’s captain that any future Level 1 offence shall result in the award of 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct36">"<b>42.4.2.3.8</b>Any overs remaining to be served from a suspension shall be carried forward to the next and subsequent innings of the match. A part over at the end of the innings shall not count towards the overs for which the player is suspended."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct37">"<b>42.4.2.4</b>As soon as practicable, the umpire shall award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team signal the Level 3 penalty to the scorers call Play."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct38">"<b>42.4.2.5</b>The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending player’s team and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such further action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct39">"<b>42.5.1</b>Any of the following actions by a player shall constitute a Level 4 offence:\n-threatening to assault an umpire\n- making inappropriate and deliberate physical contact with an umpire\n- physically assaulting a player or any other person\n- committing any other act of violence."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct40">"<b>42.5.2</b>If such an offence is committed, 42.5.2.1 to 42.5.2.5 shall be implemented."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct41">"<b>42.5.2.1</b>The umpire shall call Time, if necessary."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct42">"<b>42.5.2.2</b>Together the umpires shall summon and inform the offending player’s captain that an offence at this Level has occurred."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct43">"<b>42.5.2.3</b>The umpires shall direct the captain to remove the offending player immediately from the field of play for the remainder of the match and shall apply the following:"</string>
    <string name="players_conduct44">"<b>42.5.2.3.1</b> If the offending player is a fielder, no substitute shall be allowed for him/her.  He/She is to be recorded as Retired - out at the commencement of any subsequent innings in which his/her team is the batting side."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct45">"<b>42.5.2.3.2</b>If a bowler is suspended mid-over, then that over must be completed by a different bowler, who shall not have bowled the previous over nor shall be permitted to bowl the next over."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct46">"<b>42.5.2.3.3</b> If the offending player is a batter he/she is to be recorded as Retired - out in the current innings, unless he/she has been dismissed under any of Laws 32 to 39, and at the commencement of any subsequent innings in which his/her team is the batting side.  If no further batter is available to bat, the innings is completed."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct47">"<b>42.5.2.3.4</b>Warn the offending player’s captain that any future Level 1 offence shall result in the award of 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct48">"<b>42.5.2.4</b> As soon as practicable, the umpire shall\n- award 5 Penalty runs to the opposing team\n- signal the Level 4 penalty to the scorers\n- call Play."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct49">"<b>42.5.2.5</b> The umpires together shall report the occurrence as soon as possible after the match to the Executive of the offending player’s team and to any Governing Body responsible for the match, who shall take such further action as is considered appropriate against the captain, any other individuals concerned and, if appropriate, the team."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct50">"<b>42.6.1</b> If a captain refuses to carry out an instruction under 42.4.2.3 or 42.5.2.3, the umpires shall invoke Law 16.3 (Umpires awarding a match)."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct51">"<b>42.6.2</b> If both captains refuse to carry out instructions under 42.4.2.3 or 42.5.2.3 in respect of the same incident, the umpires shall instruct the players to leave the field.  The match is not concluded as in Law 12.9 (Conclusion of match) and there shall be no result under Law 16 (The result)."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct52">"<b>42.7.1</b>If a player, while acting as wicket-keeper, commits a Level 3 or Level 4 offence, Law 24.1.2 (Substitute fielders) shall not apply, meaning that only a nominated player may act as wicket-keeper, even if another fielder becomes injured or ill and is replaced by a substitute."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct53">"<b>42.7.2</b> A nominated player who has a substitute or has a runner will suffer a penalty for any Level 3 or Level 4 offence committed by that substitute or by that runner."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct54">"<b>42.7.2.1</b>When the offence is committed by a substitute, the nominated player and substitute will each suffer the penalty defined in 42.4.2.3 or in 42.5.2.3 as appropriate. Only the substitute will be reported as in 42.4.2.5 or 42.5.2.5."</string>
    <string name="players_conduct55">"<b>42.7.2.2</b> When the offence is committed by a runner, the batter who has the runner and the runner will each suffer the penalty defined in 42.4.2.3 or in 42.5.2.3 as appropriate. The penalty for a Level 4 offence (42.5.2.3) will apply to the runner for the remainder of the match, but in only the current innings to the batter for whom the runner acted."</string>

    <string name="chris_highlights">"Chris Gaffaney is a New Zealand cricket umpire and former cricketer who played for Otago. He became an umpire after retiring as a player. A right-handed batsman, he played in 83 first-class and 113 List A matches. Gaffaney is currently a member of the ICC Elite umpire panel and officiates in Tests, One Day Internationals and Twenty20 Internationals."</string>
    <string name="kumar_highlights">"Kumar Dharmasena came into the international scene in 1994 against South Africa, aged 22. His quickish offspinners, delivered with a slightly unorthodox action, were invariably accurate making him an ideal one-day bowler, especially in Sri Lankan conditions. With time he also developed into a useful middle order batsman, which guaranteed him a regular place in the Sri Lankan one-day squad. His career came to a standstill after the Oval Test in 1998, when the ICC questioned his bowling action. However, he was cleared to play again by the Sri Lankan cricket board in July 2000. He subsequently played frequently for the one-day team, especially during home matches, but only played Test cricket sporadically. He retired from competitive cricket in November 2006 to pursue a career in umpiring and made his international umpiring debut in 2009. He was part of the panel of 18 umpires selected for the World Cup in India in 2011, officiating in the tournament opener between Bangladesh and India in Mirpur, and later the same year was promoted to the Elite Panel of ICC Umpires."</string>
    <string name="michael_highlights">"A right-hand opening batsman, Michael Gough looked to have a promising career ahead of him. He captained the England Under-19 side and in 2002, aged 22, he averaged over 50 for Durham. But one season later and he had quit, for the simple reason he did not enjoy playing the game.He sat his umpiring exams - in between working in his father's shop - and in 2006 he was appointed to the ECB's reserve list at the age of 27. Three years later he was appointed to the full list of first-class umpires. "</string>
    <string name="richard_highlights">"A steady left-arm spinner with a clipped moustache and a gentle manner, Illingworth snared his wickets by bowling maidens and building up pressure. He later added greater turn to his repertoire, but it was for his reliability as much as anything that England chose him in 1991 for the one-day and Test teams. Illingworth took a wicket with his first ball in Tests, but the selectors rightly decided that his style was better suited to the shorter form, and he was a miserly member of the side that reached the 1992 World Cup final. Although he made a Test comeback in 1995 and toured South Africa with some success that winter, Illingworth never managed to fight off the more talented Phil Tufnell for long enough to become a regular. For Worcestershire he was a gritty No. 8 and made three centuries as nightwatchman, but after 18 years on the staff, he was sidelined in 2000, and his request for a one-day contract for 2001 was turned down. Derbyshire promptly signed him on a two-year contract, but he drifted out of the game at the end of 2002. He was appointed to the full list of first-class umpires for the 2006 season."</string>
    <string name="kettleborough_highlights">"Richard Kettleborough was a left-hand top-order batsman and occasional seamer who was on Yorkshire's books for several seasons without being able to make a first-team place his own. His only hundred came at the end of the 1996 summer but the following year he made only three appearances and he moved south to Middlesex where there was an opener's berth up for grabs. He was given an extended run but in 20 matches he only passed fifty five times and he was released at the end of 1999. He continued to play with great success in Yorkshire club cricket and in 2006 he was added to the ECB list of umpires. He made his international umpiring debut in the Twenty20 between England and Australia at Old Trafford in 2009 and was in the panel of 18 umpires for the World Cup in India in 2011. Later the same year, he was promoted to the ICC's Elite Panel and, 38 at the time, was the youngest man in the group. In 2013, just two years after getting into the Elite Panel, Kettleborough won the ICC's Umpire of the Year award."</string>
    <string name="nitin_highlights">"Nitin Menon is an Indian former cricketer and umpire.He was a right-handed batsman, representing Madhya Pradesh in List A cricket. He is now an umpire and has stood in matches in the 2015–16 Ranji Trophy and the Sheffield Shield in Australia. In June 2020, he was promoted to the Elite Panel of ICC Umpires, replacing Nigel Llong. His father Narendra Menon was also a cricketer and umpire."</string>
    <string name="ahsan_highlights">"Ahsan Raza was a wicketkeeper and tail end batsman who moved across to umpire after retiring as a player, making his first appearances as an international reserve official in the series between Pakistan and Sri Lanka in 2008–09. He was travelling to the Gaddafi Stadium on the third day of the second Test when he was shot in the back and critically wounded in a terrorist attack aimed at the Sri Lanka squad."</string>
    <string name="paul_highlights">"Paul Reiffel was a nagging right arm seam bowler and a very capable lower order batsman. Throughout a career which saw him appear in many Tests and one day internationals for his country, he was a player who distinguished himself with his ability to bowl an awkward line and length and to complement it with a capacity to cut the ball both ways off the pitch. His unstinting accuracy and control was also a key to his success. Reiffel experienced occasional problems with no balling and was afflicted by a number of injuries that threatened to end his career at different times. But he remained an outstanding player and a highly valued member of Victorian and Australian teams for more than a decade. The laid back Reiffel retired from international cricket after forming a part of Australia's victorious 1999 World Cup side, and from his state at the end of the 2001 to 2002 season."</string>
    <string name="adrian_highlights">"Adrian Holdstock is a South African cricket umpire and former cricketer who now serves as an ICC international cricket umpire. He is part of Cricket South Africa's umpire panel for first class matches."</string>
    <string name="sharfuddoula_highlights">"Sharfuddoula Saikat, is an international cricket umpire and a former first-class player from Bangladesh.In March 2024, he became the first Bangladeshi umpire to be included in the Elite Panel of ICC Umpires.He also officiated in 100 matches in men's international cricket including ICC Men's Cricket World Cup in 2023."</string>
    <string name="rod_highlights">"Rod Tucker is an Australian cricket umpire, member of the ICC Elite Umpire Panel and officiates in international Tests, ODIs and T20Is. He was a cricketer who played briefly for New South Wales from 1985/86 to 1987/88, before moving to Tasmania where he played from 1987/88 to 1998/99. He was also vice-captain of Tasmania from 1991/92 until 1995/96. He briefly played as Captain/Coach for the Canberra Comets in the 1999/2000 season before retiring from cricket as a player."</string>
    <string name="joel_highlights">"Joel Wilson is a Trinidadian international cricket umpire from Trinidad and Tobago. Wilson is a former member of the Elite Panel of ICC Umpires, who represented the West Indies. He stands in matches of all the three formats of international cricket – Tests, One Day Internationals and Twenty20 Internationals."</string>
    <string name="anil_highlights">"Anil Chaudhary is an Indian cricket umpire. He stood in his first Twenty20 International on 10 October 2013, in a match between India and Australia. His first One Day International as an umpire, between India and the West Indies, was played on 27 November 2013."</string>
    <string name="simon_highlights">"Simon James Arthur Taufel is an Australian former cricket umpire who was earlier a member of the ICC Elite umpire panel. He won five consecutive ICC umpire of the year awards between 2004 and 2008, and is widely regarded as one of the top 10 greatest umpires of all time."</string>
    <string name="aleem_highlights">"Aleem Dar is a Pakistani cricket umpire and former first-class cricketer. He is a former member of the Elite Panel of ICC Umpires. Dar won the David Shepherd Trophy three years in a row from 2009 to 2011, after being nominated twice in 2005 and 2006."</string>
    <string name="steve_highlights">"Steve Bucknor is a Jamaican former international cricket umpire. Bucknor umpired in a record 128 Test matches between 1989 and 2009, and also umpired in 181 One Day Internationals during this period, including five consecutive Cricket World Cup finals from 1992 to 2007."</string>
    <string name="jerling_highlights">"Brian Jerling is a South African Test, One Day International and Twenty20 International umpire. He made his debut as an international umpire in an ODI game between South Africa and New Zealand in October 2000. He has since umpired in more than 90 ODI games."</string>
    <string name="oxenford_highlights">"Bruce Oxenford is an Australian former cricket umpire and a former cricketer. He has been an ICC international umpire since 2008, when he first umpired an ODI match. He went on to stand in his first Test match in 2010."</string>

    <string name="bhogle_highlights">"Harsha Bhogle  is an Indian cricket commentator and journalist.Bhogle has cemented his reputation for being a notable personality in the global cricket broadcasting industry. In 1991 to 1992, he became the first Indian commentator to be invited by the Australian Broadcasting Corporation during India's cricket series before the 1992 Cricket World Cup. He has since worked for ABC Radio Grandstand during India's Australian tours, and for eight years worked for the BBC as part of their commentary team in the 1996 and the 1999 Cricket World Cups.Since 1995, he has been presenting live cricket from all around the world for ESPN STAR Sports and was part of the commentary team that included Ravi Shastri, Sunil Gavaskar, and Alan Wilkins along with Geoff Boycott and Navjot Singh Sidhu, for a few seasons, and later, Ian Chappell and Sanjay Manjrekar.Bhogle has been covering all Indian Premier League seasons since 2009."</string>
    <string name="bishop_highlights">"Ian Bishop bowled like the wind when he made it to Test cricket at 21, producing gasp-inducing speeds from a long, straight, hustling run and orthodox side-on action. But his was ultimately an injury-riddled career, remembered mostly for its unfulfilled potential.Bishop has been arguably better known in his second career - as a top-drawer commentator who has his finger on the pulse of the game around the world. To many, he will forever be legendary as the voice that excitedly exhorted us to "remember the name" of Carlos Brathwaite when he won West Indies the T20 World Cup in 2016 with four sixes in the last over."</string>
    <string name="nasser_highlights">" Hussain established himself as the best and - not coincidentally - the most articulate England captain since Mike Brearley.His success was a triumph of willpower over several technical deficiencies including a dominant bottom hand and unorthodox leg and head positions which led him to lean back in the drive.He resigned from all forms of cricket in May 2004, three days after an unbeaten hundred against New Zealand at Lord's.He immediately joined Sky Sports' commentary team, and quickly became one of its more incisive members."</string>
    <string name="holding_highlights">"It began intimidatingly far away. He turned, and began the most elegant long-striding run of them all, feet kissing the turf silently, his head turning gently and ever so slightly from side to side, rhythmically, like that of a cobra hypnotising its prey. Good batsmen tended not to watch him all the way lest they became mesmerised. To the umpires he was malevolent stealth personified so they christened him Whispering Death. No-one in the game has bowled faster. His over to Geoff Boycott in the cauldron of Kensington Oval early in 1981 has gone down in history as the finest, fastest, most ferocious gambit of all time.\n\nFive years earlier, towards the end of the drought-ridden summer of 1976, The Oval had become a wasteland, parched beyond recognition, with slow flat heart-breaking pitches, and it was on this, in the final Test of the season, through the simple device of bowling ramrod-straight at high pace and to a full length, that he conjured 14 wickets for 149, the finest match figures ever by a West Indian. Now in the commentary box, he is gentle but fearless, a rational critic who beguiles with his deep fruity measured Jamaican twang."</string>
    <string name="nicholas_highlights">"Mark Nicholas was almost a throwback to the era of amateurs, and although he did not play for England, many inferior players did during his time with Hampshire. He did captain England A to Zimbabwe, but that was as close as he got.An attacking middle-order batsman and useful medium-pacer, he led Hampshire for more than a decade, including to four one-day titles - the NatWest Trophy in 1991 and the Sunday League in 1986.He retired at the end of 1995, moving seamlessly into the media, as a journalist with The Daily Telegraph and as a TV commentator and anchorman. His slick presentation manner was popular with viewers, and he moved from Sky to Channel 4 when the latter won the contract to cover England's home cricket, and from there to Channel 5. He also became a fixture on Australian TV with Channel 9. He was named the Sports Presenter of the Year in 2001 by the Royal Television Society. "</string>
    <string name="doull_highlights">"Back and knee injuries brought a premature end to Simon Doull's career. He was taken to the 1999 World Cup but was not required in the starting eleven, and then was selected for the first Test against England but suffered a serious knee injury requiring surgery. He fought his way back to fitness and was picked for the final two one dayers and first two Tests against Australia at the tailend of the summer. Unfortunately he was unable to trouble the Australian batsmen and lost his place for the final Test to his Northern Districts teammate, Daryl Tuffey. His undoubted career highlight was his 7 for 65 in the inaugural Boxing Day Test against India in 1998. The performance was a personal best, and the fourth best by a New Zealander in Test cricket. It included the first five Indian batsmen and set the scene for a New Zealand victory. He made a seamless transition to the commentary box, and briefly flirted with a comeback in 2002 to 2003 after playing a season in Netherlands."</string>
    <string name="manjrekar_highlights">"Sanjay Manjrekar pursued technical perfection like a man obsessed, but for a batsman hailed as the next Sunil Gavaskar, he ended up with a career that was largely unrealised. Though he never saw his father Vijay bat, those who did couldn't help commenting that the technical rectitude was inherited. His century against a four prong West Indian pace attack at Bridgetown in 1988 to 1989 was masterful, and he followed it up with a double and single century in Pakistan. But he only managed one other century - a laboured if match-saving effort in Zimbabwe's inaugural Test. He struggled to find his rhythm and form on bouncy pitches in Australia and South Africa, and never recaptured that poise and balance. Manjrekar made an unsuccessful attempt at reinventing himself as an opener in 1997, and faded out of the international scene. He kept wicket occasionally, and often regaled team-mates with his singing. He now works as a television commentator and media pundit."</string>
    <string name="pommie_highlights">"Pommie Mbangwa's rise to prominence was all the more remarkable as he had no family background in cricket. A little short of the top pace, he was primarily a line and length bowler, using both seam and swing, with the away swinger his stock ball. He spent a year at school in England, and in 1996 he went to Madras for coaching by Dennis Lillee; on his return he was offered a place in the Plascon Academy in South Africa, which he attended from April to September 1996. A surprise choice for the Zimbabwe tour of Pakistan in 1996 to 1997, he made his Test debut after the first choice bowlers were injured but made the most of his opportunity, taking the vital wickets of Ijaz Ahmed and Wasim Akram. But thereafter he struggled to maintain consistency, and his lack of pace meant that he was easy picking for international batsmen. He drifted in and out of the side, before disappearing from the international scene. In 2001 he started television commentary, where his quiet thoughtful views were well received, and in 2005 he ended a brief foray into coaching by commiting full-time to his TV career. He was one of international cricket's genuine No. 11s."</string>


</resources>


